[
    {
        "question": "What is Anxiety and Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nAnxiety is a feeling of nervousness, worry, or concern?",
        "answer": "These feelings are normal and\ncommon.\nAn anxiety disorder is a mental health condition that happens when anxiety gets in the\nway of daily life"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These feelings are normal and\ncommon.\nAn anxiety disorder is a mental health condition that happens when anxiety gets in the\nway of daily life?",
        "answer": "This is more than a temporary fear"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is more than a temporary fear?",
        "answer": "The anxiety is intense, lasts a long\ntime, or both.\nLike other health conditions, anxiety disorders can be treated"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The anxiety is intense, lasts a long\ntime, or both.\nLike other health conditions, anxiety disorders can be treated?",
        "answer": "Getting help is the best\nthing you can do for you and your family.\nFAQs\nWhat is anxiety?\nWhat are common types of anxiety?\nGeneralized anxiety disorder\u2014You feel very worried about your life most of the time.\nIt is hard to stop having negative thoughts"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Getting help is the best\nthing you can do for you and your family.\nFAQs\nWhat is anxiety?\nWhat are common types of anxiety?\nGeneralized anxiety disorder\u2014You feel very worried about your life most of the time.\nIt is hard to stop having negative thoughts?",
        "answer": "You might have trouble sleeping, an upset\nstomach, or headaches.\n\u2022\nPanic disorder\u2014You feel terrified for short, intense periods of time"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You might have trouble sleeping, an upset\nstomach, or headaches.\n\u2022\nPanic disorder\u2014You feel terrified for short, intense periods of time?",
        "answer": "These reactions\nare called panic attacks"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These reactions\nare called panic attacks?",
        "answer": "You might have a racing heart, feel sweaty or nauseated, or\nhave chest pain.\n\u2022\nSocial phobia or social anxiety disorder\u2014You feel nervous or afraid of social\nsituations"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You might have a racing heart, feel sweaty or nauseated, or\nhave chest pain.\n\u2022\nSocial phobia or social anxiety disorder\u2014You feel nervous or afraid of social\nsituations?",
        "answer": "You might avoid being around other people.\n\u2022\nAdditional symptoms of anxiety disorders are described below"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You might avoid being around other people.\n\u2022\nAdditional symptoms of anxiety disorders are described below?",
        "answer": "With any anxiety\ndisorder, you may have multiple symptoms.\nObsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) also\nare related to anxiety disorders"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is With any anxiety\ndisorder, you may have multiple symptoms.\nObsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) also\nare related to anxiety disorders?",
        "answer": "OCD causes recurring, unwanted thoughts (obsessions)\nand urges to repeat specific behaviors (compulsions)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is OCD causes recurring, unwanted thoughts (obsessions)\nand urges to repeat specific behaviors (compulsions)?",
        "answer": "PTSD may develop after\nexperiencing trauma, such as exposure to violence, death, serious injury, or sexual\nassault.\nAnxiety disorders are the most common type of mental health condition"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is PTSD may develop after\nexperiencing trauma, such as exposure to violence, death, serious injury, or sexual\nassault.\nAnxiety disorders are the most common type of mental health condition?",
        "answer": "Nearly 1 in 5\nadults has an anxiety disorder, including those who are pregnant or postpartum .\nYou may have anxiety for the first time in your life during pregnancy or after delivery.\nAnxiety can start at any time during or after pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Nearly 1 in 5\nadults has an anxiety disorder, including those who are pregnant or postpartum .\nYou may have anxiety for the first time in your life during pregnancy or after delivery.\nAnxiety can start at any time during or after pregnancy?",
        "answer": "It most often begins right after\ndelivery and up to 6 weeks postpartum, though it may happen up to a year after delivery.\nSometimes anxiety begins\nYou may be at higher risk for an anxiety disorder during or after pregnancy if you\nHow common is anxiety?\nWhen does anxiety related to pregnancy usually start?\nafter weaning your baby from breastfeeding\n\u2022\nwhen your menstrual periods \u00a0return\n\u2022\nWhat are risk factors for anxiety related to pregnancy?\nhad an anxiety disorder in the past\n\u2022\nhave family members who have anxiety disorders\n\u2022\nexperienced a previous pregnancy loss\n\u2022\nhad health challenges during pregnancy or labor and delivery\n\u2022\nhave other personal health challenges, including current or former mental health\nconditions\n\u2022\nhave a baby with health challenges\n\u2022\nThe symptoms are different for everyone and each type of anxiety disorder"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It most often begins right after\ndelivery and up to 6 weeks postpartum, though it may happen up to a year after delivery.\nSometimes anxiety begins\nYou may be at higher risk for an anxiety disorder during or after pregnancy if you\nHow common is anxiety?\nWhen does anxiety related to pregnancy usually start?\nafter weaning your baby from breastfeeding\n\u2022\nwhen your menstrual periods \u00a0return\n\u2022\nWhat are risk factors for anxiety related to pregnancy?\nhad an anxiety disorder in the past\n\u2022\nhave family members who have anxiety disorders\n\u2022\nexperienced a previous pregnancy loss\n\u2022\nhad health challenges during pregnancy or labor and delivery\n\u2022\nhave other personal health challenges, including current or former mental health\nconditions\n\u2022\nhave a baby with health challenges\n\u2022\nThe symptoms are different for everyone and each type of anxiety disorder?",
        "answer": "But they\nusually include\nA symptom of all anxiety disorders is feeling very worried or fearful for long periods of\ntime.\nTalk with your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn) \u00a0as soon as possible"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But they\nusually include\nA symptom of all anxiety disorders is feeling very worried or fearful for long periods of\ntime.\nTalk with your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn) \u00a0as soon as possible?",
        "answer": "Tell them if you\nhad anxiety in the past, if you take medication for anxiety or other mental health\nconditions, or if you are feeling anxious now"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Tell them if you\nhad anxiety in the past, if you take medication for anxiety or other mental health\nconditions, or if you are feeling anxious now?",
        "answer": "Also see the Resources section below for\nadditional support options.\nYour ob-gyn may ask questions about your mood during your prenatal or postpartum\ncare visits"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also see the Resources section below for\nadditional support options.\nYour ob-gyn may ask questions about your mood during your prenatal or postpartum\ncare visits?",
        "answer": "You may be asked to write down answers to questions that screen for\nmental health conditions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may be asked to write down answers to questions that screen for\nmental health conditions?",
        "answer": "Your answers will help your ob-gyn understand what kind of\nhelp you need.\nTreating anxiety can help you and your pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your answers will help your ob-gyn understand what kind of\nhelp you need.\nTreating anxiety can help you and your pregnancy?",
        "answer": "When you are less focused on\nanxiety, you may take better care of yourself"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When you are less focused on\nanxiety, you may take better care of yourself?",
        "answer": "You may have more energy to eat healthy\nmeals, get regular exercise, and follow other prenatal care  advice"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may have more energy to eat healthy\nmeals, get regular exercise, and follow other prenatal care  advice?",
        "answer": "You may be less\nlikely to give birth early and have a baby with a low birth weight than if you went without\ntreatment.\nexperienced trauma in your childhood, such as violence, abuse, or neglect\n\u2022\nWhat are the symptoms of anxiety?\nmental and emotional symptoms, such as constant worry, tension, and a feeling of\ndoom\n\u2022\nphysical symptoms, such as trouble sleeping, a rapid heartbeat, dizziness, chest or\nstomach pains, headaches, or nausea\n\u2022\nchanges in behavior, such as avoiding something you fear, avoiding leaving your\nhome, or constantly watching for danger\n\u2022\nHow can I get help for anxiety during or after pregnancy?\nWhat are the benefits of getting treatment for anxiety disorders?\nThe benefits of treatment continue after pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may be less\nlikely to give birth early and have a baby with a low birth weight than if you went without\ntreatment.\nexperienced trauma in your childhood, such as violence, abuse, or neglect\n\u2022\nWhat are the symptoms of anxiety?\nmental and emotional symptoms, such as constant worry, tension, and a feeling of\ndoom\n\u2022\nphysical symptoms, such as trouble sleeping, a rapid heartbeat, dizziness, chest or\nstomach pains, headaches, or nausea\n\u2022\nchanges in behavior, such as avoiding something you fear, avoiding leaving your\nhome, or constantly watching for danger\n\u2022\nHow can I get help for anxiety during or after pregnancy?\nWhat are the benefits of getting treatment for anxiety disorders?\nThe benefits of treatment continue after pregnancy?",
        "answer": "With treatment, you may be less\nlikely to have severe postpartum depression"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is With treatment, you may be less\nlikely to have severe postpartum depression?",
        "answer": "You may have an easier time bonding with\nyour baby, and your baby may have a lower risk of mental health conditions and long-\nterm behavior problems.\nTherapy is recommended to help treat anxiety"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may have an easier time bonding with\nyour baby, and your baby may have a lower risk of mental health conditions and long-\nterm behavior problems.\nTherapy is recommended to help treat anxiety?",
        "answer": "You also can consider medication,\nespecially if anxiety has a big impact on your life or if therapy does not help on its own.\nMaking time for self-care, joining support groups, and using community resources also\ncan help with anxiety.\nTogether you and your ob-gyn should discuss your options"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You also can consider medication,\nespecially if anxiety has a big impact on your life or if therapy does not help on its own.\nMaking time for self-care, joining support groups, and using community resources also\ncan help with anxiety.\nTogether you and your ob-gyn should discuss your options?",
        "answer": "Your ob-gyn also may help\nyou contact a psychiatrist, psychologist, social worker, doula , or other health care\nprofessionals for additional help"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your ob-gyn also may help\nyou contact a psychiatrist, psychologist, social worker, doula , or other health care\nprofessionals for additional help?",
        "answer": "Support groups can be helpful, too.\nAnxiety typically is treated with psychotherapy , also called talk therapy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Support groups can be helpful, too.\nAnxiety typically is treated with psychotherapy , also called talk therapy?",
        "answer": "Therapy can\nhelp you function better and help you heal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Therapy can\nhelp you function better and help you heal?",
        "answer": "In talk therapy, you may work with a therapist\nto\nThere are different methods and formats of talk therapy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In talk therapy, you may work with a therapist\nto\nThere are different methods and formats of talk therapy?",
        "answer": "For example, some types of\ntherapy help you change how you think and behave"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For example, some types of\ntherapy help you change how you think and behave?",
        "answer": "Other types of therapy help you\nbetter understand the causes of your feelings and behavior.\nYou may have one-on-one therapy (with just you and the therapist) or group therapy\nwhere you meet with a therapist and other people with similar concerns"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Other types of therapy help you\nbetter understand the causes of your feelings and behavior.\nYou may have one-on-one therapy (with just you and the therapist) or group therapy\nwhere you meet with a therapist and other people with similar concerns?",
        "answer": "Another option\nis family or couples therapy, in which you and family members or your partner may work\nwith a therapist"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Another option\nis family or couples therapy, in which you and family members or your partner may work\nwith a therapist?",
        "answer": "Therapy may be done in person or with telehealth, where you speak\nwith a therapist by phone or video chat.\nHow is anxiety treated during and after pregnancy?\nHow can therapy help treat anxiety?\nidentify unhealthy thought patterns\n\u2022\ndevelop ways to change these patterns\n\u2022\nimprove troubling symptoms\n\u2022\nHow is medication used to treat anxiety during and after pregnancy?\nAntidepressants  are used to treat anxiety"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Therapy may be done in person or with telehealth, where you speak\nwith a therapist by phone or video chat.\nHow is anxiety treated during and after pregnancy?\nHow can therapy help treat anxiety?\nidentify unhealthy thought patterns\n\u2022\ndevelop ways to change these patterns\n\u2022\nimprove troubling symptoms\n\u2022\nHow is medication used to treat anxiety during and after pregnancy?\nAntidepressants  are used to treat anxiety?",
        "answer": "These medications work to balance the\nchemicals in the brain that affect your moods"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These medications work to balance the\nchemicals in the brain that affect your moods?",
        "answer": "There are many types of antidepressants.\nIf one type does not work for you, you and your ob-gyn can talk about other options.\nIf you took an antidepressant before pregnancy that worked well for you, it is best to\ncontinue that medication during and after pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There are many types of antidepressants.\nIf one type does not work for you, you and your ob-gyn can talk about other options.\nIf you took an antidepressant before pregnancy that worked well for you, it is best to\ncontinue that medication during and after pregnancy?",
        "answer": "The dose may need to be\nincreased late in pregnancy.\nIf you start taking an antidepressant during pregnancy, you and your ob-gyn should talk\nat each visit about how you are feeling and whether the medication is working"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The dose may need to be\nincreased late in pregnancy.\nIf you start taking an antidepressant during pregnancy, you and your ob-gyn should talk\nat each visit about how you are feeling and whether the medication is working?",
        "answer": "After\npregnancy, you should continue checking in with your ob-gyn or another doctor.\nA healthy mother is important for a healthy pregnancy and baby"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is After\npregnancy, you should continue checking in with your ob-gyn or another doctor.\nA healthy mother is important for a healthy pregnancy and baby?",
        "answer": "There are risks of\nuntreated mental health conditions during and after pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There are risks of\nuntreated mental health conditions during and after pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Remember that treating\nanxiety can help you, your fetus , and your baby\u2019s future health.\nThe most commonly used antidepressants are called selective serotonin reuptake\ninhibitors (SSRIs)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Remember that treating\nanxiety can help you, your fetus , and your baby\u2019s future health.\nThe most commonly used antidepressants are called selective serotonin reuptake\ninhibitors (SSRIs)?",
        "answer": "Studies suggest that most SSRIs do not increase the risk of birth\ndefects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Studies suggest that most SSRIs do not increase the risk of birth\ndefects?",
        "answer": "Other antidepressants may be safe to take during pregnancy too"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Other antidepressants may be safe to take during pregnancy too?",
        "answer": "You and your\nob-gyn can discuss which medication is best for you and your pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You and your\nob-gyn can discuss which medication is best for you and your pregnancy?",
        "answer": "You also may\ndiscuss medication options with a psychiatrist.\nSelf-care can be a useful way to help your mood and your overall health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You also may\ndiscuss medication options with a psychiatrist.\nSelf-care can be a useful way to help your mood and your overall health?",
        "answer": "There are many\ndifferent approaches to self-care:\nIs it safe to take antidepressants during pregnancy or while breastfeeding?\nHow can self-care help with anxiety?\nMake time for activities that you enjoy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There are many\ndifferent approaches to self-care:\nIs it safe to take antidepressants during pregnancy or while breastfeeding?\nHow can self-care help with anxiety?\nMake time for activities that you enjoy?",
        "answer": "Try to do one simple, fun activity each day.\n\u2022\nStart or continue physical activity"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Try to do one simple, fun activity each day.\n\u2022\nStart or continue physical activity?",
        "answer": "Even just a few minutes of activity can be helpful.\nRead Exercise During Pregnancy\u00a0and Exercise After Pregnancy\u00a0for advice.\n\u2022\nEat a healthy diet"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Even just a few minutes of activity can be helpful.\nRead Exercise During Pregnancy\u00a0and Exercise After Pregnancy\u00a0for advice.\n\u2022\nEat a healthy diet?",
        "answer": "The MyPlate website from the U.S"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The MyPlate website from the U.S?",
        "answer": "Department of Agriculture has\nadvice for what to eat during and after pregnancy.\n\u2022\nAsk people in your life for help, such as a spouse or partner, parents, other family\nmembers, or friends"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Department of Agriculture has\nadvice for what to eat during and after pregnancy.\n\u2022\nAsk people in your life for help, such as a spouse or partner, parents, other family\nmembers, or friends?",
        "answer": "Visit Your Postpartum Care Team\u00a0for ideas.\n\u2022\nWith anything you try, make your goal simple and break it down into small steps"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Visit Your Postpartum Care Team\u00a0for ideas.\n\u2022\nWith anything you try, make your goal simple and break it down into small steps?",
        "answer": "Write\ndown the small steps you plan to take each day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Write\ndown the small steps you plan to take each day?",
        "answer": "You can make this list during pregnancy\nand then update it again after you give birth.\nDepression  is common during this time and often happens alongside anxiety (read\nDepression During Pregnancy and Postpartum Depression)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can make this list during pregnancy\nand then update it again after you give birth.\nDepression  is common during this time and often happens alongside anxiety (read\nDepression During Pregnancy and Postpartum Depression)?",
        "answer": "Bipolar disorder , OCD, and\nPTSD also are common"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Bipolar disorder , OCD, and\nPTSD also are common?",
        "answer": "Therapy and medications can help with these conditions during\nand after pregnancy.\nTalk with your ob-gyn if you feel sad, stressed, anxious, or if you have any mood\nchanges"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Therapy and medications can help with these conditions during\nand after pregnancy.\nTalk with your ob-gyn if you feel sad, stressed, anxious, or if you have any mood\nchanges?",
        "answer": "Also tell your ob-gyn about any stressful life events"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also tell your ob-gyn about any stressful life events?",
        "answer": "These may include losing\na loved one, having a loved one who is ill, living far from your friends and family, or\nmoving.\nNot having support and resources for your pregnancy can be a major source of stress.\nTalk with your health care team so you can get the help you need"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These may include losing\na loved one, having a loved one who is ill, living far from your friends and family, or\nmoving.\nNot having support and resources for your pregnancy can be a major source of stress.\nTalk with your health care team so you can get the help you need?",
        "answer": "Also see the\nResources section below for more ways to find help.\nPostpartum Support International (PSI) Helpline\nwww.postpartum.net\n800-944-4773\nText 800-944-4773 (English) or 971-203-7773 (Spanish)\nContact this nonemergency helpline for support, information, or referrals to mental\nhealth professionals during or after pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also see the\nResources section below for more ways to find help.\nPostpartum Support International (PSI) Helpline\nwww.postpartum.net\n800-944-4773\nText 800-944-4773 (English) or 971-203-7773 (Spanish)\nContact this nonemergency helpline for support, information, or referrals to mental\nhealth professionals during or after pregnancy?",
        "answer": "The helpline is open 7 days per week.\nTalk with and spend time with loved ones"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The helpline is open 7 days per week.\nTalk with and spend time with loved ones?",
        "answer": "Just being together can be helpful, even if\nyou don\u2019t want to talk about how you\u2019re feeling.\n\u2022\nWork on healthy sleep habits"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Just being together can be helpful, even if\nyou don\u2019t want to talk about how you\u2019re feeling.\n\u2022\nWork on healthy sleep habits?",
        "answer": "Though sleep is difficult with a newborn, some things\nmay help, such as avoiding caffeine late in the day and limiting screen time and\nbright lights before bed"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Though sleep is difficult with a newborn, some things\nmay help, such as avoiding caffeine late in the day and limiting screen time and\nbright lights before bed?",
        "answer": "Visit the American Academy of Sleep Medicine for more\ntips.\n\u2022\nSlowly breathe in from the very bottom of your belly for a few minutes twice a day.\nAlso try noticing how you feel and how your body is moving when you breathe\nnaturally"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Visit the American Academy of Sleep Medicine for more\ntips.\n\u2022\nSlowly breathe in from the very bottom of your belly for a few minutes twice a day.\nAlso try noticing how you feel and how your body is moving when you breathe\nnaturally?",
        "answer": "These are breathing exercises called belly breathing and mindful breathing.\n\u2022\nWhat other mental health conditions are common during and after pregnancy?\nResources\nLeave a confidential message at any time, and a volunteer will return your call or text as\nsoon as possible.\nPSI also offers online support group meetings and weekly Chat With an Expert phone\nsessions.\nAnxiety and Depression Association of America\nFind a Therapist: https://members.adaa.org/page/FATMain\nTherapists who offer telehealth: https://adaa.org/finding-help/telemental-\nhealth/provider_listing\nDirectories of health care professionals who offer mental health care in person or with\ntelehealth (using chat, video chat, or a phone call).\nNational Alliance on Mental Illness HelpLine\n1-800-950-NAMI (6264)\nhttps://nami.org/help\nFree, nationwide support service for anyone with questions or concerns about mental\nhealth.\nSubstance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) Helpline\n800-662-HELP (4357)\n800-487-4889 (TTY)\nwww.samhsa.gov/find-help/national-helpline\nFree, confidential mental health support in English and Spanish"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These are breathing exercises called belly breathing and mindful breathing.\n\u2022\nWhat other mental health conditions are common during and after pregnancy?\nResources\nLeave a confidential message at any time, and a volunteer will return your call or text as\nsoon as possible.\nPSI also offers online support group meetings and weekly Chat With an Expert phone\nsessions.\nAnxiety and Depression Association of America\nFind a Therapist: https://members.adaa.org/page/FATMain\nTherapists who offer telehealth: https://adaa.org/finding-help/telemental-\nhealth/provider_listing\nDirectories of health care professionals who offer mental health care in person or with\ntelehealth (using chat, video chat, or a phone call).\nNational Alliance on Mental Illness HelpLine\n1-800-950-NAMI (6264)\nhttps://nami.org/help\nFree, nationwide support service for anyone with questions or concerns about mental\nhealth.\nSubstance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) Helpline\n800-662-HELP (4357)\n800-487-4889 (TTY)\nwww.samhsa.gov/find-help/national-helpline\nFree, confidential mental health support in English and Spanish?",
        "answer": "Available 24 hours a\nday, 7 days a week, 365 days a year.\n988 Suicide & Crisis Lifeline\n988\nhttps://988lifeline.org/\nLifeline Chat: https://988lifeline.org/chat/\nFree help from trained counselors by phone or live online chat"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Available 24 hours a\nday, 7 days a week, 365 days a year.\n988 Suicide & Crisis Lifeline\n988\nhttps://988lifeline.org/\nLifeline Chat: https://988lifeline.org/chat/\nFree help from trained counselors by phone or live online chat?",
        "answer": "Available 24 hours a day,\n7 days a week, 365 days a year"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Available 24 hours a day,\n7 days a week, 365 days a year?",
        "answer": "If you or someone you love has thoughts of suicide, call\nor chat for help.\nCrisis Text Line\nwww.crisistextline.org\nText HOME to 741741 (US and Canada) for free, 24/7 crisis counseling.\nAntidepressants: Drugs that are used to treat depression.\nBipolar Disorder: A mental health disorder that causes intense changes in a person\u2019s\nmood, energy, and behavior"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you or someone you love has thoughts of suicide, call\nor chat for help.\nCrisis Text Line\nwww.crisistextline.org\nText HOME to 741741 (US and Canada) for free, 24/7 crisis counseling.\nAntidepressants: Drugs that are used to treat depression.\nBipolar Disorder: A mental health disorder that causes intense changes in a person\u2019s\nmood, energy, and behavior?",
        "answer": "Moods may range from very happy or irritable (manic\nepisodes) to very sad or indifferent (depressive episodes).\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth.\nDepression: Feelings of sadness for periods of at least 2 weeks.\nDoula: A birth coach who gives continual emotional and physical support to a woman\nduring labor and childbirth.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nMenstrual Periods: The monthly shedding of blood and tissue from the uterus.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPostpartum: Related to the weeks following the birth of a child.\nPostpartum Depression: A type of depressive mood disorder that develops in the first\nyear after the birth of a child"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Moods may range from very happy or irritable (manic\nepisodes) to very sad or indifferent (depressive episodes).\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth.\nDepression: Feelings of sadness for periods of at least 2 weeks.\nDoula: A birth coach who gives continual emotional and physical support to a woman\nduring labor and childbirth.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nMenstrual Periods: The monthly shedding of blood and tissue from the uterus.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPostpartum: Related to the weeks following the birth of a child.\nPostpartum Depression: A type of depressive mood disorder that develops in the first\nyear after the birth of a child?",
        "answer": "This type of depression can affect a woman\u2019s ability to\ntake care of her child.\nPrenatal Care: A program of care for a pregnant woman before the birth of her baby.\nPsychotherapy: Working with a therapist to identify problems and find ways to change\nbehavior.\nSelective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitors (SSRIs): A type of medication used to treat\ndepression.\nGlossary\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ527\nLast updated: March 2024\nLast reviewed:\u00a0March 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This type of depression can affect a woman\u2019s ability to\ntake care of her child.\nPrenatal Care: A program of care for a pregnant woman before the birth of her baby.\nPsychotherapy: Working with a therapist to identify problems and find ways to change\nbehavior.\nSelective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitors (SSRIs): A type of medication used to treat\ndepression.\nGlossary\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ527\nLast updated: March 2024\nLast reviewed:\u00a0March 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nBack Pain During Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nBackache is one of the most common pregnancy problems, especially in the later\nmonths"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nBack Pain During Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nBackache is one of the most common pregnancy problems, especially in the later\nmonths?",
        "answer": "The pain usually goes away after the baby is born"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The pain usually goes away after the baby is born?",
        "answer": "But for many women, back\npain lingers for months after giving birth.\nYou can blame your growing uterus  for your aching back"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But for many women, back\npain lingers for months after giving birth.\nYou can blame your growing uterus  for your aching back?",
        "answer": "Your expanding uterus shifts\nyour center of gravity and stretches out and weakens your abdominal muscles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your expanding uterus shifts\nyour center of gravity and stretches out and weakens your abdominal muscles?",
        "answer": "This\nchanges your posture and puts a strain on your back"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This\nchanges your posture and puts a strain on your back?",
        "answer": "Plus, the extra weight you\u2019re\ncarrying means more work for your muscles and increased stress on your joints"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Plus, the extra weight you\u2019re\ncarrying means more work for your muscles and increased stress on your joints?",
        "answer": "This is\nwhy your back may feel worse at the end of the day.\nThe abdominal muscles support the spine and play an important role in the health of the\nback"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is\nwhy your back may feel worse at the end of the day.\nThe abdominal muscles support the spine and play an important role in the health of the\nback?",
        "answer": "During pregnancy, these muscles stretch and weaken"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During pregnancy, these muscles stretch and weaken?",
        "answer": "These changes also can\nincrease your risk of hurting your back during exercise.\nYes, pregnancy hormones  can contribute to back pain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These changes also can\nincrease your risk of hurting your back during exercise.\nYes, pregnancy hormones  can contribute to back pain?",
        "answer": "To prepare for the passage of\nthe baby through the birth canal, a hormone relaxes the ligaments  in the joints of your\nFAQs\nIs back pain normal during pregnancy?\nWhat causes back pain during pregnancy?\nWhat role do the abdominal muscles play in back pain?\nDo hormones contribute to back pain?\npelvis to make them more flexible"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is To prepare for the passage of\nthe baby through the birth canal, a hormone relaxes the ligaments  in the joints of your\nFAQs\nIs back pain normal during pregnancy?\nWhat causes back pain during pregnancy?\nWhat role do the abdominal muscles play in back pain?\nDo hormones contribute to back pain?\npelvis to make them more flexible?",
        "answer": "Back pain can occur if the joints become too flexible.\nThere are several things you can do to prevent or ease back pain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Back pain can occur if the joints become too flexible.\nThere are several things you can do to prevent or ease back pain?",
        "answer": "For example, wear\nsupportive clothing and shoes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For example, wear\nsupportive clothing and shoes?",
        "answer": "Pay attention to your position when sitting, sleeping, and\nlifting things"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Pay attention to your position when sitting, sleeping, and\nlifting things?",
        "answer": "If you need to stand for a long time, rest one foot on a stool or a box to\ntake the strain off your back"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you need to stand for a long time, rest one foot on a stool or a box to\ntake the strain off your back?",
        "answer": "You also can use heat or cold to soothe sore muscles.\nLook for an abdominal support garment (for sale in maternity stores and catalogs)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You also can use heat or cold to soothe sore muscles.\nLook for an abdominal support garment (for sale in maternity stores and catalogs)?",
        "answer": "It\nlooks like a girdle and helps take the weight of your belly off your back muscles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\nlooks like a girdle and helps take the weight of your belly off your back muscles?",
        "answer": "Also,\nsome maternity pants come with a wide elastic band that fits under the curve of your\nbelly to help support its weight.\nWear low-heeled (but not flat) shoes with good arch support, such as walking shoes or\nathletic shoes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also,\nsome maternity pants come with a wide elastic band that fits under the curve of your\nbelly to help support its weight.\nWear low-heeled (but not flat) shoes with good arch support, such as walking shoes or\nathletic shoes?",
        "answer": "Avoid high heels\u2014they tilt your body forward and strain your lower back\nmuscles.\nSit in chairs with good back support or tuck a small pillow behind your lower back.\nLumbar supports, special devices that support the lower back, are sold at office supply\nand medical supply stores.\nIf you must lift something, squat down, bend your knees, and keep your back straight.\nDo not bend at the waist to pick up things.\nSleeping on your side is best later in pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Avoid high heels\u2014they tilt your body forward and strain your lower back\nmuscles.\nSit in chairs with good back support or tuck a small pillow behind your lower back.\nLumbar supports, special devices that support the lower back, are sold at office supply\nand medical supply stores.\nIf you must lift something, squat down, bend your knees, and keep your back straight.\nDo not bend at the waist to pick up things.\nSleeping on your side is best later in pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Keep one or both knees bent"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Keep one or both knees bent?",
        "answer": "It also\nmay help to place a pillow between your knees and another under your belly"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It also\nmay help to place a pillow between your knees and another under your belly?",
        "answer": "You also\ncan try a full-length body pillow.\nWhat can I do to prevent or ease back pain during pregnancy?\nWhat can I wear to support my back?\nWhat shoes should I wear during pregnancy?\nWhat can I do for support when sitting?\nHow can I lift things safely?\nWhat can I do during sleep to better support my back?\nYou can use a heating pad or warm water bottle for painful back muscles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You also\ncan try a full-length body pillow.\nWhat can I do to prevent or ease back pain during pregnancy?\nWhat can I wear to support my back?\nWhat shoes should I wear during pregnancy?\nWhat can I do for support when sitting?\nHow can I lift things safely?\nWhat can I do during sleep to better support my back?\nYou can use a heating pad or warm water bottle for painful back muscles?",
        "answer": "Heating pads\nshould be set at the lowest possible temperature setting"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Heating pads\nshould be set at the lowest possible temperature setting?",
        "answer": "Wrap your heating pad or\nwarm water bottle in a towel to help prevent burns"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Wrap your heating pad or\nwarm water bottle in a towel to help prevent burns?",
        "answer": "Cold compresses also can help ease\npain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Cold compresses also can help ease\npain?",
        "answer": "Limit the time you use heat or cold.\nIf you have severe back pain, or if the pain goes on for more than two weeks, call your\nobstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  or other obstetric care provider"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Limit the time you use heat or cold.\nIf you have severe back pain, or if the pain goes on for more than two weeks, call your\nobstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  or other obstetric care provider?",
        "answer": "He or she will\nwant to rule out other causes of the pain.\nBack pain can be a sign of some pregnancy complications"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is He or she will\nwant to rule out other causes of the pain.\nBack pain can be a sign of some pregnancy complications?",
        "answer": "For example, back pain can\nbe a symptom of preterm  labor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For example, back pain can\nbe a symptom of preterm  labor?",
        "answer": "Pain also can be a sign of a urinary tract infection\n(UTI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Pain also can be a sign of a urinary tract infection\n(UTI)?",
        "answer": "Contact your ob-gyn or other obstetric care provider if, in addition to back pain,\nyou:\nOnce other causes for your pain are ruled out, your ob-gyn or other obstetric care\nprovider may recommend that you see a rehabilitation specialist or a physical therapist.\nHe or she also may recommend a maternity girdle or brace if you aren\u2019t already using\none.\nYes, exercises for the back can:\nHow can I use heat or cold safely?\nWhen should I call my health care professional?\nWhat health conditions can cause back pain?\nHave a fever\n\u2022\nFeel burning during urination\n\u2022\nHave vaginal bleeding\n\u2022\nWhat if the back pain is not caused by an infection or preterm labor?\nCan exercise help with back pain?\nStrengthen and stretch the muscles that support your back and legs\n\u2022\nPromote good posture\n\u2022\nBefore doing any exercises, talk with your ob-gyn or other obstetric care provider to\nmake sure they are safe for you"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Contact your ob-gyn or other obstetric care provider if, in addition to back pain,\nyou:\nOnce other causes for your pain are ruled out, your ob-gyn or other obstetric care\nprovider may recommend that you see a rehabilitation specialist or a physical therapist.\nHe or she also may recommend a maternity girdle or brace if you aren\u2019t already using\none.\nYes, exercises for the back can:\nHow can I use heat or cold safely?\nWhen should I call my health care professional?\nWhat health conditions can cause back pain?\nHave a fever\n\u2022\nFeel burning during urination\n\u2022\nHave vaginal bleeding\n\u2022\nWhat if the back pain is not caused by an infection or preterm labor?\nCan exercise help with back pain?\nStrengthen and stretch the muscles that support your back and legs\n\u2022\nPromote good posture\n\u2022\nBefore doing any exercises, talk with your ob-gyn or other obstetric care provider to\nmake sure they are safe for you?",
        "answer": "Exercising should not cause pain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Exercising should not cause pain?",
        "answer": "If you have pain, stop\ndoing the exercise"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have pain, stop\ndoing the exercise?",
        "answer": "See Exercise During Pregnancy\u00a0for more exercise tips.\nYes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is See Exercise During Pregnancy\u00a0for more exercise tips.\nYes?",
        "answer": "Walking generally is safe during pregnancy and is great for the back"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Walking generally is safe during pregnancy and is great for the back?",
        "answer": "Wear walking\nshoes or tennis shoes that fit well and give good support, flexibility, and cushioning.\nWater exercise can be especially helpful for back pain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Wear walking\nshoes or tennis shoes that fit well and give good support, flexibility, and cushioning.\nWater exercise can be especially helpful for back pain?",
        "answer": "The water supports your weight\nso you avoid injury and muscle strain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The water supports your weight\nso you avoid injury and muscle strain?",
        "answer": "Many women swim right up to the end of their\npregnancies.\nIf you have no complications that prevent you from doing so, staying active during\npregnancy reduces back pain and increases your ability to go about your daily activities.\nAlways talk with your ob-gyn or other obstetric care provider before starting or changing\nan exercise program during pregnancy.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Many women swim right up to the end of their\npregnancies.\nIf you have no complications that prevent you from doing so, staying active during\npregnancy reduces back pain and increases your ability to go about your daily activities.\nAlways talk with your ob-gyn or other obstetric care provider before starting or changing\nan exercise program during pregnancy.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition?",
        "answer": "An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu?",
        "answer": "A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy?",
        "answer": "An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nHormones: Substances made in the body by cells or organs that control the function of\ncells or organs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nHormones: Substances made in the body by cells or organs that control the function of\ncells or organs?",
        "answer": "An example is estrogen, which controls the function of female\nreproductive organs.\nLigaments: Bands of tissue that connect bones or support large internal organs.\nKeep the muscles of the back, abdomen, hips, and upper body strong\n\u2022\nHelp ease back pain\n\u2022\nHelp prepare you for labor and childbirth\n\u2022\nIs it okay to walk during pregnancy?\nIs swimming a safe form of exercise?\nWhat about other types of exercise?\nGlossary\nObstetric Care Provider: A health care professional who cares for a woman during\npregnancy, labor, and delivery"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example is estrogen, which controls the function of female\nreproductive organs.\nLigaments: Bands of tissue that connect bones or support large internal organs.\nKeep the muscles of the back, abdomen, hips, and upper body strong\n\u2022\nHelp ease back pain\n\u2022\nHelp prepare you for labor and childbirth\n\u2022\nIs it okay to walk during pregnancy?\nIs swimming a safe form of exercise?\nWhat about other types of exercise?\nGlossary\nObstetric Care Provider: A health care professional who cares for a woman during\npregnancy, labor, and delivery?",
        "answer": "These professionals include obstetrician\u2013gynecologists\n(ob-gyns), certified nurse\u2013midwives (CNMs), maternal\u2013fetal medicine specialists\n(MFMs), and family practice doctors with experience in maternal care.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nUrinary Tract Infection (UTI): An infection in any part of the urinary system, including\nthe kidneys, bladder, or urethra.\nUterus: A muscular organ located in the female pelvis that contains and nourishes the\ndeveloping fetus during pregnancy.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ115\nPublished: May 2020\nLast reviewed: December 2021\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These professionals include obstetrician\u2013gynecologists\n(ob-gyns), certified nurse\u2013midwives (CNMs), maternal\u2013fetal medicine specialists\n(MFMs), and family practice doctors with experience in maternal care.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nUrinary Tract Infection (UTI): An infection in any part of the urinary system, including\nthe kidneys, bladder, or urethra.\nUterus: A muscular organ located in the female pelvis that contains and nourishes the\ndeveloping fetus during pregnancy.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ115\nPublished: May 2020\nLast reviewed: December 2021\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nDealing With Preterm Birth and\nPostpartum Depression\nLeila reflects on her experiences with two challenging pregnancies.\nLeila\u2019s first pregnancy was a traumatic one"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nDealing With Preterm Birth and\nPostpartum Depression\nLeila reflects on her experiences with two challenging pregnancies.\nLeila\u2019s first pregnancy was a traumatic one?",
        "answer": "She had preeclampsia\u00a0and a\npreterm birth, and her baby spent 6 weeks in the NICU (neonatal intensive care\nunit).\nFour years later, she was pregnant again"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is She had preeclampsia\u00a0and a\npreterm birth, and her baby spent 6 weeks in the NICU (neonatal intensive care\nunit).\nFour years later, she was pregnant again?",
        "answer": "This time, she found herself facing\ndepression during pregnancy, another stressful preterm birth, and postpartum\nPatient Story\n\ue925\ndepression.\nLeila, now 38 and living in Texas, shares what she went through and what she\u2019s\nlearned in this edited interview.\nACOG: Describe your first pregnancy and the onset of preeclampsia.\nLeila: Up until 26 weeks, I was having the perfect pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This time, she found herself facing\ndepression during pregnancy, another stressful preterm birth, and postpartum\nPatient Story\n\ue925\ndepression.\nLeila, now 38 and living in Texas, shares what she went through and what she\u2019s\nlearned in this edited interview.\nACOG: Describe your first pregnancy and the onset of preeclampsia.\nLeila: Up until 26 weeks, I was having the perfect pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Then I went in for a\nroutine appointment, and my ob-gyn told me, \u201cYou're spilling protein into your\nurine and your blood pressure's spiking"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Then I went in for a\nroutine appointment, and my ob-gyn told me, \u201cYou're spilling protein into your\nurine and your blood pressure's spiking?",
        "answer": "I'm diagnosing you with preeclampsia.\u201d\nIt was like a bomb had gone off in my head"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I'm diagnosing you with preeclampsia.\u201d\nIt was like a bomb had gone off in my head?",
        "answer": "I was more scared about my\ndaughter than myself"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I was more scared about my\ndaughter than myself?",
        "answer": "I was thinking, \u201cWhat is happening? What do I do next?\u201d\nACOG: What were the following\nweeks of your pregnancy like?\nLeila: I was keeping a daily diary of\nmy blood pressure readings, in the\nmorning and in the evening"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I was thinking, \u201cWhat is happening? What do I do next?\u201d\nACOG: What were the following\nweeks of your pregnancy like?\nLeila: I was keeping a daily diary of\nmy blood pressure readings, in the\nmorning and in the evening?",
        "answer": "I would\ntalk with my ob-gyn every week \u2013 I\nwould do urine tests and she would\nmonitor me"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I would\ntalk with my ob-gyn every week \u2013 I\nwould do urine tests and she would\nmonitor me?",
        "answer": "I also had to do\nnonstress tests\u00a0between 26 and 31\nweeks.\nThen I woke up one day, and I just had a very bad feeling"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I also had to do\nnonstress tests\u00a0between 26 and 31\nweeks.\nThen I woke up one day, and I just had a very bad feeling?",
        "answer": "I went to see my ob-\ngyn, and sure enough \u2013 she told me I needed to be admitted to the hospital"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I went to see my ob-\ngyn, and sure enough \u2013 she told me I needed to be admitted to the hospital?",
        "answer": "I\nchecked in to the hospital Thursday evening, and a cesarean was planned for\nSaturday morning.\nACOG: At 31 weeks, what was your daughter\u2019s condition?\nLeila: She was born at 3 pounds, 4 ounces"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I\nchecked in to the hospital Thursday evening, and a cesarean was planned for\nSaturday morning.\nACOG: At 31 weeks, what was your daughter\u2019s condition?\nLeila: She was born at 3 pounds, 4 ounces?",
        "answer": "Her foot was the size of my thumb"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Her foot was the size of my thumb?",
        "answer": "I\nwasn\u2019t allowed to hold her"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I\nwasn\u2019t allowed to hold her?",
        "answer": "The hospital where we delivered didn't have a NICU,\nso she was transferred to a hospital that was more than 2 hours away"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The hospital where we delivered didn't have a NICU,\nso she was transferred to a hospital that was more than 2 hours away?",
        "answer": "I couldn\u2019t\nbe with her, and that was hard.\nShe had a machine to help her breathe, and she had trouble learning how to\nsuck"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I couldn\u2019t\nbe with her, and that was hard.\nShe had a machine to help her breathe, and she had trouble learning how to\nsuck?",
        "answer": "She was in the NICU for 43 days"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is She was in the NICU for 43 days?",
        "answer": "She was finally sent home with a heart\nmonitor, and by then she was eating.\nACOG: Four years later, you were pregnant again with your son"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is She was finally sent home with a heart\nmonitor, and by then she was eating.\nACOG: Four years later, you were pregnant again with your son?",
        "answer": "What was your\nframe of mind at that point?\nLeila: That was so hard"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is What was your\nframe of mind at that point?\nLeila: That was so hard?",
        "answer": "To be honest, I was upset\u00a0\u2013\u00a0I didn't want to be pregnant.\nIronically, everything was perfectly textbook for most of the pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is To be honest, I was upset\u00a0\u2013\u00a0I didn't want to be pregnant.\nIronically, everything was perfectly textbook for most of the pregnancy?",
        "answer": "I wasn't\nsick"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I wasn't\nsick?",
        "answer": "I had great energy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I had great energy?",
        "answer": "But emotionally, I just wasn't feeling it.\nACOG: What did your ob-gyn have to say about your stressful feelings?\nLeila: She said, \u201cI know you're scared\u00a0\u2013\u00a0and this is scary\u00a0\u2013\u00a0but you went through\nit once, and we\u2019re going to get through this.\u201d\nShe also said that maybe I had a little PTSD [post-traumatic stress disorder]\nfrom my first birth experience"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But emotionally, I just wasn't feeling it.\nACOG: What did your ob-gyn have to say about your stressful feelings?\nLeila: She said, \u201cI know you're scared\u00a0\u2013\u00a0and this is scary\u00a0\u2013\u00a0but you went through\nit once, and we\u2019re going to get through this.\u201d\nShe also said that maybe I had a little PTSD [post-traumatic stress disorder]\nfrom my first birth experience?",
        "answer": "She said I might need to start talking to someone\nabout this anxiety I was building up, which I knew wasn't good for me or the\nbaby.\nShe did recommend counseling, but at that point I was brushing it off"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is She said I might need to start talking to someone\nabout this anxiety I was building up, which I knew wasn't good for me or the\nbaby.\nShe did recommend counseling, but at that point I was brushing it off?",
        "answer": "In those\nearly months, I understood that she was trying to help, but I was not ready for\nthat conversation.\nACOG: Looking back, were there any early signs that you might have been\ndepressed?\nLeila: I realize now this was a really bad sign, but between 26 and 31 weeks, I\nstarted writing goodbye letters for my daughter"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In those\nearly months, I understood that she was trying to help, but I was not ready for\nthat conversation.\nACOG: Looking back, were there any early signs that you might have been\ndepressed?\nLeila: I realize now this was a really bad sign, but between 26 and 31 weeks, I\nstarted writing goodbye letters for my daughter?",
        "answer": "I kept thinking, \u201cI'm not going to\nget out of this"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I kept thinking, \u201cI'm not going to\nget out of this?",
        "answer": "I'm just going to stay in the hospital"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I'm just going to stay in the hospital?",
        "answer": "Baby would come home and\nbe fine, sister would be fine, but mommy would definitely not be there.\u201d\n[Depression During Pregnancy]\nACOG: How did your second pregnancy conclude?\nLeila: I kept telling my doctor every time I would visit, \u201cYou know, I'm going to\nhave preeclampsia again"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Baby would come home and\nbe fine, sister would be fine, but mommy would definitely not be there.\u201d\n[Depression During Pregnancy]\nACOG: How did your second pregnancy conclude?\nLeila: I kept telling my doctor every time I would visit, \u201cYou know, I'm going to\nhave preeclampsia again?",
        "answer": "This is going to happen.\u201d And she would say, \u201cNo, your\nlabs look fine, your blood pressure's perfect"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is going to happen.\u201d And she would say, \u201cNo, your\nlabs look fine, your blood pressure's perfect?",
        "answer": "You don't have to worry about it.\u201d\nThen one morning when I was 34 and a half weeks, I had the most intense\nmigraine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You don't have to worry about it.\u201d\nThen one morning when I was 34 and a half weeks, I had the most intense\nmigraine?",
        "answer": "I didn't think anything of it, but I checked my blood pressure and it was\nextremely high"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I didn't think anything of it, but I checked my blood pressure and it was\nextremely high?",
        "answer": "Then I started throwing up and having blurry vision, a sign of\npreeclampsia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Then I started throwing up and having blurry vision, a sign of\npreeclampsia?",
        "answer": "I called my husband and said, \u201cI think it's time!\u201d Because of my\nanxiety, I had already prepacked everything, including baby things, and they were\nalready in the car.\nWe made it to the hospital, and the doctors spoke with me about having a\ncesarean"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I called my husband and said, \u201cI think it's time!\u201d Because of my\nanxiety, I had already prepacked everything, including baby things, and they were\nalready in the car.\nWe made it to the hospital, and the doctors spoke with me about having a\ncesarean?",
        "answer": "It happened the next day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It happened the next day?",
        "answer": "My blood pressure had to be lowered a little\nbit before I could have the cesarean.\nACOG: How were you and your son after the delivery?\nLeila: He was born at 5 pounds, 5 ounces and went to the NICU for 11 days"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is My blood pressure had to be lowered a little\nbit before I could have the cesarean.\nACOG: How were you and your son after the delivery?\nLeila: He was born at 5 pounds, 5 ounces and went to the NICU for 11 days?",
        "answer": "He\ncould have come home in a few days, but he needed some time to learn to eat\nby himself.\nI went back to work after 10 weeks, but I wasn't really engaged"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is He\ncould have come home in a few days, but he needed some time to learn to eat\nby himself.\nI went back to work after 10 weeks, but I wasn't really engaged?",
        "answer": "I remember\nduring my hour-long commute to and from work, sometimes I would pull over\nand just sit in my car on the interstate"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I remember\nduring my hour-long commute to and from work, sometimes I would pull over\nand just sit in my car on the interstate?",
        "answer": "That didn\u2019t seem off to me at the time"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is That didn\u2019t seem off to me at the time?",
        "answer": "I\nthought, \u201cOh, I just need a moment"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I\nthought, \u201cOh, I just need a moment?",
        "answer": "Just give me a moment.\u201d If I had gotten hit, I\ndon't think I would have cared at that point"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Just give me a moment.\u201d If I had gotten hit, I\ndon't think I would have cared at that point?",
        "answer": "Or if I had kept driving past work or\npast my house, it wouldn't have been a big deal to me.\nI just had those moments where I felt, I\u2019ve already said goodbye to my daughter\nin letters, and I didn't even want my son"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Or if I had kept driving past work or\npast my house, it wouldn't have been a big deal to me.\nI just had those moments where I felt, I\u2019ve already said goodbye to my daughter\nin letters, and I didn't even want my son?",
        "answer": "I wasn't crying or upset"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I wasn't crying or upset?",
        "answer": "I was just\nnumb.\n[Postpartum Depression]\nACOG: When did you end up getting help for depression?\nLeila: My boss finally called me in to a meeting one day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I was just\nnumb.\n[Postpartum Depression]\nACOG: When did you end up getting help for depression?\nLeila: My boss finally called me in to a meeting one day?",
        "answer": "She told me she had\ngone through postpartum depression and maybe I should look into it.\nThe next time I went back to my doctor, she also noticed a change in me"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is She told me she had\ngone through postpartum depression and maybe I should look into it.\nThe next time I went back to my doctor, she also noticed a change in me?",
        "answer": "She\nsaid, \u201cYou had built up this anxiety so much over the course of your pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is She\nsaid, \u201cYou had built up this anxiety so much over the course of your pregnancy?",
        "answer": "I\nthink it's time to go get help.\u201d\nI found a therapist online and chatted with her"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I\nthink it's time to go get help.\u201d\nI found a therapist online and chatted with her?",
        "answer": "She suggested group counseling\nand I found a group that was nearby"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is She suggested group counseling\nand I found a group that was nearby?",
        "answer": "I only went once, but it was helpful"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I only went once, but it was helpful?",
        "answer": "The\ngroup counselor said that I should try therapeutic writing, since I like to write.\nShe also made me check in with her every so often"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The\ngroup counselor said that I should try therapeutic writing, since I like to write.\nShe also made me check in with her every so often?",
        "answer": "The writing really did help\nme"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The writing really did help\nme?",
        "answer": "I journaled anything and everything"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I journaled anything and everything?",
        "answer": "If I was feeling overwhelmed, I wrote it\ndown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If I was feeling overwhelmed, I wrote it\ndown?",
        "answer": "If I was feeling numb, I wrote it down"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If I was feeling numb, I wrote it down?",
        "answer": "If I was busy, I wrote it down.\nI also learned about an online support group, Postpartum Support International.\nYou can text their help line whenever you need to.\nACOG: Your kids are now 7 and 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If I was busy, I wrote it down.\nI also learned about an online support group, Postpartum Support International.\nYou can text their help line whenever you need to.\nACOG: Your kids are now 7 and 4?",
        "answer": "What do you think about all of this now,\nlooking back?\nLeila: Sometimes I still wonder why I had preeclampsia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is What do you think about all of this now,\nlooking back?\nLeila: Sometimes I still wonder why I had preeclampsia?",
        "answer": "I didn\u2019t smoke, I didn't\ndrink, I worked out, I walked, I ate healthy meals"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I didn\u2019t smoke, I didn't\ndrink, I worked out, I walked, I ate healthy meals?",
        "answer": "But I also think about moms\nwho aren\u2019t able to have a baby at all"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But I also think about moms\nwho aren\u2019t able to have a baby at all?",
        "answer": "So in the end, I'm grateful for the way my\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\nstory played out"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is So in the end, I'm grateful for the way my\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\nstory played out?",
        "answer": "I\u2019ve come to realize that we all have different birth experiences,\nand not everyone's going to have the same story.\nACOG: What do you wish other women knew about postpartum depression?\nLeila: Statistically, 1 in 7 women get postpartum depression, and everyone\nknows more than seven women"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I\u2019ve come to realize that we all have different birth experiences,\nand not everyone's going to have the same story.\nACOG: What do you wish other women knew about postpartum depression?\nLeila: Statistically, 1 in 7 women get postpartum depression, and everyone\nknows more than seven women?",
        "answer": "We should always strive to reach out to moms.\nI know it's lovely to just think, \u201cOh, I want to hold the baby,\u201d but try to at least get\nin there and see about the mom"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is We should always strive to reach out to moms.\nI know it's lovely to just think, \u201cOh, I want to hold the baby,\u201d but try to at least get\nin there and see about the mom?",
        "answer": "Really ask how she is doing.\nPostpartum depression is most often temporary and treatable"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Really ask how she is doing.\nPostpartum depression is most often temporary and treatable?",
        "answer": "Almost all\nwomen who seek treatment recover fully"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Almost all\nwomen who seek treatment recover fully?",
        "answer": "Contact the Postpartum Support\nInternational Helpline by calling 1-800-944-4773, or by texting 800-944-4773\n(English) or 971-203-7773 (Spanish)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Contact the Postpartum Support\nInternational Helpline by calling 1-800-944-4773, or by texting 800-944-4773\n(English) or 971-203-7773 (Spanish)?",
        "answer": "You also can contact the National Suicide\nPrevention Lifeline at 1-800-273-8255 or use their live online chat.\nPublished: October 2020\nLast reviewed: September 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You also can contact the National Suicide\nPrevention Lifeline at 1-800-273-8255 or use their live online chat.\nPublished: October 2020\nLast reviewed: September 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved.\nRead copyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved.\nRead copyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It\ndoes not explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\ndoes not explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the\nadvice of a physician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the\nadvice of a physician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nDepression During Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nDepression  is a common illness that can be mild or very serious"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nDepression During Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nDepression  is a common illness that can be mild or very serious?",
        "answer": "It is more than feeling\nsad or upset for a short time or feeling grief after a loss"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is more than feeling\nsad or upset for a short time or feeling grief after a loss?",
        "answer": "Depression changes your\nthoughts, feelings, behavior, and physical health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Depression changes your\nthoughts, feelings, behavior, and physical health?",
        "answer": "It affects how you function in your daily\nlife"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It affects how you function in your daily\nlife?",
        "answer": "It can also affect how you relate to your family, friends, and coworkers"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It can also affect how you relate to your family, friends, and coworkers?",
        "answer": "Depression\ncan occur at different times of life or in different situations.\nDepression is common during pregnancy, affecting about 1 in 10 pregnant women.\nSome women have depression and anxiety for the first time in their lives during\npregnancy or after delivery"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Depression\ncan occur at different times of life or in different situations.\nDepression is common during pregnancy, affecting about 1 in 10 pregnant women.\nSome women have depression and anxiety for the first time in their lives during\npregnancy or after delivery?",
        "answer": "(Read Postpartum Depression to learn about depression\nafter pregnancy.)\nThe signs of depression can seem like the normal ups and downs of pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is (Read Postpartum Depression to learn about depression\nafter pregnancy.)\nThe signs of depression can seem like the normal ups and downs of pregnancy?",
        "answer": "A blue\nmood now and then is normal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A blue\nmood now and then is normal?",
        "answer": "But it\u2019s important to know the signs of depression"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But it\u2019s important to know the signs of depression?",
        "answer": "Talk\nwith your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  if you have any of these signs for at least\n2 weeks:\nFAQs\nWhat is depression?\nHow common is depression during pregnancy?\nWhat are the signs of depression during pregnancy?\nDepressed mood most of the day, nearly every day\n\u2022\nLoss of interest in work or other activities\n\u2022\nFeeling guilty, hopeless, or worthless\n\u2022\nThinking about death or suicide is a sign of depression"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Talk\nwith your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  if you have any of these signs for at least\n2 weeks:\nFAQs\nWhat is depression?\nHow common is depression during pregnancy?\nWhat are the signs of depression during pregnancy?\nDepressed mood most of the day, nearly every day\n\u2022\nLoss of interest in work or other activities\n\u2022\nFeeling guilty, hopeless, or worthless\n\u2022\nThinking about death or suicide is a sign of depression?",
        "answer": "If you are in crisis or feel like\nyou want to harm yourself or others, call 988 right away"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are in crisis or feel like\nyou want to harm yourself or others, call 988 right away?",
        "answer": "988 is the Suicide & Crisis\nLifeline, which offers free support and resources"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is 988 is the Suicide & Crisis\nLifeline, which offers free support and resources?",
        "answer": "Read the Resources section for other\nsupport options, including more helplines you can text or call and online pregnancy\nsupport groups"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read the Resources section for other\nsupport options, including more helplines you can text or call and online pregnancy\nsupport groups?",
        "answer": "You can also talk with a trusted friend, family member, or your ob-gyn.\nWomen who have severe depression during pregnancy may have trouble taking care of\nthemselves"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can also talk with a trusted friend, family member, or your ob-gyn.\nWomen who have severe depression during pregnancy may have trouble taking care of\nthemselves?",
        "answer": "They may not eat healthfully, attend prenatal care checkups, or get enough\nrest"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They may not eat healthfully, attend prenatal care checkups, or get enough\nrest?",
        "answer": "If you took antidepressants before pregnancy, you may become depressed again if\nyou stop taking them"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you took antidepressants before pregnancy, you may become depressed again if\nyou stop taking them?",
        "answer": "Having untreated depression during pregnancy also raises your\nrisk of postpartum depression"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Having untreated depression during pregnancy also raises your\nrisk of postpartum depression?",
        "answer": "Read\u00a0Postpartum Depression to learn more.\nDepression during pregnancy has been linked to several problems, including:\nAlso, when depression isn\u2019t treated during pregnancy, it can increase the risk of\nproblems for your child:\nSleeping more than normal or having trouble sleeping\n\u2022\nLoss of appetite, losing weight, or eating much more than normal and gaining weight\n\u2022\nFeeling very tired or without energy\n\u2022\nHaving trouble paying attention, concentrating, or making decisions\n\u2022\nBeing restless or slowed down in a way that others notice\n\u2022\nThinking about death or suicide (see below)\n\u2022\nWhat should I do if I am thinking about death or suicide?\nHow can untreated depression affect me during pregnancy?\nHow can untreated depression affect my fetus and newborn?\nThe fetus  not growing well in the uterus\n\u2022\nGoing into labor too early\n\u2022\nThe baby being too small at birth\n\u2022\nHealth complications  for the baby after birth\n\u2022\nYour newborn may cry more and be harder to comfort.\nTalk with your ob-gyn as soon as possible"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\u00a0Postpartum Depression to learn more.\nDepression during pregnancy has been linked to several problems, including:\nAlso, when depression isn\u2019t treated during pregnancy, it can increase the risk of\nproblems for your child:\nSleeping more than normal or having trouble sleeping\n\u2022\nLoss of appetite, losing weight, or eating much more than normal and gaining weight\n\u2022\nFeeling very tired or without energy\n\u2022\nHaving trouble paying attention, concentrating, or making decisions\n\u2022\nBeing restless or slowed down in a way that others notice\n\u2022\nThinking about death or suicide (see below)\n\u2022\nWhat should I do if I am thinking about death or suicide?\nHow can untreated depression affect me during pregnancy?\nHow can untreated depression affect my fetus and newborn?\nThe fetus  not growing well in the uterus\n\u2022\nGoing into labor too early\n\u2022\nThe baby being too small at birth\n\u2022\nHealth complications  for the baby after birth\n\u2022\nYour newborn may cry more and be harder to comfort.\nTalk with your ob-gyn as soon as possible?",
        "answer": "Tell them if you had depression in the past, if\nyou take medication for depression, or if you are feeling depressed now"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Tell them if you had depression in the past, if\nyou take medication for depression, or if you are feeling depressed now?",
        "answer": "Also read the\nResources section for more support options.\nYour ob-gyn may ask questions about your mood during prenatal care  or postpartum\nvisits"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also read the\nResources section for more support options.\nYour ob-gyn may ask questions about your mood during prenatal care  or postpartum\nvisits?",
        "answer": "Or they may ask you to write down answers to a survey that screens for mental\nhealth conditions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Or they may ask you to write down answers to a survey that screens for mental\nhealth conditions?",
        "answer": "Your answers will help your ob-gyn understand what kind of help you\nneed.\nTreatment of depression may include psychotherapy  (talk therapy), medication called\nantidepressants , or a combination of both"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your answers will help your ob-gyn understand what kind of help you\nneed.\nTreatment of depression may include psychotherapy  (talk therapy), medication called\nantidepressants , or a combination of both?",
        "answer": "Support from your partner, family members,\nand friends can also be helpful"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Support from your partner, family members,\nand friends can also be helpful?",
        "answer": "Your loved ones may be able to see if your depression is\ngetting worse before you notice it yourself.\nMany people also find that self-care (including sleep, healthful eating, and light exercise)\nand social support groups can be helpful in recovering from depression"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your loved ones may be able to see if your depression is\ngetting worse before you notice it yourself.\nMany people also find that self-care (including sleep, healthful eating, and light exercise)\nand social support groups can be helpful in recovering from depression?",
        "answer": "Postpartum\nSupport International offers online support group meetings and referrals to mental\nhealth professionals who offer care during and after pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Postpartum\nSupport International offers online support group meetings and referrals to mental\nhealth professionals who offer care during and after pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Read the Resources\nsection for more ways to get help.\nIn psychotherapy or \u201ctalk therapy,\u201d a therapist will work with you to:\nTherapy can help you function better, increase your well-being, and help you heal.\n\u2022 Older children may have more emotional and behavioral problems than other\nchildren.\n\u2022\nHow can I get help for depression during pregnancy?\nHow is depression during pregnancy treated?\nWhat is psychotherapy?\nIdentify any issues\n\u2022\nDevelop ways to address issues\n\u2022\nControl troubling symptoms\n\u2022\nThere are different methods and formats of therapy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read the Resources\nsection for more ways to get help.\nIn psychotherapy or \u201ctalk therapy,\u201d a therapist will work with you to:\nTherapy can help you function better, increase your well-being, and help you heal.\n\u2022 Older children may have more emotional and behavioral problems than other\nchildren.\n\u2022\nHow can I get help for depression during pregnancy?\nHow is depression during pregnancy treated?\nWhat is psychotherapy?\nIdentify any issues\n\u2022\nDevelop ways to address issues\n\u2022\nControl troubling symptoms\n\u2022\nThere are different methods and formats of therapy?",
        "answer": "For example, some types of therapy\nhelp you change how you think and behave, while other types of therapy help you better\nunderstand underlying issues"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For example, some types of therapy\nhelp you change how you think and behave, while other types of therapy help you better\nunderstand underlying issues?",
        "answer": "You may have one-on-one therapy (with just you and the\ntherapist) or group therapy where you meet with a therapist and other people with\nproblems similar to yours"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may have one-on-one therapy (with just you and the\ntherapist) or group therapy where you meet with a therapist and other people with\nproblems similar to yours?",
        "answer": "Another option is family or couples therapy, in which you and\nfamily members or your partner may work with a therapist.\nAntidepressants are medications that work to balance the chemicals in the brain that\naffect your moods"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Another option is family or couples therapy, in which you and\nfamily members or your partner may work with a therapist.\nAntidepressants are medications that work to balance the chemicals in the brain that\naffect your moods?",
        "answer": "There are many types of antidepressants"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There are many types of antidepressants?",
        "answer": "If one type does not work\nfor you, your ob-gyn can prescribe another"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If one type does not work\nfor you, your ob-gyn can prescribe another?",
        "answer": "It often takes at least 3 to 4 weeks of taking\nthe medication before you start to feel better.\nUntreated depression can be harmful to you, your fetus, and your baby after birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It often takes at least 3 to 4 weeks of taking\nthe medication before you start to feel better.\nUntreated depression can be harmful to you, your fetus, and your baby after birth?",
        "answer": "The\nrisks of untreated depression need to be weighed against the risks of the medication.\nStudies suggest that most selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs)  do not\nincrease the risk of birth defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The\nrisks of untreated depression need to be weighed against the risks of the medication.\nStudies suggest that most selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs)  do not\nincrease the risk of birth defects?",
        "answer": "But researchers are still learning whether other\nantidepressants can cause certain birth defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But researchers are still learning whether other\nantidepressants can cause certain birth defects?",
        "answer": "You and your ob-gyn can discuss\nwhich medication is best for you and your fetus.\nAnxiety is common during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You and your ob-gyn can discuss\nwhich medication is best for you and your fetus.\nAnxiety is common during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Pregnancy also can trigger obsessive-compulsive\ndisorder (OCD)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Pregnancy also can trigger obsessive-compulsive\ndisorder (OCD)?",
        "answer": "Anxiety and OCD can occur alone or with other mental health\nconditions, including depression.\n[What I Tell My Pregnant and Postpartum Patients About Depression and Anxiety]\nIf you have anxiety and stress, tell your ob-gyn"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Anxiety and OCD can occur alone or with other mental health\nconditions, including depression.\n[What I Tell My Pregnant and Postpartum Patients About Depression and Anxiety]\nIf you have anxiety and stress, tell your ob-gyn?",
        "answer": "Also tell them about any stressful life\nevents"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also tell them about any stressful life\nevents?",
        "answer": "These may include losing a loved one, having a loved one who is ill, living far\nfrom your friends and family, or moving"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These may include losing a loved one, having a loved one who is ill, living far\nfrom your friends and family, or moving?",
        "answer": "Not having support and resources for your\npregnancy can also be a major source of stress"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Not having support and resources for your\npregnancy can also be a major source of stress?",
        "answer": "Talk with your ob-gyn so you can get\nthe help you need.\nWhat are antidepressants?\nWhat should I know about taking an antidepressant during pregnancy?\nWhat other mental health conditions are common during pregnancy?\n988 Suicide & Crisis Lifeline\n988\nhttps://988lifeline.org\nLifeline Chat https://988lifeline.org/chat\nFree help from trained counselors by phone or live online chat"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Talk with your ob-gyn so you can get\nthe help you need.\nWhat are antidepressants?\nWhat should I know about taking an antidepressant during pregnancy?\nWhat other mental health conditions are common during pregnancy?\n988 Suicide & Crisis Lifeline\n988\nhttps://988lifeline.org\nLifeline Chat https://988lifeline.org/chat\nFree help from trained counselors by phone or live online chat?",
        "answer": "Available 24 hours a day,\n7 days a week"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Available 24 hours a day,\n7 days a week?",
        "answer": "If you or someone you love has thoughts of suicide, call or chat for help.\nPostpartum Support International (PSI) Helpline\n800-944-4773\nText 800-944-4773\u00a0(English) or 971-203-7773 (Spanish)\nwww.postpartum.net\nContact this nonemergency helpline for support, information, or referrals to mental\nhealth\u00a0professionals during or after pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you or someone you love has thoughts of suicide, call or chat for help.\nPostpartum Support International (PSI) Helpline\n800-944-4773\nText 800-944-4773\u00a0(English) or 971-203-7773 (Spanish)\nwww.postpartum.net\nContact this nonemergency helpline for support, information, or referrals to mental\nhealth\u00a0professionals during or after pregnancy?",
        "answer": "The helpline is open 7 days per week.\nLeave a confidential message at any time, and a volunteer will return your call or text as\nsoon as possible.\nPSI also offers online support group meetings to help you connect with other families.\nYou can also join PSI\u2019s weekly Chat with an Expert.\nNational Maternal Mental Health Hotline\n1-833-TLC-MAMA (1-833-852-6262)\nhttps://mchb.hrsa.gov/national-maternal-mental-health-hotline\nFree, confidential hotline for pregnant and new moms in English and Spanish"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The helpline is open 7 days per week.\nLeave a confidential message at any time, and a volunteer will return your call or text as\nsoon as possible.\nPSI also offers online support group meetings to help you connect with other families.\nYou can also join PSI\u2019s weekly Chat with an Expert.\nNational Maternal Mental Health Hotline\n1-833-TLC-MAMA (1-833-852-6262)\nhttps://mchb.hrsa.gov/national-maternal-mental-health-hotline\nFree, confidential hotline for pregnant and new moms in English and Spanish?",
        "answer": "Available\n24 hours a day, 7 days a week.\nNational Alliance on Mental Illness HelpLine\n1-800-950-NAMI (6264)\nhttps://nami.org/help\nFree, nationwide support service for anyone with questions or concerns about mental\nhealth.\nSubstance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) Helpline\n800-662-HELP (4357)\n800-487-4889 (TTY)\nwww.samhsa.gov/find-help/national-helpline\nFree, confidential help in English and Spanish"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Available\n24 hours a day, 7 days a week.\nNational Alliance on Mental Illness HelpLine\n1-800-950-NAMI (6264)\nhttps://nami.org/help\nFree, nationwide support service for anyone with questions or concerns about mental\nhealth.\nSubstance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) Helpline\n800-662-HELP (4357)\n800-487-4889 (TTY)\nwww.samhsa.gov/find-help/national-helpline\nFree, confidential help in English and Spanish?",
        "answer": "Available 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.\nResources\nAntidepressants: Drugs that are used to treat depression.\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Available 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.\nResources\nAntidepressants: Drugs that are used to treat depression.\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition?",
        "answer": "An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu?",
        "answer": "A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy?",
        "answer": "An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nDepression: Feelings of sadness for periods of at least 2 weeks.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPostpartum Depression: A type of depressive mood disorder that develops in the first\nyear after the birth of a child"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nDepression: Feelings of sadness for periods of at least 2 weeks.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPostpartum Depression: A type of depressive mood disorder that develops in the first\nyear after the birth of a child?",
        "answer": "This type of depression can affect a woman\u2019s ability to\ntake care of her child.\nPrenatal Care: A program of care for a pregnant woman before the birth of her baby.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nPsychotherapy: Working with a therapist to identify problems and find ways to change\nbehavior.\nSelective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitors (SSRIs): A type of medication used to treat\ndepression.\nUterus: A muscular organ in the female pelvis"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This type of depression can affect a woman\u2019s ability to\ntake care of her child.\nPrenatal Care: A program of care for a pregnant woman before the birth of her baby.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nPsychotherapy: Working with a therapist to identify problems and find ways to change\nbehavior.\nSelective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitors (SSRIs): A type of medication used to treat\ndepression.\nUterus: A muscular organ in the female pelvis?",
        "answer": "During pregnancy, this organ holds and\nnourishes the fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During pregnancy, this organ holds and\nnourishes the fetus?",
        "answer": "Also called the womb.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nGlossary\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nFAQ515\nLast updated: May 2023\nLast reviewed: August 2022\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also called the womb.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nGlossary\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nFAQ515\nLast updated: May 2023\nLast reviewed: August 2022\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nExercise During Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nSafety and Benefits of Exercise\nIf you are healthy and your pregnancy is normal, it is safe to continue or start regular\nphysical activity"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nExercise During Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nSafety and Benefits of Exercise\nIf you are healthy and your pregnancy is normal, it is safe to continue or start regular\nphysical activity?",
        "answer": "Physical activity does not increase your risk of miscarriage, low birth\nweight, or early delivery.\nIt\u2019s still important to discuss exercise with your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)\nduring your early prenatal visits"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Physical activity does not increase your risk of miscarriage, low birth\nweight, or early delivery.\nIt\u2019s still important to discuss exercise with your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)\nduring your early prenatal visits?",
        "answer": "If your ob-gyn gives you the OK to exercise, you can\ndiscuss what activities you can do safely.\nRegular exercise during pregnancy benefits you and your fetus in these key ways:\nFAQs\nIs it safe to exercise during pregnancy?\nWhat are the benefits of exercise during pregnancy?\nReduces back pain\n\u2022\nEases constipation\n\u2022\nMay decrease your risk of gestational diabetes , preeclampsia, and cesarean birth\n\u2022\nPromotes healthy weight gain during pregnancy\n\u2022\nImproves your overall fitness and strengthens your heart and blood vessels\n\u2022\nHelps you to lose the baby weight after your baby is born\n\u2022\nGuidelines for Exercise\nIdeally, pregnant women should get at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity aerobic\nactivity every week"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If your ob-gyn gives you the OK to exercise, you can\ndiscuss what activities you can do safely.\nRegular exercise during pregnancy benefits you and your fetus in these key ways:\nFAQs\nIs it safe to exercise during pregnancy?\nWhat are the benefits of exercise during pregnancy?\nReduces back pain\n\u2022\nEases constipation\n\u2022\nMay decrease your risk of gestational diabetes , preeclampsia, and cesarean birth\n\u2022\nPromotes healthy weight gain during pregnancy\n\u2022\nImproves your overall fitness and strengthens your heart and blood vessels\n\u2022\nHelps you to lose the baby weight after your baby is born\n\u2022\nGuidelines for Exercise\nIdeally, pregnant women should get at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity aerobic\nactivity every week?",
        "answer": "An aerobic activity is one in which you move large muscles of the\nbody (like those in the legs and arms) in a rhythmic way"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An aerobic activity is one in which you move large muscles of the\nbody (like those in the legs and arms) in a rhythmic way?",
        "answer": "Moderate intensity means you\nare moving enough to raise your heart rate and start sweating"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Moderate intensity means you\nare moving enough to raise your heart rate and start sweating?",
        "answer": "You still can talk\nnormally, but you cannot sing.\nExamples of moderate-intensity aerobic activity include brisk walking and general\ngardening (raking, weeding, or digging)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You still can talk\nnormally, but you cannot sing.\nExamples of moderate-intensity aerobic activity include brisk walking and general\ngardening (raking, weeding, or digging)?",
        "answer": "You can divide the 150 minutes into 30-minute\nworkouts on 5 days of the week or into smaller 10-minute workouts throughout each\nday.\nIf you are new to exercise, start out slowly and gradually increase your activity"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can divide the 150 minutes into 30-minute\nworkouts on 5 days of the week or into smaller 10-minute workouts throughout each\nday.\nIf you are new to exercise, start out slowly and gradually increase your activity?",
        "answer": "Begin\nwith as little as 5 minutes a day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Begin\nwith as little as 5 minutes a day?",
        "answer": "Add 5 minutes each week until you can stay active for\n30 minutes a day.\nIf you were very active before pregnancy, you can keep doing the same workouts with\nyour\u00a0ob-gyn\u2019s approval.\u00a0But if you start to lose weight, you may need to increase the\nnumber of calories that you eat.\nYour body goes through many changes during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Add 5 minutes each week until you can stay active for\n30 minutes a day.\nIf you were very active before pregnancy, you can keep doing the same workouts with\nyour\u00a0ob-gyn\u2019s approval.\u00a0But if you start to lose weight, you may need to increase the\nnumber of calories that you eat.\nYour body goes through many changes during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "It is important to choose\nexercises that take these changes into account:\nHow much should I exercise during pregnancy?\nWhat changes occur in the body during pregnancy that can affect my exercise\nroutine?\nJoints\u2014The hormones  made during pregnancy cause the ligaments that support\nyour joints to become relaxed"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is important to choose\nexercises that take these changes into account:\nHow much should I exercise during pregnancy?\nWhat changes occur in the body during pregnancy that can affect my exercise\nroutine?\nJoints\u2014The hormones  made during pregnancy cause the ligaments that support\nyour joints to become relaxed?",
        "answer": "This makes the joints more mobile and at risk of\ninjury"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This makes the joints more mobile and at risk of\ninjury?",
        "answer": "Avoid jerky, bouncy, or high-impact motions that can increase your risk of\nbeing hurt.\n\u2022\nBalance\u2014The extra weight in the front of your body shifts your center of gravity"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Avoid jerky, bouncy, or high-impact motions that can increase your risk of\nbeing hurt.\n\u2022\nBalance\u2014The extra weight in the front of your body shifts your center of gravity?",
        "answer": "This\nplaces stress on joints and muscles, especially those in your pelvis and lower back.\nBecause you are less stable and more likely to lose your balance, you are at greater\nrisk of falling.\n\u2022\nExercising Safely\nExperts agree these exercises are safest for pregnant women:\nBreathing\u2014When you exercise, oxygen  and blood flow are directed to your muscles\nand away from other areas of your body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This\nplaces stress on joints and muscles, especially those in your pelvis and lower back.\nBecause you are less stable and more likely to lose your balance, you are at greater\nrisk of falling.\n\u2022\nExercising Safely\nExperts agree these exercises are safest for pregnant women:\nBreathing\u2014When you exercise, oxygen  and blood flow are directed to your muscles\nand away from other areas of your body?",
        "answer": "While you are pregnant, your need for\noxygen increases"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is While you are pregnant, your need for\noxygen increases?",
        "answer": "This may affect your ability to do strenuous exercise, especially if\nyou are overweight or obese.\n\u2022\nWhat precautions should I take when exercising during pregnancy?\nDrink plenty of water before, during, and after your workout"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This may affect your ability to do strenuous exercise, especially if\nyou are overweight or obese.\n\u2022\nWhat precautions should I take when exercising during pregnancy?\nDrink plenty of water before, during, and after your workout?",
        "answer": "Signs of dehydration\ninclude dizziness, a racing or pounding heart, and urinating only small amounts or\nhaving urine that is dark yellow.\n\u2022\nWear a sports bra that gives lots of support to help protect your breasts"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Signs of dehydration\ninclude dizziness, a racing or pounding heart, and urinating only small amounts or\nhaving urine that is dark yellow.\n\u2022\nWear a sports bra that gives lots of support to help protect your breasts?",
        "answer": "Later in\npregnancy, a belly support belt may reduce discomfort while walking or running.\n\u2022\nAvoid becoming overheated, especially in the first trimester"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Later in\npregnancy, a belly support belt may reduce discomfort while walking or running.\n\u2022\nAvoid becoming overheated, especially in the first trimester?",
        "answer": "Drink plenty of water,\nwear loose-fitting clothing, and exercise in a temperature-controlled room"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Drink plenty of water,\nwear loose-fitting clothing, and exercise in a temperature-controlled room?",
        "answer": "Do not\nexercise outside when it is very hot or humid.\n\u2022\nAvoid standing still or lying flat on your back as much as possible"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Do not\nexercise outside when it is very hot or humid.\n\u2022\nAvoid standing still or lying flat on your back as much as possible?",
        "answer": "When you lie on\nyour back, your uterus  presses on a large vein that returns blood to the heart.\nStanding motionless can cause blood to pool in your legs and feet"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When you lie on\nyour back, your uterus  presses on a large vein that returns blood to the heart.\nStanding motionless can cause blood to pool in your legs and feet?",
        "answer": "These positions\nmay cause your blood pressure to decrease for a short time.\n\u2022\nWhat are some safe exercises I can do during pregnancy?\nWalking\u2014Brisk walking gives a total body workout and is easy on the joints and\nmuscles.\n\u2022\nSwimming and water workouts\u2014Water workouts use many of the body\u2019s muscles.\nThe water supports your weight so you avoid injury and muscle strain.\n\u2022\nStationary bicycling\u2014Because your growing belly can affect your balance and make\nyou more prone to falls, riding a standard bicycle during pregnancy can be risky.\nCycling on a stationary bike is a better choice.\n\u2022\nIf you are an experienced runner, jogger, or racquet-sports player, you may be able to\nkeep doing these activities during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These positions\nmay cause your blood pressure to decrease for a short time.\n\u2022\nWhat are some safe exercises I can do during pregnancy?\nWalking\u2014Brisk walking gives a total body workout and is easy on the joints and\nmuscles.\n\u2022\nSwimming and water workouts\u2014Water workouts use many of the body\u2019s muscles.\nThe water supports your weight so you avoid injury and muscle strain.\n\u2022\nStationary bicycling\u2014Because your growing belly can affect your balance and make\nyou more prone to falls, riding a standard bicycle during pregnancy can be risky.\nCycling on a stationary bike is a better choice.\n\u2022\nIf you are an experienced runner, jogger, or racquet-sports player, you may be able to\nkeep doing these activities during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Discuss these activities with your ob-gyn.\nWhile pregnant, avoid activities that put you at increased risk of injury, such as the\nfollowing:\nWhether you\u2019re a seasoned athlete or a beginner, watch for the following warning signs\nwhen you exercise"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Discuss these activities with your ob-gyn.\nWhile pregnant, avoid activities that put you at increased risk of injury, such as the\nfollowing:\nWhether you\u2019re a seasoned athlete or a beginner, watch for the following warning signs\nwhen you exercise?",
        "answer": "If you have any of them, stop and call your ob-gyn.\nModified yoga and modified Pilates\u2014Yoga reduces stress, improves flexibility, and\nencourages stretching and focused breathing"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have any of them, stop and call your ob-gyn.\nModified yoga and modified Pilates\u2014Yoga reduces stress, improves flexibility, and\nencourages stretching and focused breathing?",
        "answer": "There are prenatal yoga and Pilates\nclasses designed for pregnant women"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There are prenatal yoga and Pilates\nclasses designed for pregnant women?",
        "answer": "These classes often teach modified poses\nthat accommodate a pregnant woman\u2019s shifting balance"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These classes often teach modified poses\nthat accommodate a pregnant woman\u2019s shifting balance?",
        "answer": "You should avoid poses\nthat require you to be still or lie on your back for long periods.\n\u2022\nWhat exercises should I avoid during pregnancy?\nContact sports and sports that put you at risk of getting hit in the abdomen, including\nice hockey, boxing, soccer, and basketball\n\u2022\nSkydiving\n\u2022\nActivities that may result in a fall, such as downhill snow skiing, water skiing, surfing,\noff-road cycling, gymnastics, and horseback riding\n\u2022\n\"Hot yoga\u201d or \u201chot Pilates,\u201d which may cause you to become overheated\n\u2022\nScuba diving\n\u2022\nActivities performed above 6,000 feet (if you do not already live at a high altitude)\n\u2022\nWhat are warning signs that I should stop exercising?\nBleeding from the vagina\n\u2022\nFeeling dizzy or faint\n\u2022\nShortness of breath before starting exercise\n\u2022\nChest pain\n\u2022\nHeadache\n\u2022\nMuscle weakness\n\u2022\nCalf pain or swelling\n\u2022\nOther Questions\nExercising after your baby is born may help improve mood and decreases the risk of\ndeep vein thrombosis (DVT) , a condition that can occur more frequently in women in\nthe weeks after childbirth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You should avoid poses\nthat require you to be still or lie on your back for long periods.\n\u2022\nWhat exercises should I avoid during pregnancy?\nContact sports and sports that put you at risk of getting hit in the abdomen, including\nice hockey, boxing, soccer, and basketball\n\u2022\nSkydiving\n\u2022\nActivities that may result in a fall, such as downhill snow skiing, water skiing, surfing,\noff-road cycling, gymnastics, and horseback riding\n\u2022\n\"Hot yoga\u201d or \u201chot Pilates,\u201d which may cause you to become overheated\n\u2022\nScuba diving\n\u2022\nActivities performed above 6,000 feet (if you do not already live at a high altitude)\n\u2022\nWhat are warning signs that I should stop exercising?\nBleeding from the vagina\n\u2022\nFeeling dizzy or faint\n\u2022\nShortness of breath before starting exercise\n\u2022\nChest pain\n\u2022\nHeadache\n\u2022\nMuscle weakness\n\u2022\nCalf pain or swelling\n\u2022\nOther Questions\nExercising after your baby is born may help improve mood and decreases the risk of\ndeep vein thrombosis (DVT) , a condition that can occur more frequently in women in\nthe weeks after childbirth?",
        "answer": "In addition to these health benefits, exercise after pregnancy\ncan help you lose the extra pounds that you may have gained during pregnancy.\nThe Move Your Way website from the U.S"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In addition to these health benefits, exercise after pregnancy\ncan help you lose the extra pounds that you may have gained during pregnancy.\nThe Move Your Way website from the U.S?",
        "answer": "Department of Health and Human Services\ncan help you find safe, fun ways to get active during and after pregnancy.\nCesarean Delivery: Delivery of a fetus from the uterus through an incision made in the\nwoman\u2019s abdomen.\nDeep Vein Thrombosis (DVT): A condition in which a blood clot forms in veins in the leg\nor other areas of the body.\nDehydration: A condition that happens when the body does not have as much water as\nit needs.\nGestational Diabetes: Diabetes that starts during pregnancy.\nHormones: Substances made in the body that control the function of cells or organs.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOxygen: An element that we breathe in to sustain life.\nRegular, painful contractions of the uterus\n\u2022\nFluid gushing or leaking from the vagina\n\u2022\nWhy is it important to keep exercising after my baby is born?\nWhere can I learn more about exercise and pregnancy?\nGlossary\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nUterus: A muscular organ in the female pelvis"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Department of Health and Human Services\ncan help you find safe, fun ways to get active during and after pregnancy.\nCesarean Delivery: Delivery of a fetus from the uterus through an incision made in the\nwoman\u2019s abdomen.\nDeep Vein Thrombosis (DVT): A condition in which a blood clot forms in veins in the leg\nor other areas of the body.\nDehydration: A condition that happens when the body does not have as much water as\nit needs.\nGestational Diabetes: Diabetes that starts during pregnancy.\nHormones: Substances made in the body that control the function of cells or organs.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOxygen: An element that we breathe in to sustain life.\nRegular, painful contractions of the uterus\n\u2022\nFluid gushing or leaking from the vagina\n\u2022\nWhy is it important to keep exercising after my baby is born?\nWhere can I learn more about exercise and pregnancy?\nGlossary\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nUterus: A muscular organ in the female pelvis?",
        "answer": "During pregnancy, this organ holds and\nnourishes the fetus.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ119\nLast updated: September 2024\nLast reviewed: September 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During pregnancy, this organ holds and\nnourishes the fetus.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ119\nLast updated: September 2024\nLast reviewed: September 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nGenetic Disorders and Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nOverview\nGenetic disorders are disorders caused by changes in genes  or chromosomes .\nGenetic disorders may be a physical problem or intellectual disability that is present at\nbirth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nGenetic Disorders and Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nOverview\nGenetic disorders are disorders caused by changes in genes  or chromosomes .\nGenetic disorders may be a physical problem or intellectual disability that is present at\nbirth?",
        "answer": "They are a type of birth defect"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They are a type of birth defect?",
        "answer": "Some genetic disorders may not be noticed until\nthe child is older.\nGenetic counseling and screening tests  can help assess your risk of having a baby with\ncertain genetic disorders"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some genetic disorders may not be noticed until\nthe child is older.\nGenetic counseling and screening tests  can help assess your risk of having a baby with\ncertain genetic disorders?",
        "answer": "Diagnostic tests  can detect if a specific genetic disorder is\npresent in the fetus .\nA gene is a small piece of hereditary material called DNA"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Diagnostic tests  can detect if a specific genetic disorder is\npresent in the fetus .\nA gene is a small piece of hereditary material called DNA?",
        "answer": "Each gene controls some\naspect of how your body looks or functions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Each gene controls some\naspect of how your body looks or functions?",
        "answer": "Genes come in pairs.\nChromosomes are the structures inside cells  that carry genes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Genes come in pairs.\nChromosomes are the structures inside cells  that carry genes?",
        "answer": "Chromosomes also\ncome in pairs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Chromosomes also\ncome in pairs?",
        "answer": "Most cells have 23 pairs of chromosomes for a total of 46\nchromosomes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Most cells have 23 pairs of chromosomes for a total of 46\nchromosomes?",
        "answer": "Sperm  and egg  cells each have 23 chromosomes.\nDuring fertilization , when the egg and sperm join, the two sets of chromosomes come\ntogether"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Sperm  and egg  cells each have 23 chromosomes.\nDuring fertilization , when the egg and sperm join, the two sets of chromosomes come\ntogether?",
        "answer": "In this way, one half of a baby\u2019s genes come from the baby\u2019s mother and one\nFAQs\nWhat are genetic disorders?\nWhat are genes?\nWhat are chromosomes?\nhalf come from the baby\u2019s father.\nYour baby\u2019s sex is determined by sex chromosomes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In this way, one half of a baby\u2019s genes come from the baby\u2019s mother and one\nFAQs\nWhat are genetic disorders?\nWhat are genes?\nWhat are chromosomes?\nhalf come from the baby\u2019s father.\nYour baby\u2019s sex is determined by sex chromosomes?",
        "answer": "There are two sex chromosomes:\nX and Y"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There are two sex chromosomes:\nX and Y?",
        "answer": "Egg cells only contain an X chromosome"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Egg cells only contain an X chromosome?",
        "answer": "Sperm cells can carry an X or a Y"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Sperm cells can carry an X or a Y?",
        "answer": "A\ncombination of XX results in a girl and XY results in a boy.\nTypes of Genetic Disorders\nChromosome disorders involve having missing or extra chromosomes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A\ncombination of XX results in a girl and XY results in a boy.\nTypes of Genetic Disorders\nChromosome disorders involve having missing or extra chromosomes?",
        "answer": "This is called\naneuploidy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is called\naneuploidy?",
        "answer": "Most children with chromosome disorders have physical defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Most children with chromosome disorders have physical defects?",
        "answer": "Some\nhave intellectual disabilities.\nTrisomy  is the most common aneuploidy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some\nhave intellectual disabilities.\nTrisomy  is the most common aneuploidy?",
        "answer": "In trisomy, there is an extra chromosome"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In trisomy, there is an extra chromosome?",
        "answer": "A\ncommon trisomy is Down syndrome (trisomy 21)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A\ncommon trisomy is Down syndrome (trisomy 21)?",
        "answer": "Other trisomies include Patau\nsyndrome (trisomy 13)  and Edwards syndrome (trisomy 18) .\nMonosomy  is another type of aneuploidy in which there is a missing chromosome"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Other trisomies include Patau\nsyndrome (trisomy 13)  and Edwards syndrome (trisomy 18) .\nMonosomy  is another type of aneuploidy in which there is a missing chromosome?",
        "answer": "A\ncommon monosomy is Turner syndrome , in which a female has a missing or damaged\nX chromosome.\nThe risk of having a child with chromosome disorder increases as you age.\nAn inherited disorder is caused by a faulty gene that can be passed from parent to child.\nFaulty genes can occur on any of the chromosomes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A\ncommon monosomy is Turner syndrome , in which a female has a missing or damaged\nX chromosome.\nThe risk of having a child with chromosome disorder increases as you age.\nAn inherited disorder is caused by a faulty gene that can be passed from parent to child.\nFaulty genes can occur on any of the chromosomes?",
        "answer": "There are autosomal dominant\ndisorders , autosomal recessive disorders , and sex-linked disorders .\nAn autosomal dominant disorder is caused by just one faulty gene from either parent.\n\u201cAutosomal\u201d means that the defective gene is located on any of the chromosomes that\nare not the sex chromosomes (X or Y).\nIf one parent has the gene, each child of the couple has a 50 percent chance of\ninheriting the disorder"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There are autosomal dominant\ndisorders , autosomal recessive disorders , and sex-linked disorders .\nAn autosomal dominant disorder is caused by just one faulty gene from either parent.\n\u201cAutosomal\u201d means that the defective gene is located on any of the chromosomes that\nare not the sex chromosomes (X or Y).\nIf one parent has the gene, each child of the couple has a 50 percent chance of\ninheriting the disorder?",
        "answer": "An example of an autosomal dominant disorder is Huntington\nWhat are chromosome disorders?\nWhat are inherited disorders?\nWhat is an autosomal dominant disorder?\ndisease .\nAutosomal recessive disorders only happen when both parents carry the gene"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example of an autosomal dominant disorder is Huntington\nWhat are chromosome disorders?\nWhat are inherited disorders?\nWhat is an autosomal dominant disorder?\ndisease .\nAutosomal recessive disorders only happen when both parents carry the gene?",
        "answer": "An\nexample of an autosomal recessive disorder is cystic fibrosis (CF) .\nA carrier  of a recessive disorder is a person who carries one copy of a gene that works\nincorrectly and one that works normally"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An\nexample of an autosomal recessive disorder is cystic fibrosis (CF) .\nA carrier  of a recessive disorder is a person who carries one copy of a gene that works\nincorrectly and one that works normally?",
        "answer": "A carrier may not have symptoms of the\ndisorder or may have only mild symptoms.\nIf both parents are carriers of an abnormal gene, there is a 25 percent chance that the\nchild will get the abnormal gene from each parent and will have the disorder"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A carrier may not have symptoms of the\ndisorder or may have only mild symptoms.\nIf both parents are carriers of an abnormal gene, there is a 25 percent chance that the\nchild will get the abnormal gene from each parent and will have the disorder?",
        "answer": "There is a\n50 percent chance that the child will be a carrier of the disorder\u2014just like the carrier\nparents"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There is a\n50 percent chance that the child will be a carrier of the disorder\u2014just like the carrier\nparents?",
        "answer": "If only one parent is a carrier, there is a 50 percent chance that the child will be\na carrier.\nSex-linked disorders are caused by defective genes on the sex chromosomes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If only one parent is a carrier, there is a 50 percent chance that the child will be\na carrier.\nSex-linked disorders are caused by defective genes on the sex chromosomes?",
        "answer": "An\nexample of a sex-linked disorder is hemophilia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An\nexample of a sex-linked disorder is hemophilia?",
        "answer": "This disease is caused by a faulty gene\non the X chromosome.\nMultifactorial disorders are caused by a combination of factors"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This disease is caused by a faulty gene\non the X chromosome.\nMultifactorial disorders are caused by a combination of factors?",
        "answer": "Some factors are\ngenetic and some are not"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some factors are\ngenetic and some are not?",
        "answer": "A few of these disorders can be detected during pregnancy.\nSometimes they can be corrected with surgery.\nRisk Factors and Testing\nMost babies with genetic disorders are born to couples without risk factors"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A few of these disorders can be detected during pregnancy.\nSometimes they can be corrected with surgery.\nRisk Factors and Testing\nMost babies with genetic disorders are born to couples without risk factors?",
        "answer": "But the risk\nof genetic disorders is higher when certain factors are present"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But the risk\nof genetic disorders is higher when certain factors are present?",
        "answer": "This is why screening\nWhat is an autosomal recessive disorder?\nWhat does it mean to be a carrier of a recessive disorder?\nWhat are sex-linked disorders?\nWhat are multifactorial disorders?\nWho is at risk of having a baby with a genetic disorder?\nbegins by assessing your risk factors before or during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is why screening\nWhat is an autosomal recessive disorder?\nWhat does it mean to be a carrier of a recessive disorder?\nWhat are sex-linked disorders?\nWhat are multifactorial disorders?\nWho is at risk of having a baby with a genetic disorder?\nbegins by assessing your risk factors before or during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "You are at increased\nrisk if\nSome genetic disorders are more common in certain ethnic groups.\nA genetic counselor  has special training in genetics"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You are at increased\nrisk if\nSome genetic disorders are more common in certain ethnic groups.\nA genetic counselor  has special training in genetics?",
        "answer": "A genetic counselor will study your\nfamily health history and may recommend you have physical exams or tests with your\nobstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A genetic counselor will study your\nfamily health history and may recommend you have physical exams or tests with your\nobstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)?",
        "answer": "Using the test results, the counselor will assess\nyour baby\u2019s risk of having a problem, discuss your options, and talk about any concerns\nyou may have.\nScreening tests assess the risk that a baby may be born with a specific genetic disorder.\nDiagnostic tests can detect if a specific genetic disorder is present in the fetus.\n[ACOG Explains: Prenatal Genetic Testing]\nCarrier screening is a type of screening test that can show if a person carries a gene for\nan inherited disorder"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Using the test results, the counselor will assess\nyour baby\u2019s risk of having a problem, discuss your options, and talk about any concerns\nyou may have.\nScreening tests assess the risk that a baby may be born with a specific genetic disorder.\nDiagnostic tests can detect if a specific genetic disorder is present in the fetus.\n[ACOG Explains: Prenatal Genetic Testing]\nCarrier screening is a type of screening test that can show if a person carries a gene for\nan inherited disorder?",
        "answer": "Carrier screening can be done before or during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Carrier screening can be done before or during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Read\nCarrier Screening\u00a0to learn more.\nAnyone who is thinking about pregnancy or already pregnant can have carrier screening.\nYour partner may be tested too.\nCarrier screening can test for many disorders, including cystic fibrosis (CF), spinal\nmuscular atrophy (SMA) , and hemoglobinopathies"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\nCarrier Screening\u00a0to learn more.\nAnyone who is thinking about pregnancy or already pregnant can have carrier screening.\nYour partner may be tested too.\nCarrier screening can test for many disorders, including cystic fibrosis (CF), spinal\nmuscular atrophy (SMA) , and hemoglobinopathies?",
        "answer": "You can have tests for specific\nyou have a genetic disorder\n\u2022\nyou have a child with a genetic disorder\n\u2022\nthere is a family history of a genetic disorder\n\u2022\nWhat is genetic counseling?\nWhat types of prenatal genetic tests are available?\nWhat screening tests are offered before pregnancy?\nWho can have carrier screening?\ndisorders based on your risk factors, or you can have a test for many disorders without\nregard to risk factors.\nCarrier screening can be done any time during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can have tests for specific\nyou have a genetic disorder\n\u2022\nyou have a child with a genetic disorder\n\u2022\nthere is a family history of a genetic disorder\n\u2022\nWhat is genetic counseling?\nWhat types of prenatal genetic tests are available?\nWhat screening tests are offered before pregnancy?\nWho can have carrier screening?\ndisorders based on your risk factors, or you can have a test for many disorders without\nregard to risk factors.\nCarrier screening can be done any time during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Other screening tests that can\nbe done during pregnancy include the following:\nRead Prenatal Genetic Screening Tests to learn more about these tests.\nThere are no risks to the fetus with any of these screening tests.\nDiagnostic tests may be recommended if a screening test shows an increased risk of a\nbirth defect"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Other screening tests that can\nbe done during pregnancy include the following:\nRead Prenatal Genetic Screening Tests to learn more about these tests.\nThere are no risks to the fetus with any of these screening tests.\nDiagnostic tests may be recommended if a screening test shows an increased risk of a\nbirth defect?",
        "answer": "Diagnostic tests should also be offered as a first choice to everyone during\npregnancy, even if you do not have risk factors"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Diagnostic tests should also be offered as a first choice to everyone during\npregnancy, even if you do not have risk factors?",
        "answer": "Diagnostic tests can detect if a specific\nbirth defect or genetic disorder is present.\nDiagnostic tests are done on cells from the fetus obtained through amniocentesis ,\nchorionic villus sampling (CVS) , or rarely, fetal blood sampling"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Diagnostic tests can detect if a specific\nbirth defect or genetic disorder is present.\nDiagnostic tests are done on cells from the fetus obtained through amniocentesis ,\nchorionic villus sampling (CVS) , or rarely, fetal blood sampling?",
        "answer": "The chromosomes and\ngenes in the cells are analyzed using different techniques to diagnose certain inherited\ndefects and many chromosomal defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The chromosomes and\ngenes in the cells are analyzed using different techniques to diagnose certain inherited\ndefects and many chromosomal defects?",
        "answer": "Read Prenatal Genetic Diagnostic Tests to\nlearn more.\nWhat screening tests are offered during pregnancy?\nBlood tests that measure the level of certain substances in your blood combined with\nan ultrasound exam"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read Prenatal Genetic Diagnostic Tests to\nlearn more.\nWhat screening tests are offered during pregnancy?\nBlood tests that measure the level of certain substances in your blood combined with\nan ultrasound exam?",
        "answer": "These tests assess the risk that a baby will have Down\nsyndrome, other trisomies, or neural tube defects (NTDs) .\n\u2022\nCell-free DNA  screening (also called noninvasive prenatal testing or NIPT)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These tests assess the risk that a baby will have Down\nsyndrome, other trisomies, or neural tube defects (NTDs) .\n\u2022\nCell-free DNA  screening (also called noninvasive prenatal testing or NIPT)?",
        "answer": "Cell-free\nDNA is the small amount of DNA that is released from the placenta  into your\nbloodstream"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Cell-free\nDNA is the small amount of DNA that is released from the placenta  into your\nbloodstream?",
        "answer": "The cell-free DNA in a sample of your blood can be screened for Down\nsyndrome, other trisomies, and problems with the number of sex chromosomes.\n\u2022\nAre there risks to the fetus with screening tests?\nWhen are diagnostic tests offered during pregnancy?\nHow are diagnostic tests done?\nAre there risks to the pregnancy with diagnostic tests?\nYes, diagnostic tests carry a very small risk of pregnancy loss.\nYour ob-gyn or a genetic counselor can discuss all of the testing options with you and\nhelp you decide.\nWhether you want to be tested is a personal choice"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The cell-free DNA in a sample of your blood can be screened for Down\nsyndrome, other trisomies, and problems with the number of sex chromosomes.\n\u2022\nAre there risks to the fetus with screening tests?\nWhen are diagnostic tests offered during pregnancy?\nHow are diagnostic tests done?\nAre there risks to the pregnancy with diagnostic tests?\nYes, diagnostic tests carry a very small risk of pregnancy loss.\nYour ob-gyn or a genetic counselor can discuss all of the testing options with you and\nhelp you decide.\nWhether you want to be tested is a personal choice?",
        "answer": "Some people would rather not know\nif they are at risk or whether their child will have a disorder"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some people would rather not know\nif they are at risk or whether their child will have a disorder?",
        "answer": "Others want to know in\nadvance"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Others want to know in\nadvance?",
        "answer": "Knowing beforehand gives you time to prepare for having a child with a\ndisorder and to organize the medical care that your child may need"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Knowing beforehand gives you time to prepare for having a child with a\ndisorder and to organize the medical care that your child may need?",
        "answer": "Some parents may\ndecide to end the pregnancy in certain situations.\n[3 Questions to Ask Yourself Before Getting Prenatal Genetic Testing]\nAmniocentesis: A procedure in which amniotic fluid and cells are taken from the uterus\nfor testing"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some parents may\ndecide to end the pregnancy in certain situations.\n[3 Questions to Ask Yourself Before Getting Prenatal Genetic Testing]\nAmniocentesis: A procedure in which amniotic fluid and cells are taken from the uterus\nfor testing?",
        "answer": "The procedure uses a needle to withdraw fluid and cells from the sac that\nholds the fetus.\nAneuploidy: Having an abnormal number of chromosomes.\nAutosomal Dominant Disorders: Genetic disorders caused by one defective gene"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The procedure uses a needle to withdraw fluid and cells from the sac that\nholds the fetus.\nAneuploidy: Having an abnormal number of chromosomes.\nAutosomal Dominant Disorders: Genetic disorders caused by one defective gene?",
        "answer": "The\ndefective gene is located on one of the chromosomes that is not a sex chromosome.\nAutosomal Recessive Disorders: Genetic disorders caused by two defective genes, one\ninherited from each parent"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The\ndefective gene is located on one of the chromosomes that is not a sex chromosome.\nAutosomal Recessive Disorders: Genetic disorders caused by two defective genes, one\ninherited from each parent?",
        "answer": "The defective genes are located on one of the pairs of\nchromosomes that are not the sex chromosomes.\nCarrier: A person who shows no signs of a disorder but could pass the gene to his or\nher children.\nCell-Free DNA: DNA from the placenta that moves freely in a pregnant woman\u2019s blood.\nAnalysis of this DNA can be done as a noninvasive prenatal screening test.\nWhich tests should I have?\nDo I have to have these tests?\nGlossary\nCells: The smallest units of a structure in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The defective genes are located on one of the pairs of\nchromosomes that are not the sex chromosomes.\nCarrier: A person who shows no signs of a disorder but could pass the gene to his or\nher children.\nCell-Free DNA: DNA from the placenta that moves freely in a pregnant woman\u2019s blood.\nAnalysis of this DNA can be done as a noninvasive prenatal screening test.\nWhich tests should I have?\nDo I have to have these tests?\nGlossary\nCells: The smallest units of a structure in the body?",
        "answer": "Cells are the building blocks for all\nparts of the body.\nChorionic Villus Sampling (CVS): A procedure in which a small sample of cells is taken\nfrom the placenta and tested.\nChromosomes: Structures that are located inside each cell in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Cells are the building blocks for all\nparts of the body.\nChorionic Villus Sampling (CVS): A procedure in which a small sample of cells is taken\nfrom the placenta and tested.\nChromosomes: Structures that are located inside each cell in the body?",
        "answer": "They contain the\ngenes that determine a person\u2019s physical makeup.\nCystic Fibrosis (CF): An inherited disorder that causes problems with breathing and\ndigestion.\nDiagnostic Tests: Tests that look for a disease or cause of a disease.\nDNA: The genetic material that is passed down from parent to child"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They contain the\ngenes that determine a person\u2019s physical makeup.\nCystic Fibrosis (CF): An inherited disorder that causes problems with breathing and\ndigestion.\nDiagnostic Tests: Tests that look for a disease or cause of a disease.\nDNA: The genetic material that is passed down from parent to child?",
        "answer": "DNA is packaged in\nstructures called chromosomes.\nDown Syndrome (Trisomy 21): A genetic disorder that causes abnormal features of the\nface and body, medical problems such as heart defects, and mental disability"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is DNA is packaged in\nstructures called chromosomes.\nDown Syndrome (Trisomy 21): A genetic disorder that causes abnormal features of the\nface and body, medical problems such as heart defects, and mental disability?",
        "answer": "Most\ncases of Down syndrome are caused by an extra chromosome 21 (trisomy 21).\nEdwards Syndrome (Trisomy 18): A genetic condition that causes serious problems"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Most\ncases of Down syndrome are caused by an extra chromosome 21 (trisomy 21).\nEdwards Syndrome (Trisomy 18): A genetic condition that causes serious problems?",
        "answer": "It\ncauses a small head, heart defects, and deafness.\nEgg: The female reproductive cell produced in and released from the ovaries"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\ncauses a small head, heart defects, and deafness.\nEgg: The female reproductive cell produced in and released from the ovaries?",
        "answer": "Also\ncalled the ovum.\nFertilization: A multistep process that joins the egg and the sperm.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nGene: A segment of DNA that contains instructions for the development of a person\u2019s\nphysical traits and control of the processes in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also\ncalled the ovum.\nFertilization: A multistep process that joins the egg and the sperm.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nGene: A segment of DNA that contains instructions for the development of a person\u2019s\nphysical traits and control of the processes in the body?",
        "answer": "The gene is the basic unit of\nheredity and can be passed from parent to child.\nGenetic Counselor: A health care professional with special training in genetics who can\nprovide expert advice about genetic disorders and prenatal testing.\nHemoglobinopathies: Any inherited disorder that affects the number or shape of red\nblood cells in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The gene is the basic unit of\nheredity and can be passed from parent to child.\nGenetic Counselor: A health care professional with special training in genetics who can\nprovide expert advice about genetic disorders and prenatal testing.\nHemoglobinopathies: Any inherited disorder that affects the number or shape of red\nblood cells in the body?",
        "answer": "Examples include sickle cell disease and the different forms of\nthalassemia.\nHemophilia: A disorder caused by a mutation on the X chromosome"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Examples include sickle cell disease and the different forms of\nthalassemia.\nHemophilia: A disorder caused by a mutation on the X chromosome?",
        "answer": "Affected people\nare usually males who lack a substance in the blood that helps clotting"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Affected people\nare usually males who lack a substance in the blood that helps clotting?",
        "answer": "People with\nhemophilia are at risk of severe bleeding from even minor injuries.\nHuntington Disease: A disorder that causes loss of control of body movements and\nmental function.\nMonosomy: A condition in which there is a missing chromosome\nNeural Tube Defects (NTDs): Birth defects that result from a problem in development of\nthe brain, spinal cord, or their coverings.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPatau Syndrome (Trisomy 13): A genetic condition that causes serious problems"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is People with\nhemophilia are at risk of severe bleeding from even minor injuries.\nHuntington Disease: A disorder that causes loss of control of body movements and\nmental function.\nMonosomy: A condition in which there is a missing chromosome\nNeural Tube Defects (NTDs): Birth defects that result from a problem in development of\nthe brain, spinal cord, or their coverings.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPatau Syndrome (Trisomy 13): A genetic condition that causes serious problems?",
        "answer": "It\ninvolves the heart and brain, cleft lip and palate, and extra fingers and toes.\nPlacenta: An organ that provides nutrients to and takes waste away from the fetus.\nScreening Tests: Tests that look for possible signs of disease in people who do not\nhave signs or symptoms.\nSex-Linked Disorders: Genetic disorders caused by a change in a gene located on the\nsex chromosomes.\nSperm: A cell produced in the male testicles that can fertilize a female egg.\nSpinal Muscular Atrophy (SMA): An inherited disorder that causes wasting of the\nmuscles and severe weakness"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\ninvolves the heart and brain, cleft lip and palate, and extra fingers and toes.\nPlacenta: An organ that provides nutrients to and takes waste away from the fetus.\nScreening Tests: Tests that look for possible signs of disease in people who do not\nhave signs or symptoms.\nSex-Linked Disorders: Genetic disorders caused by a change in a gene located on the\nsex chromosomes.\nSperm: A cell produced in the male testicles that can fertilize a female egg.\nSpinal Muscular Atrophy (SMA): An inherited disorder that causes wasting of the\nmuscles and severe weakness?",
        "answer": "SMA is the leading genetic cause of death in infants.\nTrisomy: A problem where there is an extra chromosome.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\nTurner Syndrome: A problem that affects women when there is a missing or damaged X\nchromosome"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is SMA is the leading genetic cause of death in infants.\nTrisomy: A problem where there is an extra chromosome.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\nTurner Syndrome: A problem that affects women when there is a missing or damaged X\nchromosome?",
        "answer": "This syndrome causes a webbed neck, short height, and heart problems.\nUltrasound Exam: A test in which sound waves are used to examine inner parts of the\nbody"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This syndrome causes a webbed neck, short height, and heart problems.\nUltrasound Exam: A test in which sound waves are used to examine inner parts of the\nbody?",
        "answer": "During pregnancy, ultrasound can be used to check the fetus.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ094\nLast updated: May 2023\nLast reviewed: December 2022\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During pregnancy, ultrasound can be used to check the fetus.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ094\nLast updated: May 2023\nLast reviewed: December 2022\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nIs it safe to have sex during pregnancy?\nMost sexual activity is safe for women having healthy pregnancies"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nIs it safe to have sex during pregnancy?\nMost sexual activity is safe for women having healthy pregnancies?",
        "answer": "This\nincludes sexual intercourse or penetration with fingers or sex toys"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This\nincludes sexual intercourse or penetration with fingers or sex toys?",
        "answer": "The amniotic\nsac and the strong muscles of the uterus protect the fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The amniotic\nsac and the strong muscles of the uterus protect the fetus?",
        "answer": "If you have\npregnancy complications or questions about what may be safe sexual activity\nfor you, talk with your ob-gyn.\nIt is normal to have cramps or spotting after sex with penetration"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have\npregnancy complications or questions about what may be safe sexual activity\nfor you, talk with your ob-gyn.\nIt is normal to have cramps or spotting after sex with penetration?",
        "answer": "Also, orgasm\ncan cause cramps"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also, orgasm\ncan cause cramps?",
        "answer": "If you have severe, persistent cramping, or if your bleeding is\nheavy (like normal menstrual bleeding), call your ob-gyn.\nOf course, it\u2019s up to you whether you feel like having sex"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have severe, persistent cramping, or if your bleeding is\nheavy (like normal menstrual bleeding), call your ob-gyn.\nOf course, it\u2019s up to you whether you feel like having sex?",
        "answer": "Some women do, and\nsome don\u2019t"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some women do, and\nsome don\u2019t?",
        "answer": "During the first trimester, you may feel too nauseated and tired to\nhave sex"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During the first trimester, you may feel too nauseated and tired to\nhave sex?",
        "answer": "But you may find that your sex drive comes back during the second\ntrimester after morning sickness goes away and you have your energy again"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But you may find that your sex drive comes back during the second\ntrimester after morning sickness goes away and you have your energy again?",
        "answer": "It\u2019s\nalso normal for desire to wane again during the third trimester"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\u2019s\nalso normal for desire to wane again during the third trimester?",
        "answer": "Whatever your\nmood, talk with your partner.\nAs your belly grows, you can try different positions to find what is most\ncomfortable for you"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Whatever your\nmood, talk with your partner.\nAs your belly grows, you can try different positions to find what is most\ncomfortable for you?",
        "answer": "Let your partner know if anything feels uncomfortable,\neven if it\u2019s something you\u2019re used to doing.\nAsk ACOG\n\ue921\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nPublished: February 2021\nLast reviewed: February 2021\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Let your partner know if anything feels uncomfortable,\neven if it\u2019s something you\u2019re used to doing.\nAsk ACOG\n\ue921\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nPublished: February 2021\nLast reviewed: February 2021\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved.\nRead copyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved.\nRead copyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It\ndoes not explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\ndoes not explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the\nadvice of a physician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the\nadvice of a physician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nListeria and Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nListeria is a kind of bacteria that is found in soil, water, and some animals, including\ncattle and poultry"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nListeria and Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nListeria is a kind of bacteria that is found in soil, water, and some animals, including\ncattle and poultry?",
        "answer": "When eaten, Listeria causes a foodborne illness called listeriosis .\nListeriosis is one of the most serious types of food poisoning.\nListeriosis can cause mild, flu-like symptoms such as fever, chills, muscle aches, and\ndiarrhea or upset stomach"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When eaten, Listeria causes a foodborne illness called listeriosis .\nListeriosis is one of the most serious types of food poisoning.\nListeriosis can cause mild, flu-like symptoms such as fever, chills, muscle aches, and\ndiarrhea or upset stomach?",
        "answer": "You also may have a stiff neck, headache, confusion, or loss\nof balance"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You also may have a stiff neck, headache, confusion, or loss\nof balance?",
        "answer": "Symptoms may appear as late as 2 months after you have eaten something\nwith Listeria"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Symptoms may appear as late as 2 months after you have eaten something\nwith Listeria?",
        "answer": "Many pregnant women do not have any symptoms"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Many pregnant women do not have any symptoms?",
        "answer": "Even if you do not feel\nsick, you can pass the infection to your fetus .\nPregnant women are 10 times more likely to get listeriosis than the general population.\nVomiting and diarrhea can cause the body to lose too much water"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Even if you do not feel\nsick, you can pass the infection to your fetus .\nPregnant women are 10 times more likely to get listeriosis than the general population.\nVomiting and diarrhea can cause the body to lose too much water?",
        "answer": "This is called\ndehydration"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is called\ndehydration?",
        "answer": "Listeriosis also can cause miscarriage , stillbirth , or preterm  labor.\nBabies born with listeriosis may have serious infections of the blood or brain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Listeriosis also can cause miscarriage , stillbirth , or preterm  labor.\nBabies born with listeriosis may have serious infections of the blood or brain?",
        "answer": "Listeriosis\ncan cause lifelong health problems for your baby, including intellectual disability,\nFAQs\nWhat is Listeria?\nWhat are the symptoms of listeriosis?\nHow can listeriosis affect pregnant women?\nHow can listeriosis affect my baby?\nparalysis, seizures, blindness, or problems with the brain, kidneys, or heart"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Listeriosis\ncan cause lifelong health problems for your baby, including intellectual disability,\nFAQs\nWhat is Listeria?\nWhat are the symptoms of listeriosis?\nHow can listeriosis affect pregnant women?\nHow can listeriosis affect my baby?\nparalysis, seizures, blindness, or problems with the brain, kidneys, or heart?",
        "answer": "Listeriosis\nalso can cause death in newborns.\nIf you think you have eaten food contaminated with Listeria or if you have any of the\nsymptoms of listeriosis, contact your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  or other\nhealth care professional right away"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Listeriosis\nalso can cause death in newborns.\nIf you think you have eaten food contaminated with Listeria or if you have any of the\nsymptoms of listeriosis, contact your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  or other\nhealth care professional right away?",
        "answer": "Remember that it can take 2 months for symptoms\nto appear.\nYour ob-gyn or other health care professional may give you a blood test to see if you\nhave listeriosis"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Remember that it can take 2 months for symptoms\nto appear.\nYour ob-gyn or other health care professional may give you a blood test to see if you\nhave listeriosis?",
        "answer": "You may need to take antibiotics  to treat the infection and prevent your\nfetus from becoming infected.\nTo help prevent listeriosis, avoid eating the following foods while you are pregnant:\nAvoid all raw and undercooked seafood, eggs, meat, and poultry while you are pregnant.\nDo not eat sushi made with raw fish (cooked sushi is safe)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may need to take antibiotics  to treat the infection and prevent your\nfetus from becoming infected.\nTo help prevent listeriosis, avoid eating the following foods while you are pregnant:\nAvoid all raw and undercooked seafood, eggs, meat, and poultry while you are pregnant.\nDo not eat sushi made with raw fish (cooked sushi is safe)?",
        "answer": "Cooking and pasteurization\nare the only ways to kill Listeria.\nFollow these steps for food safety:\nClean\nWhat should I do if I think I have listeriosis?\nHow is listeriosis treated?\nHow can I help prevent listeriosis?\nUnpasteurized milk and foods made with unpasteurized milk, including soft cheeses\n\u2022\nHot dogs and luncheon meats, unless they are heated until steaming hot just before\nserving\n\u2022\nRefrigerated p\u00e2t\u00e9 and meat spreads\n\u2022\nRefrigerated smoked seafood\n\u2022\nUnwashed raw produce such as fruits and vegetables\n\u2022\nWhat other food safety guidelines should I follow?\nSeparate\nCook\nChill\nWash your hands for at least 20 seconds before and after touching raw food, and\nafter using the bathroom, changing diapers, or touching an animal.\n\u2022\nRinse all raw produce thoroughly under running water before eating, peeling, cutting,\nor cooking.\n\u2022\nDo not rinse raw meat or poultry before cooking"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Cooking and pasteurization\nare the only ways to kill Listeria.\nFollow these steps for food safety:\nClean\nWhat should I do if I think I have listeriosis?\nHow is listeriosis treated?\nHow can I help prevent listeriosis?\nUnpasteurized milk and foods made with unpasteurized milk, including soft cheeses\n\u2022\nHot dogs and luncheon meats, unless they are heated until steaming hot just before\nserving\n\u2022\nRefrigerated p\u00e2t\u00e9 and meat spreads\n\u2022\nRefrigerated smoked seafood\n\u2022\nUnwashed raw produce such as fruits and vegetables\n\u2022\nWhat other food safety guidelines should I follow?\nSeparate\nCook\nChill\nWash your hands for at least 20 seconds before and after touching raw food, and\nafter using the bathroom, changing diapers, or touching an animal.\n\u2022\nRinse all raw produce thoroughly under running water before eating, peeling, cutting,\nor cooking.\n\u2022\nDo not rinse raw meat or poultry before cooking?",
        "answer": "That can spread bacteria to other\nkitchen surfaces.\n\u2022\nKeep your kitchen clean"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is That can spread bacteria to other\nkitchen surfaces.\n\u2022\nKeep your kitchen clean?",
        "answer": "Wash your utensils, countertops, and cutting boards with\nsoap and hot water after using them.\n\u2022\nKeep raw meat, poultry, eggs, seafood, and their juices away from other food.\n\u2022\nUse a separate cutting board for raw meat, poultry, and seafood.\n\u2022\nDo not put cooked food on a plate that also held raw food, unless the plate was\nwashed.\n\u2022\nDo not put cooked food in the same sauce that was used to marinate raw food,\nunless the sauce is boiled first.\n\u2022\nUse a food thermometer to check that meat, poultry, seafood, and eggs are at a safe\ntemperature.\n\u2022\nPlace the food thermometer in the thickest part of the food, away from bone, fat, and\ngristle.\n\u2022\nCover, stir, and rotate food in a microwave to cook the food evenly"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Wash your utensils, countertops, and cutting boards with\nsoap and hot water after using them.\n\u2022\nKeep raw meat, poultry, eggs, seafood, and their juices away from other food.\n\u2022\nUse a separate cutting board for raw meat, poultry, and seafood.\n\u2022\nDo not put cooked food on a plate that also held raw food, unless the plate was\nwashed.\n\u2022\nDo not put cooked food in the same sauce that was used to marinate raw food,\nunless the sauce is boiled first.\n\u2022\nUse a food thermometer to check that meat, poultry, seafood, and eggs are at a safe\ntemperature.\n\u2022\nPlace the food thermometer in the thickest part of the food, away from bone, fat, and\ngristle.\n\u2022\nCover, stir, and rotate food in a microwave to cook the food evenly?",
        "answer": "Allow for standing\ntime before using a food thermometer.\n\u2022\nKeep your refrigerator at 40\u00b0F or below and your freezer at 0\u00b0F or below.\n\u2022\nThaw food in a refrigerator, microwave, or cold water"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Allow for standing\ntime before using a food thermometer.\n\u2022\nKeep your refrigerator at 40\u00b0F or below and your freezer at 0\u00b0F or below.\n\u2022\nThaw food in a refrigerator, microwave, or cold water?",
        "answer": "Cook food immediately after\nthawing in a microwave or cold water.\n\u2022\nMeat and poultry thawed in the refrigerator may be refrozen before or after cooking.\nIf thawed in a microwave or cold water, cook before refreezing.\n\u2022\nAntibiotics: Drugs that treat certain types of infections.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nListeriosis: A type of illness you can get from bacteria found in unpasteurized milk, hot\ndogs, luncheon meats, and smoked seafood.\nMiscarriage: Loss of a pregnancy that is in the uterus.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPasteurization: The process of heating certain foods to a specific temperature for a set\nperiod of time to kill harmful bacteria.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nStillbirth: Birth of a dead fetus.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ501\nPublished: June 2018\nDo not leave perishable food at room temperature for more than 2 hours (1 hour\nwhen the outside temperature is above 90\u00b0F).\n\u2022\nOnly buy eggs that are refrigerated"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Cook food immediately after\nthawing in a microwave or cold water.\n\u2022\nMeat and poultry thawed in the refrigerator may be refrozen before or after cooking.\nIf thawed in a microwave or cold water, cook before refreezing.\n\u2022\nAntibiotics: Drugs that treat certain types of infections.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nListeriosis: A type of illness you can get from bacteria found in unpasteurized milk, hot\ndogs, luncheon meats, and smoked seafood.\nMiscarriage: Loss of a pregnancy that is in the uterus.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPasteurization: The process of heating certain foods to a specific temperature for a set\nperiod of time to kill harmful bacteria.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nStillbirth: Birth of a dead fetus.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ501\nPublished: June 2018\nDo not leave perishable food at room temperature for more than 2 hours (1 hour\nwhen the outside temperature is above 90\u00b0F).\n\u2022\nOnly buy eggs that are refrigerated?",
        "answer": "Store eggs in the refrigerator in their original\ncarton and use within 3\u20135 weeks.\n\u2022\nOnly buy precut produce that is refrigerated or surrounded by ice"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Store eggs in the refrigerator in their original\ncarton and use within 3\u20135 weeks.\n\u2022\nOnly buy precut produce that is refrigerated or surrounded by ice?",
        "answer": "Keep precut\nproduce refrigerated at home.\n\u2022\nGlossary\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nLast reviewed: August 2022\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Keep precut\nproduce refrigerated at home.\n\u2022\nGlossary\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nLast reviewed: August 2022\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nNutrition During Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nOverview\nEating well is one of the best things you can do during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nNutrition During Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nOverview\nEating well is one of the best things you can do during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Good nutrition helps\nyou handle the extra demands on your body as your pregnancy progresses"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Good nutrition helps\nyou handle the extra demands on your body as your pregnancy progresses?",
        "answer": "The goal is\nto balance getting enough nutrients to support the growth of your fetus  and\nmaintaining a healthy weight.\nThe popular saying is that you should \u201ceat for two\u201d when you're pregnant, but now we\nknow that it\u2019s dangerous to eat twice your usual amount of food during pregnancy.\nInstead of \u201ceating for two,\u201d think of it as eating twice as healthy.\nIf you are pregnant with one fetus, you need an extra 340 calories  per day starting in\nthe second trimester (and a bit more in the third trimester)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The goal is\nto balance getting enough nutrients to support the growth of your fetus  and\nmaintaining a healthy weight.\nThe popular saying is that you should \u201ceat for two\u201d when you're pregnant, but now we\nknow that it\u2019s dangerous to eat twice your usual amount of food during pregnancy.\nInstead of \u201ceating for two,\u201d think of it as eating twice as healthy.\nIf you are pregnant with one fetus, you need an extra 340 calories  per day starting in\nthe second trimester (and a bit more in the third trimester)?",
        "answer": "That's roughly the calorie\ncount of a glass of skim milk and half a sandwich.\nIf you are carrying twins, you should get about 600 extra calories a day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is That's roughly the calorie\ncount of a glass of skim milk and half a sandwich.\nIf you are carrying twins, you should get about 600 extra calories a day?",
        "answer": "If you are\ncarrying triplets, you should take in 900 extra calories a day.\nKey Vitamins and Minerals\nFAQs\nWhy is nutrition during pregnancy important?\nHow much should I eat during pregnancy?\nVitamins and minerals play important roles in all of your body functions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are\ncarrying triplets, you should take in 900 extra calories a day.\nKey Vitamins and Minerals\nFAQs\nWhy is nutrition during pregnancy important?\nHow much should I eat during pregnancy?\nVitamins and minerals play important roles in all of your body functions?",
        "answer": "Eating healthy\nfoods and taking a prenatal vitamin every day should supply all the vitamins and\nminerals you need during pregnancy.\nTake only one serving of your prenatal supplement each day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Eating healthy\nfoods and taking a prenatal vitamin every day should supply all the vitamins and\nminerals you need during pregnancy.\nTake only one serving of your prenatal supplement each day?",
        "answer": "Read the bottle to see how\nmany pills make up one daily serving"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read the bottle to see how\nmany pills make up one daily serving?",
        "answer": "If your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  thinks\nyou need an extra amount of a vitamin or mineral, your ob-gyn may recommend it as a\nseparate supplement.\nNo, do not take more than the recommended amount of your prenatal vitamin per day.\nSome multivitamin ingredients, such as vitamin A, can cause birth defects  at higher\ndoses.\nDuring pregnancy you need folic acid , iron, calcium, vitamin D, choline, omega-3 fatty\nacids, B vitamins, and vitamin C"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  thinks\nyou need an extra amount of a vitamin or mineral, your ob-gyn may recommend it as a\nseparate supplement.\nNo, do not take more than the recommended amount of your prenatal vitamin per day.\nSome multivitamin ingredients, such as vitamin A, can cause birth defects  at higher\ndoses.\nDuring pregnancy you need folic acid , iron, calcium, vitamin D, choline, omega-3 fatty\nacids, B vitamins, and vitamin C?",
        "answer": "See the below table for recommended amounts.\nKey Vitamins and Minerals During Pregnancy\nNutrient (Daily\nRecommended Amount)\nWhy You and Your\nFetus Need It\nBest Sources\nCalcium (1,300\nmilligrams for ages 14 to\n18; 1,000 milligrams for\nages 19 to 50)\nBuilds strong bones\nand teeth\nMilk, cheese, yogurt, sardines, dark\ngreen leafy vegetables\nIron (27 milligrams)\nHelps red blood cells\ndeliver oxygen  to your\nfetus\nLean red meat, poultry, fish, dried\nbeans and peas, iron-fortified\ncereals, prune juice\nIodine (220 micrograms) Essential for healthy\nbrain development\nIodized table salt, dairy products,\nseafood, meat, some breads, eggs\nWhy should I take a prenatal vitamin?\nHow many prenatal vitamins should I take each day?\nCan I take more prenatal vitamins to make up for a deficiency?\nWhat vitamins and minerals do I need during pregnancy?\nNutrient (Daily\nRecommended Amount)\nWhy You and Your\nFetus Need It\nBest Sources\nCholine (450 milligrams) Important for\ndevelopment of your\nfetus\u2019s brain and spinal\ncord\nMilk, beef liver, eggs, peanuts, soy\nproducts\nVitamin A (750\nmicrograms for ages 14\nto 18; 770 micrograms\nfor ages 19 to 50)\nForms healthy skin and\neyesight\nHelps with bone\ngrowth\nCarrots, green leafy vegetables,\nsweet potatoes\nVitamin C (80 milligrams\nfor ages 14 to 18; 85\nmilligrams for ages 19 to\n50)\nPromotes healthy\ngums, teeth, and bones\nCitrus fruit, broccoli, tomatoes,\nstrawberries\nVitamin D (600\ninternational units)\nBuilds your fetus\u2019s\nbones and teeth\nHelps promote healthy\neyesight and skin\nSunlight, fortified milk, fatty fish such\nas salmon and sardines\nVitamin B6 (1.9\nmilligrams)\nHelps form red blood\ncells\nHelps body use\nprotein, fat, and\ncarbohydrates\nBeef, liver, pork, ham, whole-grain\ncereals, bananas\nVitamin B12 (2.6\nmicrograms)\nMaintains nervous\nsystem\nMeat, fish, poultry, milk (vegetarians\nshould take a supplement)\nNutrient (Daily\nRecommended Amount)\nWhy You and Your\nFetus Need It\nBest Sources\nHelps form red blood\ncells\nFolic acid (600\nmicrograms)\nHelps prevent birth\ndefects of the brain\nand spine\nSupports the general\ngrowth and\ndevelopment of the\nfetus and placenta\nFortified cereal, enriched bread and\npasta, peanuts, dark green leafy\nvegetables, orange juice, beans.\nAlso, take a daily prenatal vitamin\nwith 400 micrograms of folic acid.\nFolic acid, also known as folate, is a B vitamin that is important during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is See the below table for recommended amounts.\nKey Vitamins and Minerals During Pregnancy\nNutrient (Daily\nRecommended Amount)\nWhy You and Your\nFetus Need It\nBest Sources\nCalcium (1,300\nmilligrams for ages 14 to\n18; 1,000 milligrams for\nages 19 to 50)\nBuilds strong bones\nand teeth\nMilk, cheese, yogurt, sardines, dark\ngreen leafy vegetables\nIron (27 milligrams)\nHelps red blood cells\ndeliver oxygen  to your\nfetus\nLean red meat, poultry, fish, dried\nbeans and peas, iron-fortified\ncereals, prune juice\nIodine (220 micrograms) Essential for healthy\nbrain development\nIodized table salt, dairy products,\nseafood, meat, some breads, eggs\nWhy should I take a prenatal vitamin?\nHow many prenatal vitamins should I take each day?\nCan I take more prenatal vitamins to make up for a deficiency?\nWhat vitamins and minerals do I need during pregnancy?\nNutrient (Daily\nRecommended Amount)\nWhy You and Your\nFetus Need It\nBest Sources\nCholine (450 milligrams) Important for\ndevelopment of your\nfetus\u2019s brain and spinal\ncord\nMilk, beef liver, eggs, peanuts, soy\nproducts\nVitamin A (750\nmicrograms for ages 14\nto 18; 770 micrograms\nfor ages 19 to 50)\nForms healthy skin and\neyesight\nHelps with bone\ngrowth\nCarrots, green leafy vegetables,\nsweet potatoes\nVitamin C (80 milligrams\nfor ages 14 to 18; 85\nmilligrams for ages 19 to\n50)\nPromotes healthy\ngums, teeth, and bones\nCitrus fruit, broccoli, tomatoes,\nstrawberries\nVitamin D (600\ninternational units)\nBuilds your fetus\u2019s\nbones and teeth\nHelps promote healthy\neyesight and skin\nSunlight, fortified milk, fatty fish such\nas salmon and sardines\nVitamin B6 (1.9\nmilligrams)\nHelps form red blood\ncells\nHelps body use\nprotein, fat, and\ncarbohydrates\nBeef, liver, pork, ham, whole-grain\ncereals, bananas\nVitamin B12 (2.6\nmicrograms)\nMaintains nervous\nsystem\nMeat, fish, poultry, milk (vegetarians\nshould take a supplement)\nNutrient (Daily\nRecommended Amount)\nWhy You and Your\nFetus Need It\nBest Sources\nHelps form red blood\ncells\nFolic acid (600\nmicrograms)\nHelps prevent birth\ndefects of the brain\nand spine\nSupports the general\ngrowth and\ndevelopment of the\nfetus and placenta\nFortified cereal, enriched bread and\npasta, peanuts, dark green leafy\nvegetables, orange juice, beans.\nAlso, take a daily prenatal vitamin\nwith 400 micrograms of folic acid.\nFolic acid, also known as folate, is a B vitamin that is important during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Folic\nacid may help prevent major birth defects of the fetus\u2019s brain and spine called neural\ntube defects (NTDs) .\nWhen you are pregnant you need 600 micrograms of folic acid each day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Folic\nacid may help prevent major birth defects of the fetus\u2019s brain and spine called neural\ntube defects (NTDs) .\nWhen you are pregnant you need 600 micrograms of folic acid each day?",
        "answer": "Because it\u2019s\nhard to get this much folic acid from food alone, you should take a daily prenatal vitamin\nwith at least 400 micrograms starting at least 1 month before pregnancy and during the\nfirst 12 weeks of pregnancy.\nIf you have already had a child with an NTD, you should take 4 milligrams (mg) of folic\nacid each day as a separate supplement at least 3 months before pregnancy and for the\nfirst 3 months of pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Because it\u2019s\nhard to get this much folic acid from food alone, you should take a daily prenatal vitamin\nwith at least 400 micrograms starting at least 1 month before pregnancy and during the\nfirst 12 weeks of pregnancy.\nIf you have already had a child with an NTD, you should take 4 milligrams (mg) of folic\nacid each day as a separate supplement at least 3 months before pregnancy and for the\nfirst 3 months of pregnancy?",
        "answer": "You and your ob-gyn can discuss whether you need to\nsupplement with more than 400 micrograms daily.\nIron is used by your body to make the extra blood that you and your fetus need during\npregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You and your ob-gyn can discuss whether you need to\nsupplement with more than 400 micrograms daily.\nIron is used by your body to make the extra blood that you and your fetus need during\npregnancy?",
        "answer": "When you are not pregnant, you need 18 mg of iron per day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When you are not pregnant, you need 18 mg of iron per day?",
        "answer": "When you are\npregnant, you need 27 mg per day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When you are\npregnant, you need 27 mg per day?",
        "answer": "You can get this amount in most prenatal vitamins.\nWhat is folic acid?\nHow much folic acid should I take?\nWhy is iron important during pregnancy?\nIn addition to taking a prenatal vitamin with iron, you should eat iron-rich foods such as\nbeans, lentils, enriched breakfast cereals, beef, turkey, liver, and shrimp"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can get this amount in most prenatal vitamins.\nWhat is folic acid?\nHow much folic acid should I take?\nWhy is iron important during pregnancy?\nIn addition to taking a prenatal vitamin with iron, you should eat iron-rich foods such as\nbeans, lentils, enriched breakfast cereals, beef, turkey, liver, and shrimp?",
        "answer": "You should also\neat foods that help your body absorb iron, including oranges, grapefruit, strawberries,\nbroccoli, and peppers.\nYour blood should be tested during pregnancy to check for anemia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You should also\neat foods that help your body absorb iron, including oranges, grapefruit, strawberries,\nbroccoli, and peppers.\nYour blood should be tested during pregnancy to check for anemia?",
        "answer": "If you have anemia,\nyour ob-gyn may recommend extra iron supplements.\nCalcium is a mineral that builds your fetus\u2019s bones and teeth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have anemia,\nyour ob-gyn may recommend extra iron supplements.\nCalcium is a mineral that builds your fetus\u2019s bones and teeth?",
        "answer": "If you are 18 or younger,\nyou need 1,300 mg of calcium per day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are 18 or younger,\nyou need 1,300 mg of calcium per day?",
        "answer": "If you are 19 or older, you need 1,000 mg per day.\nMilk and other dairy products, such as cheese and yogurt, are the best sources of\ncalcium"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are 19 or older, you need 1,000 mg per day.\nMilk and other dairy products, such as cheese and yogurt, are the best sources of\ncalcium?",
        "answer": "If you have trouble digesting milk products, you can get calcium from other\nsources, such as broccoli, fortified foods (cereals, breads, and juices), almonds and\nsesame seeds, sardines or anchovies with the bones, and dark green leafy vegetables.\nYou can also get calcium from calcium supplements.\nVitamin D works with calcium to help the fetus\u2019s bones and teeth develop"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have trouble digesting milk products, you can get calcium from other\nsources, such as broccoli, fortified foods (cereals, breads, and juices), almonds and\nsesame seeds, sardines or anchovies with the bones, and dark green leafy vegetables.\nYou can also get calcium from calcium supplements.\nVitamin D works with calcium to help the fetus\u2019s bones and teeth develop?",
        "answer": "Vitamin D is\nalso essential for healthy skin and eyesight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Vitamin D is\nalso essential for healthy skin and eyesight?",
        "answer": "Whether you are pregnant or not, you need\n600 international units of vitamin D a day.\nGood sources of vitamin D include fortified milk and breakfast cereal, fatty fish (salmon\nand mackerel), fish liver oils, and egg yolks.\nMany people do not get enough vitamin D"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Whether you are pregnant or not, you need\n600 international units of vitamin D a day.\nGood sources of vitamin D include fortified milk and breakfast cereal, fatty fish (salmon\nand mackerel), fish liver oils, and egg yolks.\nMany people do not get enough vitamin D?",
        "answer": "If your ob-gyn\u00a0thinks you may have low levels\nof vitamin D, a test can be done to check the level in your blood"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If your ob-gyn\u00a0thinks you may have low levels\nof vitamin D, a test can be done to check the level in your blood?",
        "answer": "If it is below normal,\nyou may need to take a vitamin D supplement.\nHow can I make sure I\u2019m getting enough iron?\nWhat is calcium and what foods contain it?\nWhat is vitamin D and what foods contain it?\nHow will I know if I\u2019m getting enough vitamin D?\nWhat is choline and what foods contain it?\nCholine plays a role in your fetus\u2019s brain development"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If it is below normal,\nyou may need to take a vitamin D supplement.\nHow can I make sure I\u2019m getting enough iron?\nWhat is calcium and what foods contain it?\nWhat is vitamin D and what foods contain it?\nHow will I know if I\u2019m getting enough vitamin D?\nWhat is choline and what foods contain it?\nCholine plays a role in your fetus\u2019s brain development?",
        "answer": "It may also help prevent some\ncommon birth defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It may also help prevent some\ncommon birth defects?",
        "answer": "Experts recommend that you get 450 mg of choline each day\nduring pregnancy.\nCholine can be found in chicken, beef, eggs, milk, soy products, and peanuts"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Experts recommend that you get 450 mg of choline each day\nduring pregnancy.\nCholine can be found in chicken, beef, eggs, milk, soy products, and peanuts?",
        "answer": "Although\nthe body produces some choline on its own, it doesn\u2019t make enough to meet all your\nneeds while you are pregnant"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Although\nthe body produces some choline on its own, it doesn\u2019t make enough to meet all your\nneeds while you are pregnant?",
        "answer": "It\u2019s important to get choline from your diet because it is\nnot found in most prenatal vitamins.\nOmega-3 fatty acids are a type of fat found naturally in many kinds of fish"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\u2019s important to get choline from your diet because it is\nnot found in most prenatal vitamins.\nOmega-3 fatty acids are a type of fat found naturally in many kinds of fish?",
        "answer": "Omega-3s\nmay be important for brain development before and after birth.\nFlaxseed (ground or as oil) is also a good source of omega-3s"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Omega-3s\nmay be important for brain development before and after birth.\nFlaxseed (ground or as oil) is also a good source of omega-3s?",
        "answer": "Other sources of omega-\n3s include broccoli, cantaloupe, kidney beans, spinach, cauliflower, and walnuts.\nEat two or three servings of fish or shellfish per week before getting pregnant, while\npregnant, and while breastfeeding"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Other sources of omega-\n3s include broccoli, cantaloupe, kidney beans, spinach, cauliflower, and walnuts.\nEat two or three servings of fish or shellfish per week before getting pregnant, while\npregnant, and while breastfeeding?",
        "answer": "A serving of fish is 4 ounces (oz).\nSome types of fish have higher levels of mercury than others"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A serving of fish is 4 ounces (oz).\nSome types of fish have higher levels of mercury than others?",
        "answer": "Mercury is a metal that\nhas been linked to birth defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Mercury is a metal that\nhas been linked to birth defects?",
        "answer": "Do not eat bigeye tuna, king mackerel, marlin, orange\nroughy, shark, swordfish, or tilefish"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Do not eat bigeye tuna, king mackerel, marlin, orange\nroughy, shark, swordfish, or tilefish?",
        "answer": "Limit white (albacore) tuna to only 6 oz a week.\u00a0Also\ncheck advisories about fish caught in local waters.\nB vitamins, including B1, B2, B6, B9, and B12, are key nutrients during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Limit white (albacore) tuna to only 6 oz a week.\u00a0Also\ncheck advisories about fish caught in local waters.\nB vitamins, including B1, B2, B6, B9, and B12, are key nutrients during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "These\nvitamins\nWhat are omega-3 fatty acids and what foods contain omega-3s?\nHow much fish should I eat to get the omega-3 fatty acids that I need?\nWhich types of fish should I avoid?\nWhat are B vitamins and what foods contain them?\ngive you energy\n\u2022\nsupply energy for your fetus\u2019s development\n\u2022\npromote good vision\n\u2022\nhelp build the placenta\n\u2022\nYour prenatal vitamin should have the right amount of B vitamins that you need each\nday"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These\nvitamins\nWhat are omega-3 fatty acids and what foods contain omega-3s?\nHow much fish should I eat to get the omega-3 fatty acids that I need?\nWhich types of fish should I avoid?\nWhat are B vitamins and what foods contain them?\ngive you energy\n\u2022\nsupply energy for your fetus\u2019s development\n\u2022\npromote good vision\n\u2022\nhelp build the placenta\n\u2022\nYour prenatal vitamin should have the right amount of B vitamins that you need each\nday?",
        "answer": "Eating foods high in B vitamins is a good idea too, including liver, pork, chicken,\nbananas, beans, and whole-grain cereals and breads.\nVitamin C is important for a healthy immune system"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Eating foods high in B vitamins is a good idea too, including liver, pork, chicken,\nbananas, beans, and whole-grain cereals and breads.\nVitamin C is important for a healthy immune system?",
        "answer": "It also helps build strong bones\nand muscles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It also helps build strong bones\nand muscles?",
        "answer": "During pregnancy, you should get at least 85 mg of vitamin C each day if\nyou are older than 19, and 80 mg if you are younger than 19.\nYou can get the right amount of vitamin C in your daily prenatal vitamin, and also from\ncitrus fruits and juices, strawberries, broccoli, and tomatoes.\nDrink throughout the day, not just when you are thirsty"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During pregnancy, you should get at least 85 mg of vitamin C each day if\nyou are older than 19, and 80 mg if you are younger than 19.\nYou can get the right amount of vitamin C in your daily prenatal vitamin, and also from\ncitrus fruits and juices, strawberries, broccoli, and tomatoes.\nDrink throughout the day, not just when you are thirsty?",
        "answer": "Aim for 8 to 12 cups of water a\nday during pregnancy.\nPlanning Healthy Meals\nThere are many tools that can help you plan healthy meals"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Aim for 8 to 12 cups of water a\nday during pregnancy.\nPlanning Healthy Meals\nThere are many tools that can help you plan healthy meals?",
        "answer": "One useful tool is the\nMyPlate food-planning guide from the U.S"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is One useful tool is the\nMyPlate food-planning guide from the U.S?",
        "answer": "Department of Agriculture"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Department of Agriculture?",
        "answer": "The MyPlate\nwebsite, www.myplate.gov, can help you learn how to make healthy food choices at\nevery meal.\nThe MyPlate website offers a MyPlate Plan, which shows how much to eat based on\nhow many calories you need each day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The MyPlate\nwebsite, www.myplate.gov, can help you learn how to make healthy food choices at\nevery meal.\nThe MyPlate website offers a MyPlate Plan, which shows how much to eat based on\nhow many calories you need each day?",
        "answer": "The MyPlate Plan is personalized based on your\nWhat is vitamin C and what foods contain it?\nHow can I get enough water during pregnancy?\nHow can I plan healthy meals during pregnancy?\nheight\n\u2022\nprepregnancy weight\n\u2022\nphysical activity level\n\u2022\nThe MyPlate Plan can help you learn about choosing foods from each food group to get\nthe vitamins and minerals you need during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The MyPlate Plan is personalized based on your\nWhat is vitamin C and what foods contain it?\nHow can I get enough water during pregnancy?\nHow can I plan healthy meals during pregnancy?\nheight\n\u2022\nprepregnancy weight\n\u2022\nphysical activity level\n\u2022\nThe MyPlate Plan can help you learn about choosing foods from each food group to get\nthe vitamins and minerals you need during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "The MyPlate Plan can also help\nyou limit calories from added sugars and saturated fats.\nBread, pasta, oatmeal, cereal, and tortillas are all grains"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The MyPlate Plan can also help\nyou limit calories from added sugars and saturated fats.\nBread, pasta, oatmeal, cereal, and tortillas are all grains?",
        "answer": "Whole grains are those that\nhaven\u2019t been processed and include the whole grain kernel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Whole grains are those that\nhaven\u2019t been processed and include the whole grain kernel?",
        "answer": "Oats, barley, quinoa, brown\nrice, and bulgur are all whole grains, as are products made with those grains"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Oats, barley, quinoa, brown\nrice, and bulgur are all whole grains, as are products made with those grains?",
        "answer": "Look for\nthe words \u201cwhole grain\u201d on the product label"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Look for\nthe words \u201cwhole grain\u201d on the product label?",
        "answer": "When you plan meals, make half of your\ngrain servings whole grains.\nYou can eat fresh, canned, frozen, or dried fruit"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When you plan meals, make half of your\ngrain servings whole grains.\nYou can eat fresh, canned, frozen, or dried fruit?",
        "answer": "Juice that is 100 percent fruit juice\ncounts in the fruit category, but it is best to eat mostly whole fruit instead of juice"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Juice that is 100 percent fruit juice\ncounts in the fruit category, but it is best to eat mostly whole fruit instead of juice?",
        "answer": "Make\nhalf your plate fruit and vegetables during mealtimes.\nYou can eat raw, canned, frozen, or dried vegetables or drink 100 percent vegetable\njuice"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Make\nhalf your plate fruit and vegetables during mealtimes.\nYou can eat raw, canned, frozen, or dried vegetables or drink 100 percent vegetable\njuice?",
        "answer": "Use dark leafy greens to make salads"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Use dark leafy greens to make salads?",
        "answer": "Make half your plate fruit and vegetables\nduring mealtimes.\nMeat, poultry, seafood, beans, peas, eggs, processed soy products, nuts, and seeds all\ncontain protein"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Make half your plate fruit and vegetables\nduring mealtimes.\nMeat, poultry, seafood, beans, peas, eggs, processed soy products, nuts, and seeds all\ncontain protein?",
        "answer": "Eat a variety of protein each day.\nWhat are the five food groups?\nGrains\n\u2022\nFruits\n\u2022\nVegetables\n\u2022\nProtein foods\n\u2022\nDairy foods\n\u2022\nWhat are grains?\nWhat types of fruit should I eat?\nWhat types of vegetables should I eat?\nWhat are protein foods?\nMilk and milk products, such as cheese and yogurt, make up the dairy group"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Eat a variety of protein each day.\nWhat are the five food groups?\nGrains\n\u2022\nFruits\n\u2022\nVegetables\n\u2022\nProtein foods\n\u2022\nDairy foods\n\u2022\nWhat are grains?\nWhat types of fruit should I eat?\nWhat types of vegetables should I eat?\nWhat are protein foods?\nMilk and milk products, such as cheese and yogurt, make up the dairy group?",
        "answer": "Make sure\nany dairy foods you eat are pasteurized"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Make sure\nany dairy foods you eat are pasteurized?",
        "answer": "Choose fat-free or low-fat (1 percent) varieties.\nOils and fats are another part of healthy eating"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Choose fat-free or low-fat (1 percent) varieties.\nOils and fats are another part of healthy eating?",
        "answer": "Although they are not a food group, they\ndo give you important nutrients"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Although they are not a food group, they\ndo give you important nutrients?",
        "answer": "During pregnancy, the fats that you eat provide energy\nand help build the placenta and many fetal organs.\nOils in food come mainly from plant sources, such as olive oil, nut oils, and grapeseed\noil"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During pregnancy, the fats that you eat provide energy\nand help build the placenta and many fetal organs.\nOils in food come mainly from plant sources, such as olive oil, nut oils, and grapeseed\noil?",
        "answer": "They can also be found in certain foods, such as some fish, avocados, nuts, and\nolives.\nMost of the fats and oils in your diet should come from plant sources"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They can also be found in certain foods, such as some fish, avocados, nuts, and\nolives.\nMost of the fats and oils in your diet should come from plant sources?",
        "answer": "Limit solid fats,\nsuch as those from animal sources"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Limit solid fats,\nsuch as those from animal sources?",
        "answer": "Solid fats can also be found in processed foods.\nWeight Gain\nWeight gain depends on your health and your body mass index (BMI)  before you were\npregnant"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Solid fats can also be found in processed foods.\nWeight Gain\nWeight gain depends on your health and your body mass index (BMI)  before you were\npregnant?",
        "answer": "If you were underweight before pregnancy, you should gain more weight than\nthose who had a normal weight before pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you were underweight before pregnancy, you should gain more weight than\nthose who had a normal weight before pregnancy?",
        "answer": "If you were overweight or obese\nbefore pregnancy, you should gain less weight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you were overweight or obese\nbefore pregnancy, you should gain less weight?",
        "answer": "The amount of weight gain differs by\ntrimester :\nSee the below table for recommended weight gain during pregnancy.\nWeight Gain During Pregnancy\nWhat are dairy foods?\nWhy are oils and fats important?\nWhat are healthy sources of oils and fats?\nHow much weight should I gain during pregnancy?\nDuring your first 12 weeks of pregnancy\u2014the first trimester\u2014you might gain only 1 to\n5 pounds or none at all.\n\u2022\nIf you were a healthy weight before pregnancy, you should gain a half-pound to 1\npound per week in your second and third trimesters.\n\u2022\nBody Mass Index\n(BMI) Before\nPregnancy\nRate of Weight Gain\nin the Second and\nThird Trimesters*\n(Pounds Per Week)\nRecommended Total\nWeight Gain With a\nSingle Fetus (in\nPounds)\nRecommended Total\nWeight Gain With\nTwins (in Pounds)\nLess than 18.5\n(underweight)\n1.0 to 1.3\n28 to 40\nNot known\n18.5 to 24.9\n(normal weight)\n0.8 to 1.0\n25 to 35\n37 to 54\n25.0 to 29.9\n(overweight)\n0.5 to 0.7\n15 to 25\n31 to 50\n30.0 and above\n(obese)\n0.4 to 0.6\n11 to 20\n25 to 42\n*Assumes a first-trimester weight gain between 1.1 and 4.4 pounds\nSource: Institute of Medicine and National Research Council"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The amount of weight gain differs by\ntrimester :\nSee the below table for recommended weight gain during pregnancy.\nWeight Gain During Pregnancy\nWhat are dairy foods?\nWhy are oils and fats important?\nWhat are healthy sources of oils and fats?\nHow much weight should I gain during pregnancy?\nDuring your first 12 weeks of pregnancy\u2014the first trimester\u2014you might gain only 1 to\n5 pounds or none at all.\n\u2022\nIf you were a healthy weight before pregnancy, you should gain a half-pound to 1\npound per week in your second and third trimesters.\n\u2022\nBody Mass Index\n(BMI) Before\nPregnancy\nRate of Weight Gain\nin the Second and\nThird Trimesters*\n(Pounds Per Week)\nRecommended Total\nWeight Gain With a\nSingle Fetus (in\nPounds)\nRecommended Total\nWeight Gain With\nTwins (in Pounds)\nLess than 18.5\n(underweight)\n1.0 to 1.3\n28 to 40\nNot known\n18.5 to 24.9\n(normal weight)\n0.8 to 1.0\n25 to 35\n37 to 54\n25.0 to 29.9\n(overweight)\n0.5 to 0.7\n15 to 25\n31 to 50\n30.0 and above\n(obese)\n0.4 to 0.6\n11 to 20\n25 to 42\n*Assumes a first-trimester weight gain between 1.1 and 4.4 pounds\nSource: Institute of Medicine and National Research Council?",
        "answer": "2009"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is 2009?",
        "answer": "Weight Gain During\nPregnancy: Reexamining the Guidelines"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Weight Gain During\nPregnancy: Reexamining the Guidelines?",
        "answer": "Washington, DC: The National Academies\nPress.\nDuring the first trimester with one fetus, usually no extra calories are needed"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Washington, DC: The National Academies\nPress.\nDuring the first trimester with one fetus, usually no extra calories are needed?",
        "answer": "In the\nsecond trimester, you will need an extra 340 calories per day, and in the third trimester,\nabout 450 extra calories a day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In the\nsecond trimester, you will need an extra 340 calories per day, and in the third trimester,\nabout 450 extra calories a day?",
        "answer": "To get the extra calories during the day, have healthy\nsnacks on hand, such as nuts, yogurt, and fresh fruit.\nExcess weight during pregnancy is associated with several pregnancy and childbirth\ncomplications , including\nObesity during pregnancy also increases the risk of:\nHow many extra calories should I eat?\nHow can being overweight cause problems during pregnancy?\nhigh blood pressure\n\u2022\npreeclampsia\n\u2022\npreterm  birth\n\u2022\ngestational diabetes\n\u2022\na larger than normal fetus ( macrosomia )\n\u2022\nYou and your ob-gyn should work together to develop a nutrition and exercise plan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is To get the extra calories during the day, have healthy\nsnacks on hand, such as nuts, yogurt, and fresh fruit.\nExcess weight during pregnancy is associated with several pregnancy and childbirth\ncomplications , including\nObesity during pregnancy also increases the risk of:\nHow many extra calories should I eat?\nHow can being overweight cause problems during pregnancy?\nhigh blood pressure\n\u2022\npreeclampsia\n\u2022\npreterm  birth\n\u2022\ngestational diabetes\n\u2022\na larger than normal fetus ( macrosomia )\n\u2022\nYou and your ob-gyn should work together to develop a nutrition and exercise plan?",
        "answer": "If\nyou are gaining less than what the guidelines suggest, and if your fetus is growing well,\ngaining less than the recommended guidelines can have benefits"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If\nyou are gaining less than what the guidelines suggest, and if your fetus is growing well,\ngaining less than the recommended guidelines can have benefits?",
        "answer": "If your fetus is not\ngrowing well, changes may need to be made to your diet and exercise plan.\nResources and Glossary\nMyPlate\nHealthy eating resources from the U.S"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If your fetus is not\ngrowing well, changes may need to be made to your diet and exercise plan.\nResources and Glossary\nMyPlate\nHealthy eating resources from the U.S?",
        "answer": "Department of Agriculture (USDA).\nwww.myplate.gov\nFood Sources of Select Nutrients\nExamples of foods that are good sources of important nutrients.\nwww.dietaryguidelines.gov/resources/2020-2025-dietary-guidelines-online-\nmaterials/food-sources-select-nutrients\nAnemia: Abnormally low levels of red blood cells in the bloodstream"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Department of Agriculture (USDA).\nwww.myplate.gov\nFood Sources of Select Nutrients\nExamples of foods that are good sources of important nutrients.\nwww.dietaryguidelines.gov/resources/2020-2025-dietary-guidelines-online-\nmaterials/food-sources-select-nutrients\nAnemia: Abnormally low levels of red blood cells in the bloodstream?",
        "answer": "Most cases are\ncaused by iron deficiency (lack of iron).\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth.\nbirth injury\n\u2022\ncesarean birth\n\u2022\nbirth defects, especially NTDs\n\u2022\nWhat if I am overweight?\nResources\nHealthy Eating on a Budget: https://www.myplate.gov/eat-healthy/healthy-eating-\nbudget\n\u2022\nPregnancy and Breastfeeding: https://www.myplate.gov/life-stages/pregnancy-and-\nbreastfeeding\n\u2022\nMyPlate Plan: https://www.myplate.gov/myplate-plan\n\u2022\nGlossary\nBody Mass Index: A number calculated from height and weight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Most cases are\ncaused by iron deficiency (lack of iron).\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth.\nbirth injury\n\u2022\ncesarean birth\n\u2022\nbirth defects, especially NTDs\n\u2022\nWhat if I am overweight?\nResources\nHealthy Eating on a Budget: https://www.myplate.gov/eat-healthy/healthy-eating-\nbudget\n\u2022\nPregnancy and Breastfeeding: https://www.myplate.gov/life-stages/pregnancy-and-\nbreastfeeding\n\u2022\nMyPlate Plan: https://www.myplate.gov/myplate-plan\n\u2022\nGlossary\nBody Mass Index: A number calculated from height and weight?",
        "answer": "BMI is used to\ndetermine whether a person is underweight, normal weight, overweight, or obese.\nCalories: Units of heat used to express the fuel or energy value of food.\nCesarean Birth: Birth of a fetus from the uterus through an incision (cut) made in the\nwoman\u2019s abdomen.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is BMI is used to\ndetermine whether a person is underweight, normal weight, overweight, or obese.\nCalories: Units of heat used to express the fuel or energy value of food.\nCesarean Birth: Birth of a fetus from the uterus through an incision (cut) made in the\nwoman\u2019s abdomen.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition?",
        "answer": "An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu?",
        "answer": "A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy?",
        "answer": "An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nFolic Acid: A vitamin that reduces the risk of certain birth defects when taken before\nand during pregnancy.\nGestational Diabetes: Diabetes that starts during pregnancy.\nHigh Blood Pressure: Blood pressure above the normal level"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nFolic Acid: A vitamin that reduces the risk of certain birth defects when taken before\nand during pregnancy.\nGestational Diabetes: Diabetes that starts during pregnancy.\nHigh Blood Pressure: Blood pressure above the normal level?",
        "answer": "Also called hypertension.\nMacrosomia: A condition in which a fetus grows more than expected, often weighing\nmore than 8 pounds and 13 ounces (4,000 grams).\nNeural Tube Defects: Birth defects that result from a problem in development of the\nbrain, spinal cord, or their coverings.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOxygen: An element that we breathe in to sustain life.\nPlacenta: An organ that provides nutrients to and takes waste away from the fetus.\nPreeclampsia: A disorder that can occur during pregnancy or after childbirth in which\nthere is high blood pressure and other signs of organ injury"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also called hypertension.\nMacrosomia: A condition in which a fetus grows more than expected, often weighing\nmore than 8 pounds and 13 ounces (4,000 grams).\nNeural Tube Defects: Birth defects that result from a problem in development of the\nbrain, spinal cord, or their coverings.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOxygen: An element that we breathe in to sustain life.\nPlacenta: An organ that provides nutrients to and takes waste away from the fetus.\nPreeclampsia: A disorder that can occur during pregnancy or after childbirth in which\nthere is high blood pressure and other signs of organ injury?",
        "answer": "These signs include an\nabnormal amount of protein in the urine, a low number of platelets, abnormal kidney or\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nliver function, pain over the upper abdomen, fluid in the lungs, or a severe headache or\nchanges in vision.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nTrimester: A 3-month time in pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These signs include an\nabnormal amount of protein in the urine, a low number of platelets, abnormal kidney or\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nliver function, pain over the upper abdomen, fluid in the lungs, or a severe headache or\nchanges in vision.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nTrimester: A 3-month time in pregnancy?",
        "answer": "It can be first, second, or third.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ001\nLast updated: June 2023\nLast reviewed: December 2021\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It can be first, second, or third.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ001\nLast updated: June 2023\nLast reviewed: December 2021\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nObesity and Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nOverview\nBeing overweight is defined as having a body mass index (BMI)  of 25 to 29.9"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nObesity and Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nOverview\nBeing overweight is defined as having a body mass index (BMI)  of 25 to 29.9?",
        "answer": "Obesity\nis defined as having a BMI of 30 or greater"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Obesity\nis defined as having a BMI of 30 or greater?",
        "answer": "Within the general category of obesity, there\nare three levels that reflect the increasing health risks that go along with increasing BMI:\nYou can find out your BMI by using an online BMI calculator.\nObesity during pregnancy puts you at risk of several serious health problems:\nFAQs\nWhat is obesity?\nObesity category I\u2014BMI of 30 to 34.9\n\u2022\nObesity category II\u2014BMI of 35 to 39.9\n\u2022\nObesity category III\u2014BMI of 40 or greater\n\u2022\nDoes obesity put me at risk of any health problems during pregnancy?\nGestational hypertension \u2014 High blood pressure  that starts during the second half\nof pregnancy is called gestational hypertension"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Within the general category of obesity, there\nare three levels that reflect the increasing health risks that go along with increasing BMI:\nYou can find out your BMI by using an online BMI calculator.\nObesity during pregnancy puts you at risk of several serious health problems:\nFAQs\nWhat is obesity?\nObesity category I\u2014BMI of 30 to 34.9\n\u2022\nObesity category II\u2014BMI of 35 to 39.9\n\u2022\nObesity category III\u2014BMI of 40 or greater\n\u2022\nDoes obesity put me at risk of any health problems during pregnancy?\nGestational hypertension \u2014 High blood pressure  that starts during the second half\nof pregnancy is called gestational hypertension?",
        "answer": "It can lead to serious\ncomplications .\n\u2022\nPreeclampsia \u2014Preeclampsia is a serious form of gestational hypertension that\nusually happens in the second half of pregnancy or soon after childbirth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It can lead to serious\ncomplications .\n\u2022\nPreeclampsia \u2014Preeclampsia is a serious form of gestational hypertension that\nusually happens in the second half of pregnancy or soon after childbirth?",
        "answer": "This\ncondition can cause your kidneys  and liver to fail"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This\ncondition can cause your kidneys  and liver to fail?",
        "answer": "In rare cases, seizures, heart\n\u2022\n[What\u2019s the Concern About High Blood Pressure During Pregnancy? An Ob-Gyn\nExplains.]\nObesity increases the risk of the following problems during pregnancy:\nPreparing for Pregnancy\nattack, and stroke  can happen"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In rare cases, seizures, heart\n\u2022\n[What\u2019s the Concern About High Blood Pressure During Pregnancy? An Ob-Gyn\nExplains.]\nObesity increases the risk of the following problems during pregnancy:\nPreparing for Pregnancy\nattack, and stroke  can happen?",
        "answer": "Other risks include problems with the placenta  and\ngrowth problems for the fetus .\nGestational diabetes \u2014High levels of glucose  (blood sugar) during pregnancy\nincrease the risk of having a very large baby"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Other risks include problems with the placenta  and\ngrowth problems for the fetus .\nGestational diabetes \u2014High levels of glucose  (blood sugar) during pregnancy\nincrease the risk of having a very large baby?",
        "answer": "This also increases the chance of\ncesarean birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This also increases the chance of\ncesarean birth?",
        "answer": "If you have had gestational diabetes, you and your children may have\na higher risk of diabetes mellitus  in the future.\n\u2022\nObstructive sleep apnea \u2014Sleep apnea is a condition in which a person stops\nbreathing for short periods during sleep"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have had gestational diabetes, you and your children may have\na higher risk of diabetes mellitus  in the future.\n\u2022\nObstructive sleep apnea \u2014Sleep apnea is a condition in which a person stops\nbreathing for short periods during sleep?",
        "answer": "During pregnancy, sleep apnea can cause\nfatigue and increase the risk of high blood pressure, preeclampsia, and heart and\nlung problems.\n\u2022\nHow can obesity affect a pregnancy?\nBirth defects \u2014Babies born to women who have obesity have an increased risk of\nhaving birth defects, such as heart defects and neural tube defects (NTDs) .\n\u2022\nProblems with diagnostic tests\u2014Having too much body fat can make it difficult to\nsee certain problems with the fetus\u2019s anatomy on an ultrasound exam"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During pregnancy, sleep apnea can cause\nfatigue and increase the risk of high blood pressure, preeclampsia, and heart and\nlung problems.\n\u2022\nHow can obesity affect a pregnancy?\nBirth defects \u2014Babies born to women who have obesity have an increased risk of\nhaving birth defects, such as heart defects and neural tube defects (NTDs) .\n\u2022\nProblems with diagnostic tests\u2014Having too much body fat can make it difficult to\nsee certain problems with the fetus\u2019s anatomy on an ultrasound exam?",
        "answer": "Checking the\nfetus\u2019s heart rate during labor may also be more difficult.\n\u2022\nMacrosomia \u2014In this condition, the fetus is larger than normal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Checking the\nfetus\u2019s heart rate during labor may also be more difficult.\n\u2022\nMacrosomia \u2014In this condition, the fetus is larger than normal?",
        "answer": "This can increase the\nrisk of injury during birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This can increase the\nrisk of injury during birth?",
        "answer": "For example, the fetus\u2019s shoulder can get stuck after the\nhead is delivered"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For example, the fetus\u2019s shoulder can get stuck after the\nhead is delivered?",
        "answer": "Macrosomia also increases the risk of cesarean birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Macrosomia also increases the risk of cesarean birth?",
        "answer": "Infants born\nwith too much body fat have a greater chance of having obesity later in life.\n\u2022\nPreterm  birth\u2014Problems associated with obesity, such as preeclampsia, may lead to\na medically indicated preterm birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Infants born\nwith too much body fat have a greater chance of having obesity later in life.\n\u2022\nPreterm  birth\u2014Problems associated with obesity, such as preeclampsia, may lead to\na medically indicated preterm birth?",
        "answer": "This means that the baby is delivered early for a\nmedical reason"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This means that the baby is delivered early for a\nmedical reason?",
        "answer": "Preterm babies are not as fully developed as babies who are born\nafter 39 weeks of pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Preterm babies are not as fully developed as babies who are born\nafter 39 weeks of pregnancy?",
        "answer": "As a result, preterm babies have an increased risk of\nshort-term and long-term health problems.\n\u2022\nStillbirth \u2014The higher your BMI, the greater the risk of stillbirth.\n\u2022\nLosing weight before you get pregnant is the best way to decrease the risk of problems\ncaused by obesity"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is As a result, preterm babies have an increased risk of\nshort-term and long-term health problems.\n\u2022\nStillbirth \u2014The higher your BMI, the greater the risk of stillbirth.\n\u2022\nLosing weight before you get pregnant is the best way to decrease the risk of problems\ncaused by obesity?",
        "answer": "If you\u2019re overweight, losing even a small amount of weight can\nimprove your overall health and pave the way for a healthier pregnancy.\nWeight loss happens when you use up more calories  than you take in"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you\u2019re overweight, losing even a small amount of weight can\nimprove your overall health and pave the way for a healthier pregnancy.\nWeight loss happens when you use up more calories  than you take in?",
        "answer": "You can do this\nby getting regular exercise\u00a0and eating healthy foods"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can do this\nby getting regular exercise\u00a0and eating healthy foods?",
        "answer": "Still, losing weight can be difficult\nfor many people"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Still, losing weight can be difficult\nfor many people?",
        "answer": "Research on the best way to lose weight continues to evolve.\nYour obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  may refer you to a nutritionist to help you plan\na healthy diet"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Research on the best way to lose weight continues to evolve.\nYour obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  may refer you to a nutritionist to help you plan\na healthy diet?",
        "answer": "Also, the MyPlate website from the U.S"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also, the MyPlate website from the U.S?",
        "answer": "Department of Agriculture has\ninformation about healthy eating while pregnant or breastfeeding.\nIncreasing your physical activity is important if you want to lose weight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Department of Agriculture has\ninformation about healthy eating while pregnant or breastfeeding.\nIncreasing your physical activity is important if you want to lose weight?",
        "answer": "Aim to be\nmoderately active for 60 minutes or vigorously active for 30 minutes on most days of\nthe week"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Aim to be\nmoderately active for 60 minutes or vigorously active for 30 minutes on most days of\nthe week?",
        "answer": "You do not have to do this amount all at once"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You do not have to do this amount all at once?",
        "answer": "For example, you can exercise\nfor 20 minutes three times a day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For example, you can exercise\nfor 20 minutes three times a day?",
        "answer": "Pick something you like to do"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Pick something you like to do?",
        "answer": "Moderate-intensity\nactivities include biking, brisk walking, and gardening"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Moderate-intensity\nactivities include biking, brisk walking, and gardening?",
        "answer": "Vigorous-intensity activities\ninclude jogging, swimming laps, and heavy yard work.\nIf you have tried to lose weight through diet changes and exercise and you still have a\nBMI of 30 or greater or a BMI of at least 27 with certain medical conditions, such as\ndiabetes or heart disease, weight-loss medications may be suggested"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Vigorous-intensity activities\ninclude jogging, swimming laps, and heavy yard work.\nIf you have tried to lose weight through diet changes and exercise and you still have a\nBMI of 30 or greater or a BMI of at least 27 with certain medical conditions, such as\ndiabetes or heart disease, weight-loss medications may be suggested?",
        "answer": "These\nmedications should not be taken if you are trying to get pregnant or are already\npregnant.\nBariatric surgery  may be an option for people who have a BMI of 40 or greater or a BMI\nbetween 35 and 39 with major health problems caused by obesity"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These\nmedications should not be taken if you are trying to get pregnant or are already\npregnant.\nBariatric surgery  may be an option for people who have a BMI of 40 or greater or a BMI\nbetween 35 and 39 with major health problems caused by obesity?",
        "answer": "If you have weight\nloss surgery, delay getting pregnant for 12 to 24 months after surgery, when you will\nhave the most rapid weight loss.\nShould I plan to lose weight before getting pregnant?\nHow can I lose weight safely?\nAre there medications to help me lose weight before getting pregnant?\nIs there surgery to help me lose weight before getting pregnant?\nIf you have had fertility problems, they may resolve on their own as you rapidly lose the\nexcess weight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have weight\nloss surgery, delay getting pregnant for 12 to 24 months after surgery, when you will\nhave the most rapid weight loss.\nShould I plan to lose weight before getting pregnant?\nHow can I lose weight safely?\nAre there medications to help me lose weight before getting pregnant?\nIs there surgery to help me lose weight before getting pregnant?\nIf you have had fertility problems, they may resolve on their own as you rapidly lose the\nexcess weight?",
        "answer": "It\u2019s important to be aware of this because the increase in fertility can\nlead to an unplanned pregnancy.\nSome types of bariatric surgery may affect how the body absorbs medications taken by\nmouth, including birth control pills"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\u2019s important to be aware of this because the increase in fertility can\nlead to an unplanned pregnancy.\nSome types of bariatric surgery may affect how the body absorbs medications taken by\nmouth, including birth control pills?",
        "answer": "You may need to switch to another form of birth\ncontrol.\nMost people who have had bariatric surgery do well during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may need to switch to another form of birth\ncontrol.\nMost people who have had bariatric surgery do well during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "When you get\npregnant after the surgery, your ob-gyn may monitor you for vitamin deficiencies"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When you get\npregnant after the surgery, your ob-gyn may monitor you for vitamin deficiencies?",
        "answer": "It may\nalso be suggested that you work with a nutritionist to learn how to meet your nutritional\nneeds during pregnancy.\nHealth During Pregnancy\nDespite the risks of obesity, you can still have a healthy pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It may\nalso be suggested that you work with a nutritionist to learn how to meet your nutritional\nneeds during pregnancy.\nHealth During Pregnancy\nDespite the risks of obesity, you can still have a healthy pregnancy?",
        "answer": "It takes careful\nmanagement of your weight, attention to diet and exercise, regular prenatal care  to\nmonitor for complications, and special considerations for your labor and delivery.\nWhile you\u2019re pregnant, the food you eat fuels your body and helps your fetus grow.\nFinding a balance between eating healthy foods\u00a0and staying at a healthy weight is\nimportant for your health and your fetus's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It takes careful\nmanagement of your weight, attention to diet and exercise, regular prenatal care  to\nmonitor for complications, and special considerations for your labor and delivery.\nWhile you\u2019re pregnant, the food you eat fuels your body and helps your fetus grow.\nFinding a balance between eating healthy foods\u00a0and staying at a healthy weight is\nimportant for your health and your fetus's health?",
        "answer": "In the second and third trimesters, you\nneed an average of 300 extra calories a day\u2014about the amount of calories in a glass of\nskim milk and half of a sandwich"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In the second and third trimesters, you\nneed an average of 300 extra calories a day\u2014about the amount of calories in a glass of\nskim milk and half of a sandwich?",
        "answer": "You can get help with planning a healthy diet by\ntalking to a nutrition counselor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can get help with planning a healthy diet by\ntalking to a nutrition counselor?",
        "answer": "You can also find help at the MyPlate website from the\nU.S"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can also find help at the MyPlate website from the\nU.S?",
        "answer": "Department of Agriculture.\nIf you have never exercised before, pregnancy is a great time to start"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Department of Agriculture.\nIf you have never exercised before, pregnancy is a great time to start?",
        "answer": "Discuss your\nexercise plan with your ob-gyn to make sure it\u2019s safe"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Discuss your\nexercise plan with your ob-gyn to make sure it\u2019s safe?",
        "answer": "Begin with as little as 5 minutes of\nexercise a day and add 5 minutes each week"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Begin with as little as 5 minutes of\nexercise a day and add 5 minutes each week?",
        "answer": "Your goal is to stay active for 30 minutes\non most or all days of the week.\nCan I still have a healthy pregnancy?\nHow can I plan healthy meals during pregnancy?\nHow much should I exercise during pregnancy?\nWalking is a good choice if you are new to exercise"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your goal is to stay active for 30 minutes\non most or all days of the week.\nCan I still have a healthy pregnancy?\nHow can I plan healthy meals during pregnancy?\nHow much should I exercise during pregnancy?\nWalking is a good choice if you are new to exercise?",
        "answer": "Swimming is another good exercise\nduring pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Swimming is another good exercise\nduring pregnancy?",
        "answer": "The water supports your weight so you can avoid injury and muscle\nstrain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The water supports your weight so you can avoid injury and muscle\nstrain?",
        "answer": "It also helps you stay cool"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It also helps you stay cool?",
        "answer": "Read Exercise During Pregnancy for more advice.\nAt your first prenatal visit, your BMI should be calculated"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read Exercise During Pregnancy for more advice.\nAt your first prenatal visit, your BMI should be calculated?",
        "answer": "A recommendation should be\nmade about the amount of weight you should gain throughout pregnancy.\nYour weight should be checked at each prenatal visit"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A recommendation should be\nmade about the amount of weight you should gain throughout pregnancy.\nYour weight should be checked at each prenatal visit?",
        "answer": "The growth of your fetus is also\nchecked"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The growth of your fetus is also\nchecked?",
        "answer": "If you are gaining less than the recommended guidelines, and if your fetus is\ngrowing well, you do not have to increase your weight gain to catch up to the guidelines.\nIf your fetus is not growing well, changes may need to be made to your diet and exercise\nplan.\nLabor, Delivery, and Postpartum Care\nPain relief during labor and delivery may take special planning if you have obesity.\nBefore you have your baby, you may meet with a health care professional to discuss\nyour pain relief options.\nAlso, women who are overweight\u00a0 have longer labors than women of normal weight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are gaining less than the recommended guidelines, and if your fetus is\ngrowing well, you do not have to increase your weight gain to catch up to the guidelines.\nIf your fetus is not growing well, changes may need to be made to your diet and exercise\nplan.\nLabor, Delivery, and Postpartum Care\nPain relief during labor and delivery may take special planning if you have obesity.\nBefore you have your baby, you may meet with a health care professional to discuss\nyour pain relief options.\nAlso, women who are overweight\u00a0 have longer labors than women of normal weight?",
        "answer": "It\ncan be harder to monitor the fetus during labor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\ncan be harder to monitor the fetus during labor?",
        "answer": "For these reasons, obesity during\npregnancy increases the likelihood of having a cesarean birth.\nIf a cesarean birth is needed, obesity can increase the risks of infection, bleeding, and\nother complications"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For these reasons, obesity during\npregnancy increases the likelihood of having a cesarean birth.\nIf a cesarean birth is needed, obesity can increase the risks of infection, bleeding, and\nother complications?",
        "answer": "Steps can be taken to reduce your risk of these complications"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Steps can be taken to reduce your risk of these complications?",
        "answer": "For\nexample, you may wear inflatable cuffs on your legs before, during, and after surgery to\nhelp prevent blood clots.\nOnce you are home with your new baby, try to stick to your healthy eating\u00a0and\nexercise\u00a0habits to reach a normal weight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For\nexample, you may wear inflatable cuffs on your legs before, during, and after surgery to\nhelp prevent blood clots.\nOnce you are home with your new baby, try to stick to your healthy eating\u00a0and\nexercise\u00a0habits to reach a normal weight?",
        "answer": "Breastfeeding is recommended for the first\nyear of a baby\u2019s life"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Breastfeeding is recommended for the first\nyear of a baby\u2019s life?",
        "answer": "Breastfeeding is good for you and your baby"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Breastfeeding is good for you and your baby?",
        "answer": "It may also help with\nHow will my weight be monitored during pregnancy?\nHow does obesity affect labor and delivery?\nHow can I manage my weight after my baby is born?\npostpartum weight loss"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It may also help with\nHow will my weight be monitored during pregnancy?\nHow does obesity affect labor and delivery?\nHow can I manage my weight after my baby is born?\npostpartum weight loss?",
        "answer": "Overall, women who breastfeed their babies for at least a few\nmonths tend to lose pregnancy weight faster than women who do not breastfeed.\nIt can be hard to lose the weight you gained during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Overall, women who breastfeed their babies for at least a few\nmonths tend to lose pregnancy weight faster than women who do not breastfeed.\nIt can be hard to lose the weight you gained during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Weight can add up with\neach pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Weight can add up with\neach pregnancy?",
        "answer": "It helps to give yourself enough time to recover from pregnancy and\nlose excess weight before you get pregnant again"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It helps to give yourself enough time to recover from pregnancy and\nlose excess weight before you get pregnant again?",
        "answer": "Read Postpartum Birth Control\u00a0to\nlearn more.\nBariatric Surgery: Surgical procedures that cause weight loss"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read Postpartum Birth Control\u00a0to\nlearn more.\nBariatric Surgery: Surgical procedures that cause weight loss?",
        "answer": "These procedures are\nused to treat obesity.\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth.\nBody Mass Index (BMI): A number calculated from height and weight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These procedures are\nused to treat obesity.\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth.\nBody Mass Index (BMI): A number calculated from height and weight?",
        "answer": "BMI is used to\ndetermine whether a person is underweight, normal weight, overweight, or obese.\nCalories: Units of heat used to express the fuel or energy value of food.\nCesarean Birth: Birth of a fetus from the uterus through an incision (cut) made in the\nwoman\u2019s abdomen.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is BMI is used to\ndetermine whether a person is underweight, normal weight, overweight, or obese.\nCalories: Units of heat used to express the fuel or energy value of food.\nCesarean Birth: Birth of a fetus from the uterus through an incision (cut) made in the\nwoman\u2019s abdomen.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition?",
        "answer": "An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu?",
        "answer": "A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy?",
        "answer": "An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nDiabetes Mellitus: A condition in which the levels of sugar in the blood are too high.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nGestational Diabetes: Diabetes that starts during pregnancy.\nGestational Hypertension: High blood pressure that is diagnosed after 20 weeks of\npregnancy.\nGlucose: A sugar in the blood that is the body\u2019s main source of fuel.\nGlossary\nHigh Blood Pressure: Blood pressure above the normal level"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nDiabetes Mellitus: A condition in which the levels of sugar in the blood are too high.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nGestational Diabetes: Diabetes that starts during pregnancy.\nGestational Hypertension: High blood pressure that is diagnosed after 20 weeks of\npregnancy.\nGlucose: A sugar in the blood that is the body\u2019s main source of fuel.\nGlossary\nHigh Blood Pressure: Blood pressure above the normal level?",
        "answer": "Also called hypertension.\nKidneys: Organs that filter the blood to remove waste that becomes urine.\nMacrosomia: A condition in which a fetus grows more than expected, often weighing\nmore than 8 pounds and 13 ounces (4,000 grams).\nNeural Tube Defects: Birth defects that result from a problem in development of the\nbrain, spinal cord, or their coverings.\nObesity: A condition characterized by excessive body fat.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nObstructive Sleep Apnea: A serious sleep disorder that causes a person to have brief\npauses in breathing during sleep.\nPlacenta: An organ that provides nutrients to and takes waste away from the fetus.\nPreeclampsia: A disorder that can occur during pregnancy or after childbirth in which\nthere is high blood pressure and other signs of organ injury"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also called hypertension.\nKidneys: Organs that filter the blood to remove waste that becomes urine.\nMacrosomia: A condition in which a fetus grows more than expected, often weighing\nmore than 8 pounds and 13 ounces (4,000 grams).\nNeural Tube Defects: Birth defects that result from a problem in development of the\nbrain, spinal cord, or their coverings.\nObesity: A condition characterized by excessive body fat.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nObstructive Sleep Apnea: A serious sleep disorder that causes a person to have brief\npauses in breathing during sleep.\nPlacenta: An organ that provides nutrients to and takes waste away from the fetus.\nPreeclampsia: A disorder that can occur during pregnancy or after childbirth in which\nthere is high blood pressure and other signs of organ injury?",
        "answer": "These signs include an\nabnormal amount of protein in the urine, a low number of platelets, abnormal kidney or\nliver function, pain over the upper abdomen, fluid in the lungs, or a severe headache or\nchanges in vision.\nPrenatal Care: A program of care for a pregnant woman before the birth of her baby.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nStillbirth: Birth of a dead fetus.\nStroke: A sudden interruption of blood flow to all or part of the brain, caused by\nblockage or bursting of a blood vessel in the brain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These signs include an\nabnormal amount of protein in the urine, a low number of platelets, abnormal kidney or\nliver function, pain over the upper abdomen, fluid in the lungs, or a severe headache or\nchanges in vision.\nPrenatal Care: A program of care for a pregnant woman before the birth of her baby.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nStillbirth: Birth of a dead fetus.\nStroke: A sudden interruption of blood flow to all or part of the brain, caused by\nblockage or bursting of a blood vessel in the brain?",
        "answer": "A stroke often results in loss of\nconsciousness and temporary or permanent paralysis.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nUltrasound Exam: A test in which sound waves are used to examine inner parts of the\nbody"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A stroke often results in loss of\nconsciousness and temporary or permanent paralysis.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nUltrasound Exam: A test in which sound waves are used to examine inner parts of the\nbody?",
        "answer": "During pregnancy, ultrasound can be used to check the fetus.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ182\nLast updated: January 2023\nLast reviewed: May 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During pregnancy, ultrasound can be used to check the fetus.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ182\nLast updated: January 2023\nLast reviewed: May 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nPreeclampsia and High Blood Pressure\nDuring Pregnancy\nBlood Pressure\nBlood pressure is the force of blood pushing against the walls of blood vessels called\narteries"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nPreeclampsia and High Blood Pressure\nDuring Pregnancy\nBlood Pressure\nBlood pressure is the force of blood pushing against the walls of blood vessels called\narteries?",
        "answer": "The arteries bring blood from the heart to your lungs, where it picks up\noxygen \u00a0and then moves to your organs and tissues"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The arteries bring blood from the heart to your lungs, where it picks up\noxygen \u00a0and then moves to your organs and tissues?",
        "answer": "The organs and tissues use the\noxygen to power their activities"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The organs and tissues use the\noxygen to power their activities?",
        "answer": "Blood vessels called veins \u00a0return the blood to the\nheart.\nHigh blood pressure  (also called hypertension ) can lead to health problems at any\ntime in life"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Blood vessels called veins \u00a0return the blood to the\nheart.\nHigh blood pressure  (also called hypertension ) can lead to health problems at any\ntime in life?",
        "answer": "High blood pressure usually does not cause symptoms"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is High blood pressure usually does not cause symptoms?",
        "answer": "During pregnancy,\nsevere or uncontrolled high blood pressure can cause problems for you and your fetus .\nSome women have high blood pressure before they get pregnant"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During pregnancy,\nsevere or uncontrolled high blood pressure can cause problems for you and your fetus .\nSome women have high blood pressure before they get pregnant?",
        "answer": "Others develop it for\nthe first time during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Others develop it for\nthe first time during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "A serious high blood pressure disorder called\npreeclampsia \u00a0can also happen during pregnancy or soon after childbirth.\nA blood pressure reading has two numbers separated by a slash"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A serious high blood pressure disorder called\npreeclampsia \u00a0can also happen during pregnancy or soon after childbirth.\nA blood pressure reading has two numbers separated by a slash?",
        "answer": "A blood pressure\nreading of 110/80 mm Hg, for example, is referred to as \u201c110 over 80.\u201d The first number\nFAQs\nWhat is blood pressure?\nWhy is high blood pressure a problem during pregnancy?\nWhat do the blood pressure numbers mean?\nis the pressure against the artery walls when the heart contracts"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A blood pressure\nreading of 110/80 mm Hg, for example, is referred to as \u201c110 over 80.\u201d The first number\nFAQs\nWhat is blood pressure?\nWhy is high blood pressure a problem during pregnancy?\nWhat do the blood pressure numbers mean?\nis the pressure against the artery walls when the heart contracts?",
        "answer": "This is called the\nsystolic blood pressure"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is called the\nsystolic blood pressure?",
        "answer": "The second number is the pressure against the artery walls\nwhen the heart relaxes between contractions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The second number is the pressure against the artery walls\nwhen the heart relaxes between contractions?",
        "answer": "This is called the diastolic blood\npressure .\nYour obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn) \u00a0should check your blood pressure at each\nprenatal care \u00a0visit"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is called the diastolic blood\npressure .\nYour obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn) \u00a0should check your blood pressure at each\nprenatal care \u00a0visit?",
        "answer": "Blood pressure changes often during the day"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Blood pressure changes often during the day?",
        "answer": "If you have one high\nreading, another reading may be taken later during your office visit.\nChronic Hypertension\nChronic hypertension  is high blood pressure that a woman has before getting pregnant\nor that develops in the first half of pregnancy (before 20 weeks of pregnancy)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have one high\nreading, another reading may be taken later during your office visit.\nChronic Hypertension\nChronic hypertension  is high blood pressure that a woman has before getting pregnant\nor that develops in the first half of pregnancy (before 20 weeks of pregnancy)?",
        "answer": "If you\nwere taking blood pressure medication before you got pregnant\u2014even if your blood\npressure is currently normal\u2014you have been diagnosed with chronic hypertension.\nWhen you are pregnant, your body makes more blood to support the fetus\u2019s growth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you\nwere taking blood pressure medication before you got pregnant\u2014even if your blood\npressure is currently normal\u2014you have been diagnosed with chronic hypertension.\nWhen you are pregnant, your body makes more blood to support the fetus\u2019s growth?",
        "answer": "If\nblood pressure goes up during pregnancy, it can place extra stress on your heart and\nkidneys"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If\nblood pressure goes up during pregnancy, it can place extra stress on your heart and\nkidneys?",
        "answer": "This can lead to heart disease, kidney disease, and stroke"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This can lead to heart disease, kidney disease, and stroke?",
        "answer": "High blood\npressure during pregnancy also increases the risk of preeclampsia, preterm \u00a0birth,\nplacental abruption , and cesarean birth .\nWhat are the guidelines for blood pressure?\nNormal: Less than 120/80 mm Hg\n\u2022\nElevated: Systolic between 120 and 129 mm Hg and diastolic less than 80 mm Hg\n\u2022\nStage 1 hypertension: Systolic between 130 and 139 mm Hg or diastolic between 80\nand 89 mm Hg\n\u2022\nStage 2 hypertension: Systolic at least 140 mm Hg or diastolic at least 90 mm Hg\n\u2022\nHow often should blood pressure be checked during pregnancy?\nWhat is chronic hypertension?\nHow does chronic hypertension affect a pregnant woman?\nHigh blood pressure may reduce blood flow to the placenta"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is High blood\npressure during pregnancy also increases the risk of preeclampsia, preterm \u00a0birth,\nplacental abruption , and cesarean birth .\nWhat are the guidelines for blood pressure?\nNormal: Less than 120/80 mm Hg\n\u2022\nElevated: Systolic between 120 and 129 mm Hg and diastolic less than 80 mm Hg\n\u2022\nStage 1 hypertension: Systolic between 130 and 139 mm Hg or diastolic between 80\nand 89 mm Hg\n\u2022\nStage 2 hypertension: Systolic at least 140 mm Hg or diastolic at least 90 mm Hg\n\u2022\nHow often should blood pressure be checked during pregnancy?\nWhat is chronic hypertension?\nHow does chronic hypertension affect a pregnant woman?\nHigh blood pressure may reduce blood flow to the placenta?",
        "answer": "As a result, the fetus may\nnot get enough of the nutrients \u00a0and oxygen needed to grow.\nIn the first half of pregnancy, blood pressure normally goes down"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is As a result, the fetus may\nnot get enough of the nutrients \u00a0and oxygen needed to grow.\nIn the first half of pregnancy, blood pressure normally goes down?",
        "answer": "If your hypertension is\nmild, your blood pressure may stay that way or even return to normal during pregnancy.\nBut if your blood pressure is 140/90 mm Hg or higher, your ob-gyn may recommend that\nyou start or continue taking blood pressure medication during pregnancy.\nYour blood pressure should be checked at every prenatal care visit"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If your hypertension is\nmild, your blood pressure may stay that way or even return to normal during pregnancy.\nBut if your blood pressure is 140/90 mm Hg or higher, your ob-gyn may recommend that\nyou start or continue taking blood pressure medication during pregnancy.\nYour blood pressure should be checked at every prenatal care visit?",
        "answer": "You may also need\nto monitor your blood pressure at home"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may also need\nto monitor your blood pressure at home?",
        "answer": "Ultrasound exams \u00a0may be done throughout\npregnancy to track the growth of the fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Ultrasound exams \u00a0may be done throughout\npregnancy to track the growth of the fetus?",
        "answer": "If growth problems are suspected, you may\nhave other tests that monitor the health of the fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If growth problems are suspected, you may\nhave other tests that monitor the health of the fetus?",
        "answer": "This testing usually begins in the\nthird trimester \u00a0of pregnancy.\nIf your condition remains stable, delivery 1 to 3 weeks before your due date (about 37\nweeks to 39 weeks of pregnancy) generally is recommended"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This testing usually begins in the\nthird trimester \u00a0of pregnancy.\nIf your condition remains stable, delivery 1 to 3 weeks before your due date (about 37\nweeks to 39 weeks of pregnancy) generally is recommended?",
        "answer": "If you or the fetus develop\ncomplications , delivery may be needed even earlier.\nAfter delivery, you will need to keep monitoring your blood pressure at home for 1 to 2\nweeks"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you or the fetus develop\ncomplications , delivery may be needed even earlier.\nAfter delivery, you will need to keep monitoring your blood pressure at home for 1 to 2\nweeks?",
        "answer": "Blood pressure often goes up in the weeks after childbirth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Blood pressure often goes up in the weeks after childbirth?",
        "answer": "You may need to\nresume taking medication, or your medication dosage may need to be adjusted.\nTalk with your ob-gyn about blood pressure medications that are safe to take if you plan\nto breastfeed"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may need to\nresume taking medication, or your medication dosage may need to be adjusted.\nTalk with your ob-gyn about blood pressure medications that are safe to take if you plan\nto breastfeed?",
        "answer": "Do not stop any medications without talking with your ob-gyn.\nGestational Hypertension\nHow does chronic hypertension affect a fetus?\nWhat is the treatment for chronic hypertension during pregnancy?\nHow will my health be monitored during pregnancy?\nWill I need to deliver early if I have chronic hypertension?\nWhat will happen after delivery if I have chronic hypertension?\nWhat is gestational hypertension?\nYou have gestational hypertension  when:\nMost women with gestational hypertension have only a small increase in blood\npressure"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Do not stop any medications without talking with your ob-gyn.\nGestational Hypertension\nHow does chronic hypertension affect a fetus?\nWhat is the treatment for chronic hypertension during pregnancy?\nHow will my health be monitored during pregnancy?\nWill I need to deliver early if I have chronic hypertension?\nWhat will happen after delivery if I have chronic hypertension?\nWhat is gestational hypertension?\nYou have gestational hypertension  when:\nMost women with gestational hypertension have only a small increase in blood\npressure?",
        "answer": "But some women develop severe hypertension (defined as systolic blood\npressure of 160 mm Hg or higher and/or diastolic blood pressure of 110 mm Hg or\nhigher)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But some women develop severe hypertension (defined as systolic blood\npressure of 160 mm Hg or higher and/or diastolic blood pressure of 110 mm Hg or\nhigher)?",
        "answer": "These women are at risk of very serious complications.\nAll women with gestational hypertension are monitored often (usually weekly) for signs\nof preeclampsia and to make sure that their blood pressure does not go too high.\nAlthough gestational hypertension usually goes away after childbirth, it may increase\nthe risk of developing high blood pressure in the future"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These women are at risk of very serious complications.\nAll women with gestational hypertension are monitored often (usually weekly) for signs\nof preeclampsia and to make sure that their blood pressure does not go too high.\nAlthough gestational hypertension usually goes away after childbirth, it may increase\nthe risk of developing high blood pressure in the future?",
        "answer": "If you had gestational\nhypertension, keep this risk in mind as you take care of your health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you had gestational\nhypertension, keep this risk in mind as you take care of your health?",
        "answer": "Healthy eating,\nweight loss, and regular exercise may help prevent high blood pressure in the future.\nPreeclampsia\nPreeclampsia is a serious disorder that can affect all the organs in your body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Healthy eating,\nweight loss, and regular exercise may help prevent high blood pressure in the future.\nPreeclampsia\nPreeclampsia is a serious disorder that can affect all the organs in your body?",
        "answer": "It usually\ndevelops after 20 weeks of pregnancy, often in the third trimester"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It usually\ndevelops after 20 weeks of pregnancy, often in the third trimester?",
        "answer": "When it develops\nbefore 34 weeks of pregnancy, it is called early-onset preeclampsia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When it develops\nbefore 34 weeks of pregnancy, it is called early-onset preeclampsia?",
        "answer": "It can also develop\nin the weeks after childbirth.\nIt is not clear why some women develop preeclampsia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It can also develop\nin the weeks after childbirth.\nIt is not clear why some women develop preeclampsia?",
        "answer": "Doctors refer to \"high risk\" and\n\"moderate risk\" of preeclampsia.\nYou have a systolic blood pressure of 140 mm Hg or higher and/or a diastolic blood\npressure of 90 mm Hg or higher.\n\u2022\nThe high blood pressure first happens after 20 weeks of pregnancy.\n\u2022\nYou had normal blood pressure before pregnancy.\n\u2022\nHow will my health be monitored if I have gestational hypertension?\nHow does gestational hypertension affect future health?\nWhat is preeclampsia?\nWhat are the risk factors for preeclampsia?\nFactors that may put you in the \u201chigh risk\u201d category include\nFactors that may put you in the \u201cmoderate risk\u201d category include\npreeclampsia in a past pregnancy\n\u2022\ncarrying more than one fetus (twins, triplets, or more)\n\u2022\nchronic hypertension\n\u2022\nkidney disease\n\u2022\ndiabetes mellitus\n\u2022\nautoimmune conditions, such as lupus  (systemic lupus erythematosus or SLE)\n\u2022\nhaving multiple moderate risk factors (see below)\n\u2022\nbeing pregnant for the first time\n\u2022\nbeing pregnant more than 10 years after your previous pregnancy\n\u2022\nbody mass index (BMI)  over 30\n\u2022\nfamily history of preeclampsia (mother or sister)\n\u2022\nbeing age 35 or older\n\u2022\ncomplications in previous pregnancies, such as having a baby with a low birth weight\n\u2022\nin vitro fertilization (IVF)\n\u2022\nBlack race (because of racism and inequities that increase risk of illness)\n\u2022\nlower income (because of inequities that increase risk of illness)\n\u2022\nHow does preeclampsia affect the body?\nPreeclampsia can lead to a condition that causes seizures and stroke.\n\u2022\nPreeclampsia can cause HELLP syndrome"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Doctors refer to \"high risk\" and\n\"moderate risk\" of preeclampsia.\nYou have a systolic blood pressure of 140 mm Hg or higher and/or a diastolic blood\npressure of 90 mm Hg or higher.\n\u2022\nThe high blood pressure first happens after 20 weeks of pregnancy.\n\u2022\nYou had normal blood pressure before pregnancy.\n\u2022\nHow will my health be monitored if I have gestational hypertension?\nHow does gestational hypertension affect future health?\nWhat is preeclampsia?\nWhat are the risk factors for preeclampsia?\nFactors that may put you in the \u201chigh risk\u201d category include\nFactors that may put you in the \u201cmoderate risk\u201d category include\npreeclampsia in a past pregnancy\n\u2022\ncarrying more than one fetus (twins, triplets, or more)\n\u2022\nchronic hypertension\n\u2022\nkidney disease\n\u2022\ndiabetes mellitus\n\u2022\nautoimmune conditions, such as lupus  (systemic lupus erythematosus or SLE)\n\u2022\nhaving multiple moderate risk factors (see below)\n\u2022\nbeing pregnant for the first time\n\u2022\nbeing pregnant more than 10 years after your previous pregnancy\n\u2022\nbody mass index (BMI)  over 30\n\u2022\nfamily history of preeclampsia (mother or sister)\n\u2022\nbeing age 35 or older\n\u2022\ncomplications in previous pregnancies, such as having a baby with a low birth weight\n\u2022\nin vitro fertilization (IVF)\n\u2022\nBlack race (because of racism and inequities that increase risk of illness)\n\u2022\nlower income (because of inequities that increase risk of illness)\n\u2022\nHow does preeclampsia affect the body?\nPreeclampsia can lead to a condition that causes seizures and stroke.\n\u2022\nPreeclampsia can cause HELLP syndrome?",
        "answer": "HELLP stands for hemolysis, elevated\nliver enzymes, and low platelet count"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is HELLP stands for hemolysis, elevated\nliver enzymes, and low platelet count?",
        "answer": "HELLP syndrome damages or destroys red\nblood cells and interferes with blood clotting"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is HELLP syndrome damages or destroys red\nblood cells and interferes with blood clotting?",
        "answer": "It can also cause chest pain, abdominal\npain, and bleeding in the liver"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It can also cause chest pain, abdominal\npain, and bleeding in the liver?",
        "answer": "HELLP syndrome is a medical emergency"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is HELLP syndrome is a medical emergency?",
        "answer": "Women can\ndie from HELLP syndrome"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Women can\ndie from HELLP syndrome?",
        "answer": "They can also have lifelong health problems from the\ncondition.\n\u2022\nFor women with preeclampsia, early delivery may be needed in some cases"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They can also have lifelong health problems from the\ncondition.\n\u2022\nFor women with preeclampsia, early delivery may be needed in some cases?",
        "answer": "Preterm\nbabies have an increased risk of problems with breathing, eating, staying warm, hearing,\nand vision"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Preterm\nbabies have an increased risk of problems with breathing, eating, staying warm, hearing,\nand vision?",
        "answer": "Some preterm complications last a lifetime and require ongoing medical\ncare.\nWomen who have had preeclampsia\u2014especially those whose babies were born preterm\n\u2014have an increased risk later in life of kidney disease, heart attack, stroke, and high\nblood pressure"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some preterm complications last a lifetime and require ongoing medical\ncare.\nWomen who have had preeclampsia\u2014especially those whose babies were born preterm\n\u2014have an increased risk later in life of kidney disease, heart attack, stroke, and high\nblood pressure?",
        "answer": "Also, having preeclampsia once increases the risk of having it again in a\nfuture pregnancy.\nPreeclampsia can develop quietly without you being aware of it"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also, having preeclampsia once increases the risk of having it again in a\nfuture pregnancy.\nPreeclampsia can develop quietly without you being aware of it?",
        "answer": "Symptoms can include\nIf you have any of these symptoms, especially if they develop in the second half of\npregnancy, call your ob-gyn right away.\nA woman with preeclampsia whose condition is worsening will develop \u201csevere\nfeatures.\u201d Severe features include\nWill I need to deliver early if I have preeclampsia?\nHow does preeclampsia affect future health?\nWhat are the signs and symptoms of preeclampsia?\nswelling of face or hands\n\u2022\nheadache that will not go away\n\u2022\nseeing spots or changes in eyesight\n\u2022\npain in the upper abdomen or shoulder\n\u2022\nnausea and vomiting (in the second half of pregnancy)\n\u2022\nsudden weight gain\n\u2022\ndifficulty breathing\n\u2022\nlow number of platelets in the blood\n\u2022\nabnormal kidney or liver function\n\u2022\npain in the upper abdomen\n\u2022\nchanges in vision\n\u2022\nfluid in the lungs\nA high blood pressure reading may be the first sign of preeclampsia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Symptoms can include\nIf you have any of these symptoms, especially if they develop in the second half of\npregnancy, call your ob-gyn right away.\nA woman with preeclampsia whose condition is worsening will develop \u201csevere\nfeatures.\u201d Severe features include\nWill I need to deliver early if I have preeclampsia?\nHow does preeclampsia affect future health?\nWhat are the signs and symptoms of preeclampsia?\nswelling of face or hands\n\u2022\nheadache that will not go away\n\u2022\nseeing spots or changes in eyesight\n\u2022\npain in the upper abdomen or shoulder\n\u2022\nnausea and vomiting (in the second half of pregnancy)\n\u2022\nsudden weight gain\n\u2022\ndifficulty breathing\n\u2022\nlow number of platelets in the blood\n\u2022\nabnormal kidney or liver function\n\u2022\npain in the upper abdomen\n\u2022\nchanges in vision\n\u2022\nfluid in the lungs\nA high blood pressure reading may be the first sign of preeclampsia?",
        "answer": "If your blood\npressure reading is high, it may be checked again to confirm the results"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If your blood\npressure reading is high, it may be checked again to confirm the results?",
        "answer": "You may have a\nurine test to check for protein"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may have a\nurine test to check for protein?",
        "answer": "You may also have tests to check how your liver and\nkidneys are working and to measure the number of platelets in your blood.\nYou and your ob-gyn should talk about how your condition will be managed"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may also have tests to check how your liver and\nkidneys are working and to measure the number of platelets in your blood.\nYou and your ob-gyn should talk about how your condition will be managed?",
        "answer": "The goal is\nto limit complications for you and to deliver the healthiest baby possible.\nWomen who have gestational hypertension or preeclampsia without severe features\nmay be treated in a hospital or as an outpatient"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The goal is\nto limit complications for you and to deliver the healthiest baby possible.\nWomen who have gestational hypertension or preeclampsia without severe features\nmay be treated in a hospital or as an outpatient?",
        "answer": "Being an outpatient means you can\nstay at home with close monitoring by your ob-gyn"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Being an outpatient means you can\nstay at home with close monitoring by your ob-gyn?",
        "answer": "You may need to keep track of your\nfetus\u2019s movement by doing a daily kick count"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may need to keep track of your\nfetus\u2019s movement by doing a daily kick count?",
        "answer": "You may also need to measure your\nblood pressure at home"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may also need to measure your\nblood pressure at home?",
        "answer": "Visits to your ob-gyn may be once or twice a week.\nAt 37 weeks of pregnancy, you and your ob-gyn may talk about delivery"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Visits to your ob-gyn may be once or twice a week.\nAt 37 weeks of pregnancy, you and your ob-gyn may talk about delivery?",
        "answer": "Labor may be\ninduced\u00a0(started with medications)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Labor may be\ninduced\u00a0(started with medications)?",
        "answer": "If test results show that the fetus is not doing well,\nyou may need to have the baby earlier"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If test results show that the fetus is not doing well,\nyou may need to have the baby earlier?",
        "answer": "Women with preeclampsia can have vaginal\ndeliveries, but if there are problems during labor, cesarean birth may be needed.\nIf you have preeclampsia with severe features, you may be treated in the hospital"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Women with preeclampsia can have vaginal\ndeliveries, but if there are problems during labor, cesarean birth may be needed.\nIf you have preeclampsia with severe features, you may be treated in the hospital?",
        "answer": "If you\nare at least 34 weeks pregnant, you and your ob-gyn may talk about having your baby as\nsoon as your condition is stable.\nIf you are less than 34 weeks pregnant and your condition is stable, it may be possible\nto wait to deliver your baby"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you\nare at least 34 weeks pregnant, you and your ob-gyn may talk about having your baby as\nsoon as your condition is stable.\nIf you are less than 34 weeks pregnant and your condition is stable, it may be possible\nto wait to deliver your baby?",
        "answer": "Delaying delivery for just a few days may be helpful in some\n\u2022 severe headache\n\u2022\nsystolic pressure of 160 mm Hg or higher or diastolic pressure of 110 mm Hg or\nhigher\n\u2022\nHow is preeclampsia diagnosed?\nHow is preeclampsia managed?\nHow is preeclampsia managed when there are no severe features?\nHow is preeclampsia managed when there are severe features?\ncases"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Delaying delivery for just a few days may be helpful in some\n\u2022 severe headache\n\u2022\nsystolic pressure of 160 mm Hg or higher or diastolic pressure of 110 mm Hg or\nhigher\n\u2022\nHow is preeclampsia diagnosed?\nHow is preeclampsia managed?\nHow is preeclampsia managed when there are no severe features?\nHow is preeclampsia managed when there are severe features?\ncases?",
        "answer": "It allows time to give corticosteroids , which can help the fetus\u2019s lungs mature.\nDelaying can also give you time to take medications to reduce your blood pressure and\nhelp prevent seizures"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It allows time to give corticosteroids , which can help the fetus\u2019s lungs mature.\nDelaying can also give you time to take medications to reduce your blood pressure and\nhelp prevent seizures?",
        "answer": "If your health or the fetus\u2019s health worsens, you and your ob-gyn\nshould discuss immediate delivery.\nRead Preterm Labor and Birth or Extremely Preterm Birth to learn more.\nPrevention involves identifying whether you have risk factors for preeclampsia and\ntaking steps to address them.\nLow-dose aspirin may reduce the risk of preeclampsia in some women"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If your health or the fetus\u2019s health worsens, you and your ob-gyn\nshould discuss immediate delivery.\nRead Preterm Labor and Birth or Extremely Preterm Birth to learn more.\nPrevention involves identifying whether you have risk factors for preeclampsia and\ntaking steps to address them.\nLow-dose aspirin may reduce the risk of preeclampsia in some women?",
        "answer": "Your ob-gyn\nmay recommend that you take low-dose aspirin if\nLow-dose aspirin may also be considered if you are Black or if you have a low income,\neven if you have no other risk factors.\nTalk with your ob-gyn about whether you should take aspirin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your ob-gyn\nmay recommend that you take low-dose aspirin if\nLow-dose aspirin may also be considered if you are Black or if you have a low income,\neven if you have no other risk factors.\nTalk with your ob-gyn about whether you should take aspirin?",
        "answer": "Do not start taking aspirin\non your own without talking with your ob-gyn.\nIf you have high blood pressure and want to get pregnant, see your ob-gyn for a check-\nup"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Do not start taking aspirin\non your own without talking with your ob-gyn.\nIf you have high blood pressure and want to get pregnant, see your ob-gyn for a check-\nup?",
        "answer": "Your ob-gyn will want to know if your high blood pressure is under control and if it\nhas affected your health.\nYou may have tests to check how your heart and kidneys are working"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your ob-gyn will want to know if your high blood pressure is under control and if it\nhas affected your health.\nYou may have tests to check how your heart and kidneys are working?",
        "answer": "Your medications\nshould be reviewed to see if you need to switch to others that are safer during\npregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your medications\nshould be reviewed to see if you need to switch to others that are safer during\npregnancy?",
        "answer": "You should also talk about the signs and symptoms of preeclampsia.\nCan preeclampsia be prevented?\nDoes low-dose aspirin prevent preeclampsia?\nyou are at high risk of developing preeclampsia\n\u2022\nyou have two or more moderate risk factors for preeclampsia\n\u2022\nWhat should I do if I have high blood pressure and want to get pregnant?\nGlossary\nArteries: Blood vessels that carry oxygen-rich blood from the heart to the rest of the\nbody.\nBody Mass Index (BMI): A number calculated from height and weight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You should also talk about the signs and symptoms of preeclampsia.\nCan preeclampsia be prevented?\nDoes low-dose aspirin prevent preeclampsia?\nyou are at high risk of developing preeclampsia\n\u2022\nyou have two or more moderate risk factors for preeclampsia\n\u2022\nWhat should I do if I have high blood pressure and want to get pregnant?\nGlossary\nArteries: Blood vessels that carry oxygen-rich blood from the heart to the rest of the\nbody.\nBody Mass Index (BMI): A number calculated from height and weight?",
        "answer": "BMI is used to\ndetermine whether a person is underweight, normal weight, overweight, or obese.\nCesarean Birth: Birth of a fetus from the uterus through an incision (cut) made in the\nwoman\u2019s abdomen.\nChronic Hypertension: Blood pressure that is higher than normal for a person\u2019s age, sex,\nand physical condition.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is BMI is used to\ndetermine whether a person is underweight, normal weight, overweight, or obese.\nCesarean Birth: Birth of a fetus from the uterus through an incision (cut) made in the\nwoman\u2019s abdomen.\nChronic Hypertension: Blood pressure that is higher than normal for a person\u2019s age, sex,\nand physical condition.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition?",
        "answer": "An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu?",
        "answer": "A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy?",
        "answer": "An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nCorticosteroids: Drugs given for arthritis or other medical conditions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nCorticosteroids: Drugs given for arthritis or other medical conditions?",
        "answer": "These drugs also\nare given to help fetal lungs mature before birth.\nDiabetes Mellitus: A condition in which the levels of sugar in the blood are too high.\nDiastolic Blood Pressure: The force of the blood in the arteries when the heart is\nrelaxed"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These drugs also\nare given to help fetal lungs mature before birth.\nDiabetes Mellitus: A condition in which the levels of sugar in the blood are too high.\nDiastolic Blood Pressure: The force of the blood in the arteries when the heart is\nrelaxed?",
        "answer": "It is the lower reading when blood pressure is taken.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nGestational Hypertension: High blood pressure that is diagnosed after 20 weeks of\npregnancy.\nHELLP Syndrome: A severe type of preeclampsia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is the lower reading when blood pressure is taken.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nGestational Hypertension: High blood pressure that is diagnosed after 20 weeks of\npregnancy.\nHELLP Syndrome: A severe type of preeclampsia?",
        "answer": "HELLP stands for hemolysis, elevated\nliver enzymes, and low platelet count.\nHigh Blood Pressure: Blood pressure above the normal level"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is HELLP stands for hemolysis, elevated\nliver enzymes, and low platelet count.\nHigh Blood Pressure: Blood pressure above the normal level?",
        "answer": "Also called hypertension.\nHypertension: High blood pressure.\nIn Vitro Fertilization (IVF): A procedure in which an egg is removed from a woman\u2019s\novary, fertilized in a laboratory with the man\u2019s sperm, and then transferred to the\nwoman\u2019s uterus to achieve a pregnancy.\nKick Count: A record kept during late pregnancy of the number of times a fetus moves\nover a certain period.\nKidneys: Organs that filter the blood to remove waste that becomes urine.\nLupus: An autoimmune disorder that affects the connective tissues in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also called hypertension.\nHypertension: High blood pressure.\nIn Vitro Fertilization (IVF): A procedure in which an egg is removed from a woman\u2019s\novary, fertilized in a laboratory with the man\u2019s sperm, and then transferred to the\nwoman\u2019s uterus to achieve a pregnancy.\nKick Count: A record kept during late pregnancy of the number of times a fetus moves\nover a certain period.\nKidneys: Organs that filter the blood to remove waste that becomes urine.\nLupus: An autoimmune disorder that affects the connective tissues in the body?",
        "answer": "The\ndisorder can cause arthritis, kidney disease, heart disease, blood disorders, and\ncomplications during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The\ndisorder can cause arthritis, kidney disease, heart disease, blood disorders, and\ncomplications during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Also called systemic lupus erythematosus or SLE.\nNutrients: Nourishing substances found in food, such as vitamins and minerals.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOxygen: An element that we breathe in to sustain life.\nPlacenta: An organ that provides nutrients to and takes waste away from the fetus.\nPlacental Abruption: A condition in which the placenta has begun to separate from the\nuterus before the fetus is born.\nPreeclampsia: A disorder that can occur during pregnancy or after childbirth in which\nthere is high blood pressure and other signs of organ injury"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also called systemic lupus erythematosus or SLE.\nNutrients: Nourishing substances found in food, such as vitamins and minerals.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOxygen: An element that we breathe in to sustain life.\nPlacenta: An organ that provides nutrients to and takes waste away from the fetus.\nPlacental Abruption: A condition in which the placenta has begun to separate from the\nuterus before the fetus is born.\nPreeclampsia: A disorder that can occur during pregnancy or after childbirth in which\nthere is high blood pressure and other signs of organ injury?",
        "answer": "These signs include an\nabnormal amount of protein in the urine, a low number of platelets, abnormal kidney or\nliver function, pain in the upper abdomen, fluid in the lungs, or a severe headache or\nchanges in vision.\nPrenatal Care: A program of care for a pregnant woman before the birth of her baby.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nStroke: A sudden interruption of blood flow to all or part of the brain, caused by\nblockage or bursting of a blood vessel in the brain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These signs include an\nabnormal amount of protein in the urine, a low number of platelets, abnormal kidney or\nliver function, pain in the upper abdomen, fluid in the lungs, or a severe headache or\nchanges in vision.\nPrenatal Care: A program of care for a pregnant woman before the birth of her baby.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nStroke: A sudden interruption of blood flow to all or part of the brain, caused by\nblockage or bursting of a blood vessel in the brain?",
        "answer": "A stroke often results in loss of\nconsciousness and temporary or permanent paralysis.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nSystolic Blood Pressure: The force of the blood in the arteries when the heart is\ncontracting"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A stroke often results in loss of\nconsciousness and temporary or permanent paralysis.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nSystolic Blood Pressure: The force of the blood in the arteries when the heart is\ncontracting?",
        "answer": "It is the higher reading when blood pressure is taken.\nTrimester: A 3-month time in pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is the higher reading when blood pressure is taken.\nTrimester: A 3-month time in pregnancy?",
        "answer": "It can be first, second, or third.\nUltrasound Exams: Tests in which sound waves are used to examine inner parts of the\nbody"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It can be first, second, or third.\nUltrasound Exams: Tests in which sound waves are used to examine inner parts of the\nbody?",
        "answer": "During pregnancy, ultrasound can be used to check the fetus.\nVeins: Blood vessels that carry blood from various parts of the body back to the heart.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ034\nLast updated: April 2022\nLast reviewed: April 2023\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During pregnancy, ultrasound can be used to check the fetus.\nVeins: Blood vessels that carry blood from various parts of the body back to the heart.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ034\nLast updated: April 2022\nLast reviewed: April 2023\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nPREECLAMPSIA \nAND PREGNANCY\nPreeclampsia is a serious blood pressure disorder that \ncan happen during pregnancy or soon after childbirth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nPREECLAMPSIA \nAND PREGNANCY\nPreeclampsia is a serious blood pressure disorder that \ncan happen during pregnancy or soon after childbirth?",
        "answer": "Preeclampsia is a leading cause of death worldwide for \nwomen, fetuses, and newborns"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Preeclampsia is a leading cause of death worldwide for \nwomen, fetuses, and newborns?",
        "answer": "It can develop without \nyou realizing it, so it\u2019s important to learn the symptoms.\nWHAT ARE THE WARNING SIGNS?\nWhen there are symptoms, they may include...\na headache that \nwill not go away \nseeing spots, blurry \nvision, or other changes \nin eyesight \nswelling of \nface or hands \nsudden \nweight gain\nnausea and \nvomiting in the 2nd \nhalf of pregnancy\npain in the \nupper abdomen \nor shoulder \nshortness \nof breath \nWHAT ARE THE RISK FACTORS?\nAnyone can develop preeclampsia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It can develop without \nyou realizing it, so it\u2019s important to learn the symptoms.\nWHAT ARE THE WARNING SIGNS?\nWhen there are symptoms, they may include...\na headache that \nwill not go away \nseeing spots, blurry \nvision, or other changes \nin eyesight \nswelling of \nface or hands \nsudden \nweight gain\nnausea and \nvomiting in the 2nd \nhalf of pregnancy\npain in the \nupper abdomen \nor shoulder \nshortness \nof breath \nWHAT ARE THE RISK FACTORS?\nAnyone can develop preeclampsia?",
        "answer": "Many women who get preeclampsia are \notherwise healthy and do not have clear risk factors"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Many women who get preeclampsia are \notherwise healthy and do not have clear risk factors?",
        "answer": "But some women may \nhave a higher risk than others.\nRisk factors for women at high risk \ninclude\n\u2022\t preeclampsia in a past pregnancy\n\u2022\t carrying more than one fetus\n\u2022\t chronic high blood pressure\n\u2022\t kidney disease\n\u2022\t diabetes mellitus\n\u2022\t autoimmune conditions, such \nas lupus\nRisk factors for women at \nmoderate risk include\n\u2022\t being pregnant for the first time\n\u2022\t being pregnant more than \n10 years after your previous \npregnancy\n\u2022\t body mass index (BMI) over 30\n\u2022\t family history of preeclampsia \n(mother or sister)\n\u2022\t being age 35 or older\n\u2022\t complications in previous \npregnancies, such as having a \nbaby with a low birth weight\n\u2022\t in vitro fertilization (IVF)\n\u2022\t Black race (because of racism \nand inequities that increase risk of \nillness)\n\u2022\t lower income (because of \ninequities that increase risk of \nillness)\nLow-dose aspirin may reduce the risk of preeclampsia in some women"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But some women may \nhave a higher risk than others.\nRisk factors for women at high risk \ninclude\n\u2022\t preeclampsia in a past pregnancy\n\u2022\t carrying more than one fetus\n\u2022\t chronic high blood pressure\n\u2022\t kidney disease\n\u2022\t diabetes mellitus\n\u2022\t autoimmune conditions, such \nas lupus\nRisk factors for women at \nmoderate risk include\n\u2022\t being pregnant for the first time\n\u2022\t being pregnant more than \n10 years after your previous \npregnancy\n\u2022\t body mass index (BMI) over 30\n\u2022\t family history of preeclampsia \n(mother or sister)\n\u2022\t being age 35 or older\n\u2022\t complications in previous \npregnancies, such as having a \nbaby with a low birth weight\n\u2022\t in vitro fertilization (IVF)\n\u2022\t Black race (because of racism \nand inequities that increase risk of \nillness)\n\u2022\t lower income (because of \ninequities that increase risk of \nillness)\nLow-dose aspirin may reduce the risk of preeclampsia in some women?",
        "answer": "Talk with your ob-gyn about whether you should take aspirin.\nYOUR FUTURE HEALTH\nIf you are diagnosed with preeclampsia during pregnancy, \nyou may be more likely to have health problems in the future \nwhen you are not pregnant"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Talk with your ob-gyn about whether you should take aspirin.\nYOUR FUTURE HEALTH\nIf you are diagnosed with preeclampsia during pregnancy, \nyou may be more likely to have health problems in the future \nwhen you are not pregnant?",
        "answer": "These problems may include...\nheart attack\nstroke\nkidney disease\nhigh blood pressure\nYou may need to see your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn) \nearlier or more often after childbirth so your ob-gyn can keep \na close eye on your health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These problems may include...\nheart attack\nstroke\nkidney disease\nhigh blood pressure\nYou may need to see your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn) \nearlier or more often after childbirth so your ob-gyn can keep \na close eye on your health?",
        "answer": "You should also tell any future health \ncare professionals that you had preeclampsia.\nREMEMBER\nMany women who get preeclampsia do not \nhave clear risk factors"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You should also tell any future health \ncare professionals that you had preeclampsia.\nREMEMBER\nMany women who get preeclampsia do not \nhave clear risk factors?",
        "answer": "Talk with your ob-\ngyn away if you have any warning signs.\nacog.org\nPFSI018: This information is designed as an educational aid for the \npublic"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Talk with your ob-\ngyn away if you have any warning signs.\nacog.org\nPFSI018: This information is designed as an educational aid for the \npublic?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and opinions related to women\u2019s \nhealth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and opinions related to women\u2019s \nhealth?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does \nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does \nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a \nsubstitute for the advice of a physician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a \nsubstitute for the advice of a physician?",
        "answer": "For ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer, \nvisit www.acog.org/WomensHealth-Disclaimer.\nCopyright December 2021 by the American College of Obstetricians \nand Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer, \nvisit www.acog.org/WomensHealth-Disclaimer.\nCopyright December 2021 by the American College of Obstetricians \nand Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "No part of this publication may \nbe reproduced, stored in a retrieval system, posted on the internet, \nor transmitted, in any form or by any means, electronic, mechanical, \nphotocopying, recording, or otherwise, without prior written permission \nfrom the publisher.\nReducing Risks of Birth Defects\nFrequently Asked Questions\nA birth defect  is a condition that is present at birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is No part of this publication may \nbe reproduced, stored in a retrieval system, posted on the internet, \nor transmitted, in any form or by any means, electronic, mechanical, \nphotocopying, recording, or otherwise, without prior written permission \nfrom the publisher.\nReducing Risks of Birth Defects\nFrequently Asked Questions\nA birth defect  is a condition that is present at birth?",
        "answer": "Some birth defects can be seen\nright after the baby is born, such as a clubfoot  or extra fingers or toes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some birth defects can be seen\nright after the baby is born, such as a clubfoot  or extra fingers or toes?",
        "answer": "Special tests\nmay be needed to find others, such as heart defects or hearing loss"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Special tests\nmay be needed to find others, such as heart defects or hearing loss?",
        "answer": "Some birth defects\nare not noticed until later in life.\nSome birth defects are caused by genes  that can be passed from parents to children.\nOthers result from a problem with chromosomes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some birth defects\nare not noticed until later in life.\nSome birth defects are caused by genes  that can be passed from parents to children.\nOthers result from a problem with chromosomes?",
        "answer": "A small number of birth defects are\ncaused by exposure during pregnancy to certain medications, infections, and chemicals.\nFor many birth defects, the cause is not known.\nMost birth defects cannot be prevented because their cause is not known"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A small number of birth defects are\ncaused by exposure during pregnancy to certain medications, infections, and chemicals.\nFor many birth defects, the cause is not known.\nMost birth defects cannot be prevented because their cause is not known?",
        "answer": "For a few\nbirth defects, you may be able to decrease your risk by taking certain steps:\nFAQs\nWhat is a birth defect?\nWhat causes birth defects?\nWhat can I do before or during pregnancy to decrease my risk of having a baby\nwith certain birth defects?\nSee your doctor before getting pregnant.\n\u2022\nKnow your risk factors.\n\u2022\nTake a daily multivitamin before and during pregnancy.\n\u2022\nMaintain a healthy weight.\n\u2022\nScheduling a health care visit before getting pregnant is a good idea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For a few\nbirth defects, you may be able to decrease your risk by taking certain steps:\nFAQs\nWhat is a birth defect?\nWhat causes birth defects?\nWhat can I do before or during pregnancy to decrease my risk of having a baby\nwith certain birth defects?\nSee your doctor before getting pregnant.\n\u2022\nKnow your risk factors.\n\u2022\nTake a daily multivitamin before and during pregnancy.\n\u2022\nMaintain a healthy weight.\n\u2022\nScheduling a health care visit before getting pregnant is a good idea?",
        "answer": "You can get advice\nabout diet and exercise from your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  or other health\ncare professional"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can get advice\nabout diet and exercise from your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  or other health\ncare professional?",
        "answer": "You can talk about whether you have any factors that increase the\nrisk of having a child with a birth defect"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can talk about whether you have any factors that increase the\nrisk of having a child with a birth defect?",
        "answer": "If you have a medical condition, you can talk\nabout any special care that you may need before or during pregnancy.\nYou may be at an increased risk of having a baby with a birth defect if you:\nIf you have any risk factors, your ob-gyn or other health care professional may\nrecommend special tests or other steps that may help reduce your risk"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have a medical condition, you can talk\nabout any special care that you may need before or during pregnancy.\nYou may be at an increased risk of having a baby with a birth defect if you:\nIf you have any risk factors, your ob-gyn or other health care professional may\nrecommend special tests or other steps that may help reduce your risk?",
        "answer": "For example, if\nyou have a personal or family history of birth defects, genetic counseling and testing\nmay be recommended.\nPrenatal vitamin supplements contain the recommended amounts of the vitamins and\nminerals you will need during your pregnancy, including:\nUse medications wisely.\n\u2022\nTake care of medical conditions before pregnancy.\n\u2022\nDo not use alcohol, marijuana, illegal drugs, or prescription drugs for a nonmedical\nreason.\n\u2022\nPrevent infections.\n\u2022\nAvoid known harmful agents.\n\u2022\nWhy should I see a health care professional before becoming pregnant?\nWhat factors increase the risk of having a baby with a birth defect?\nAre older\n\u2022\nHave a family or personal history of birth defects\n\u2022\nHave had a child with a birth defect\n\u2022\nUse certain medicines around the time you become pregnant\n\u2022\nHave a medical condition such as diabetes mellitus  or obesity\n\u2022\nUse recreational drugs or drink alcohol during pregnancy\n\u2022\nWhy is taking a multivitamin important before and during pregnancy?\nTaking 400 micrograms (mcg) of folic acid daily for at least 1 month before pregnancy\nand during pregnancy helps prevent major birth defects called neural tube defects\n(NTDs)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For example, if\nyou have a personal or family history of birth defects, genetic counseling and testing\nmay be recommended.\nPrenatal vitamin supplements contain the recommended amounts of the vitamins and\nminerals you will need during your pregnancy, including:\nUse medications wisely.\n\u2022\nTake care of medical conditions before pregnancy.\n\u2022\nDo not use alcohol, marijuana, illegal drugs, or prescription drugs for a nonmedical\nreason.\n\u2022\nPrevent infections.\n\u2022\nAvoid known harmful agents.\n\u2022\nWhy should I see a health care professional before becoming pregnant?\nWhat factors increase the risk of having a baby with a birth defect?\nAre older\n\u2022\nHave a family or personal history of birth defects\n\u2022\nHave had a child with a birth defect\n\u2022\nUse certain medicines around the time you become pregnant\n\u2022\nHave a medical condition such as diabetes mellitus  or obesity\n\u2022\nUse recreational drugs or drink alcohol during pregnancy\n\u2022\nWhy is taking a multivitamin important before and during pregnancy?\nTaking 400 micrograms (mcg) of folic acid daily for at least 1 month before pregnancy\nand during pregnancy helps prevent major birth defects called neural tube defects\n(NTDs)?",
        "answer": "These are defects of the brain and spine of the fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These are defects of the brain and spine of the fetus?",
        "answer": "Most prenatal and\n\u201cwomen\u2019s formula\u201d multivitamin supplements contain 400\u2013800 mcg of folic acid.\nA few medications have been linked to birth defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Most prenatal and\n\u201cwomen\u2019s formula\u201d multivitamin supplements contain 400\u2013800 mcg of folic acid.\nA few medications have been linked to birth defects?",
        "answer": "You should tell anyone who\nprescribes drugs for you that you are pregnant or thinking about getting pregnant"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You should tell anyone who\nprescribes drugs for you that you are pregnant or thinking about getting pregnant?",
        "answer": "This\nincludes doctors you may see for dental care, mental health care, or other nonpregnancy\nproblems"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This\nincludes doctors you may see for dental care, mental health care, or other nonpregnancy\nproblems?",
        "answer": "Also, check with your ob-gyn or other health care professional before taking\nany over-the-counter drug, such as pain relievers, laxatives, cold or allergy remedies,\nvitamins, herbal products, and skin treatments"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also, check with your ob-gyn or other health care professional before taking\nany over-the-counter drug, such as pain relievers, laxatives, cold or allergy remedies,\nvitamins, herbal products, and skin treatments?",
        "answer": "A good source for information about the\nsafety or risk of specific drugs during pregnancy is the website of the Organization of\nTeratology Information Specialists: www.mothertobaby.org.\nWomen who are obese (defined as having a body mass index [BMI]  of 30 or greater)\nwhen they get pregnant have an increased risk of having babies with certain birth\ndefects than women who are a normal weight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A good source for information about the\nsafety or risk of specific drugs during pregnancy is the website of the Organization of\nTeratology Information Specialists: www.mothertobaby.org.\nWomen who are obese (defined as having a body mass index [BMI]  of 30 or greater)\nwhen they get pregnant have an increased risk of having babies with certain birth\ndefects than women who are a normal weight?",
        "answer": "Among the most common obesity-\nrelated birth defects are NTDs, heart defects, and cleft palate"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Among the most common obesity-\nrelated birth defects are NTDs, heart defects, and cleft palate?",
        "answer": "If you are planning a\npregnancy, the best way to prevent problems caused by obesity is to be at a normal\nweight before you get pregnant.\nSome medical conditions\u2014such as diabetes, high blood pressure , and seizure\ndisorders \u2014may increase the risk of having a baby with certain birth defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are planning a\npregnancy, the best way to prevent problems caused by obesity is to be at a normal\nweight before you get pregnant.\nSome medical conditions\u2014such as diabetes, high blood pressure , and seizure\ndisorders \u2014may increase the risk of having a baby with certain birth defects?",
        "answer": "If you have\na medical condition, see your ob-gyn or other health care professional to discuss any\nVvitamins A, C, and D\n\u2022\nFolic acid\n\u2022\nMinerals such as iron\n\u2022\nWhat do I need to know about taking medications during pregnancy?\nHow can obesity have an impact on my pregnancy?\nI have certain medical conditions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have\na medical condition, see your ob-gyn or other health care professional to discuss any\nVvitamins A, C, and D\n\u2022\nFolic acid\n\u2022\nMinerals such as iron\n\u2022\nWhat do I need to know about taking medications during pregnancy?\nHow can obesity have an impact on my pregnancy?\nI have certain medical conditions?",
        "answer": "Why is it important to talk with my ob-gyn or\nother health care professional if I am thinking about getting pregnant?\nchanges you need to make in your diet, medication, or other areas to bring the condition\nunder control before you try to get pregnant.\nAlcohol can interfere with the normal growth of the fetus and cause birth defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Why is it important to talk with my ob-gyn or\nother health care professional if I am thinking about getting pregnant?\nchanges you need to make in your diet, medication, or other areas to bring the condition\nunder control before you try to get pregnant.\nAlcohol can interfere with the normal growth of the fetus and cause birth defects?",
        "answer": "When\na woman drinks during pregnancy, her fetus can develop physical, intellectual,\nbehavioral, and learning disabilities that can last a lifetime"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When\na woman drinks during pregnancy, her fetus can develop physical, intellectual,\nbehavioral, and learning disabilities that can last a lifetime?",
        "answer": "It is best not to drink at all\nduring pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is best not to drink at all\nduring pregnancy?",
        "answer": "If it is hard for you to stop drinking, talk with your ob-gyn or other\nhealth care professional or contact Alcoholics Anonymous on its website: www.aa.org.\nUsing substances\u2014including heroin, cocaine, methamphetamines, and prescription\ndrugs taken for a nonmedical reason\u2014is a widespread problem in the United States.\nUsing illegal drugs early in pregnancy can cause birth defects and miscarriage"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If it is hard for you to stop drinking, talk with your ob-gyn or other\nhealth care professional or contact Alcoholics Anonymous on its website: www.aa.org.\nUsing substances\u2014including heroin, cocaine, methamphetamines, and prescription\ndrugs taken for a nonmedical reason\u2014is a widespread problem in the United States.\nUsing illegal drugs early in pregnancy can cause birth defects and miscarriage?",
        "answer": "During\nthe later weeks of pregnancy, illegal drugs can interfere with the growth of the fetus and\ncause preterm  birth and fetal death"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During\nthe later weeks of pregnancy, illegal drugs can interfere with the growth of the fetus and\ncause preterm  birth and fetal death?",
        "answer": "Infants born to women who used illegal drugs\nduring pregnancy may need specialized care after birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Infants born to women who used illegal drugs\nduring pregnancy may need specialized care after birth?",
        "answer": "If you need help quitting illegal\ndrugs, you can find resources at the website of Narcotics Anonymous: www.na.org.\nRecreational marijuana used during pregnancy is associated with attention and\nbehavioral problems in children"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you need help quitting illegal\ndrugs, you can find resources at the website of Narcotics Anonymous: www.na.org.\nRecreational marijuana used during pregnancy is associated with attention and\nbehavioral problems in children?",
        "answer": "Marijuana may increase the risk of stillbirth  and the\nrisk that babies will be smaller than babies who are not exposed to marijuana before\nbirth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Marijuana may increase the risk of stillbirth  and the\nrisk that babies will be smaller than babies who are not exposed to marijuana before\nbirth?",
        "answer": "Medical marijuana also should be avoided"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Medical marijuana also should be avoided?",
        "answer": "The American College of Obstetricians\nand Gynecologists recommends that pregnant women and those planning to become\npregnant not use any form of marijuana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The American College of Obstetricians\nand Gynecologists recommends that pregnant women and those planning to become\npregnant not use any form of marijuana?",
        "answer": "You and your ob-gyn or other health care\nprofessional can discuss alternative treatments that will be safe for your fetus.\nOpioids  are a type of medication that relieves pain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You and your ob-gyn or other health care\nprofessional can discuss alternative treatments that will be safe for your fetus.\nOpioids  are a type of medication that relieves pain?",
        "answer": "Doctors may prescribe opioids for\npeople who have had surgery, dental work, or an injury"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Doctors may prescribe opioids for\npeople who have had surgery, dental work, or an injury?",
        "answer": "Prescribed opioids include\noxycodone, hydromorphone, hydrocodone, and codeine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Prescribed opioids include\noxycodone, hydromorphone, hydrocodone, and codeine?",
        "answer": "When taken under a doctor\u2019s\ncare, opioids are safe for both you and your fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When taken under a doctor\u2019s\ncare, opioids are safe for both you and your fetus?",
        "answer": "It is important to take the medication\nonly as prescribed.\nWhy is it important for me to not drink alcohol during pregnancy?\nHow can recreational drug use affect my pregnancy?\nCan using marijuana affect my pregnancy?\nHow can opioids affect my pregnancy?\nMost people who use a prescription opioid have no trouble stopping their use, but some\npeople develop an addiction"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is important to take the medication\nonly as prescribed.\nWhy is it important for me to not drink alcohol during pregnancy?\nHow can recreational drug use affect my pregnancy?\nCan using marijuana affect my pregnancy?\nHow can opioids affect my pregnancy?\nMost people who use a prescription opioid have no trouble stopping their use, but some\npeople develop an addiction?",
        "answer": "Misusing opioids during pregnancy can increase the risk of\nserious complications , including preterm birth, stillbirth, and problems with the\nplacenta and fetal growth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Misusing opioids during pregnancy can increase the risk of\nserious complications , including preterm birth, stillbirth, and problems with the\nplacenta and fetal growth?",
        "answer": "If you need help with an opioid addiction, you can find\nresources at the website of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services\nAdministration (SAMHSA): www.samhsa.gov"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you need help with an opioid addiction, you can find\nresources at the website of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services\nAdministration (SAMHSA): www.samhsa.gov?",
        "answer": "SAMHSA also has a 24 hour treatment\nreferral line: 800-662-HELP (4357).\nSome infections can increase the risk of birth defects and other problems during\npregnancy for you and your fetus:\nWhat infections should I be concerned about and how can I reduce my risk of\ngetting them during pregnancy?\nRubella  (German measles) is a viral infection that usually causes a mild rash and a\nlow fever"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is SAMHSA also has a 24 hour treatment\nreferral line: 800-662-HELP (4357).\nSome infections can increase the risk of birth defects and other problems during\npregnancy for you and your fetus:\nWhat infections should I be concerned about and how can I reduce my risk of\ngetting them during pregnancy?\nRubella  (German measles) is a viral infection that usually causes a mild rash and a\nlow fever?",
        "answer": "Having rubella during pregnancy can cause miscarriage  or result in\ndeafness, intellectual disability, heart defects, and blindness in a newborn"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Having rubella during pregnancy can cause miscarriage  or result in\ndeafness, intellectual disability, heart defects, and blindness in a newborn?",
        "answer": "There is a\nvaccine  against rubella, but it is not recommended for pregnant women"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There is a\nvaccine  against rubella, but it is not recommended for pregnant women?",
        "answer": "If you have\nnot already had the disease or been vaccinated, you should be vaccinated against\nrubella and wait at least 1 month before becoming pregnant.\n\u2022\nToxoplasmosis  is a disease caused by a parasite that lives in soil"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have\nnot already had the disease or been vaccinated, you should be vaccinated against\nrubella and wait at least 1 month before becoming pregnant.\n\u2022\nToxoplasmosis  is a disease caused by a parasite that lives in soil?",
        "answer": "You can become\ninfected by eating raw or undercooked meat or unwashed vegetables or by coming\ninto contact with animal feces, especially from cats that go outdoors"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can become\ninfected by eating raw or undercooked meat or unwashed vegetables or by coming\ninto contact with animal feces, especially from cats that go outdoors?",
        "answer": "If you are\ninfected for the first time while you are pregnant, you can pass the disease on to your\nbaby"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are\ninfected for the first time while you are pregnant, you can pass the disease on to your\nbaby?",
        "answer": "Toxoplasmosis can cause birth defects, including hearing loss, vision\nproblems, and intellectual disability"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Toxoplasmosis can cause birth defects, including hearing loss, vision\nproblems, and intellectual disability?",
        "answer": "Make sure that you eat well-cooked meat and\nwear gloves while gardening or handling unwashed vegetables"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Make sure that you eat well-cooked meat and\nwear gloves while gardening or handling unwashed vegetables?",
        "answer": "If you have an\noutdoor cat that uses a litter box, have someone else empty it"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have an\noutdoor cat that uses a litter box, have someone else empty it?",
        "answer": "If you must empty the\nlitter box, use gloves and wash your hands well after doing so.\n\u2022\nSexually transmitted infections (STIs)  can cause serious birth defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you must empty the\nlitter box, use gloves and wash your hands well after doing so.\n\u2022\nSexually transmitted infections (STIs)  can cause serious birth defects?",
        "answer": "Treating an\nSTI\u2014preferably before you get pregnant\u2014may prevent or reduce harm to the fetus.\n\u2022\nCytomegalovirus (CMV) , is a common viral infection"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Treating an\nSTI\u2014preferably before you get pregnant\u2014may prevent or reduce harm to the fetus.\n\u2022\nCytomegalovirus (CMV) , is a common viral infection?",
        "answer": "Most CMV infections cause no\nsignificant problems"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Most CMV infections cause no\nsignificant problems?",
        "answer": "If you are infected for the first time when you are pregnant,\nCMV can infect the fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are infected for the first time when you are pregnant,\nCMV can infect the fetus?",
        "answer": "In a small number of cases, the infection can cause\nintellectual disability, hearing loss, and vision problems"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In a small number of cases, the infection can cause\nintellectual disability, hearing loss, and vision problems?",
        "answer": "CMV can be spread by\ncontact with an infected child\u2019s urine or other body fluids"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is CMV can be spread by\ncontact with an infected child\u2019s urine or other body fluids?",
        "answer": "Pregnant women who work\nwith young children, such as day care workers or health care workers, should take\n\u2022\nZika virus can be transmitted through the bite of an infected mosquito or through sex\nwith an infected partner"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Pregnant women who work\nwith young children, such as day care workers or health care workers, should take\n\u2022\nZika virus can be transmitted through the bite of an infected mosquito or through sex\nwith an infected partner?",
        "answer": "To avoid Zika virus, take strict steps to avoid mosquito bites"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is To avoid Zika virus, take strict steps to avoid mosquito bites?",
        "answer": "If\nyour male partner lives in or travels to an area where Zika virus is spreading, use a\ncondom each time you have sex"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If\nyour male partner lives in or travels to an area where Zika virus is spreading, use a\ncondom each time you have sex?",
        "answer": "Do not travel to areas where Zika virus is known to be\nactive.\nIf you or your partner must travel to an area where Zika virus is active, strictly follow\nthese four steps to prevent mosquito bites:\nA few precautions that are recommended for all pregnant women include the following:\nsteps to prevent infection, including wearing gloves when changing diapers"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Do not travel to areas where Zika virus is known to be\nactive.\nIf you or your partner must travel to an area where Zika virus is active, strictly follow\nthese four steps to prevent mosquito bites:\nA few precautions that are recommended for all pregnant women include the following:\nsteps to prevent infection, including wearing gloves when changing diapers?",
        "answer": "Frequent\nhandwashing also is recommended"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Frequent\nhandwashing also is recommended?",
        "answer": "Pregnant women with young children at home\nalso are at risk and should take these steps.\nZika  virus has been found in South America, Central America, and North America.\nInfection with the virus during pregnancy can cause serious birth defects, including\nmicrocephaly  (a birth defect in which a baby\u2019s head and brain are smaller than\nnormal) and other brain abnormalities"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Pregnant women with young children at home\nalso are at risk and should take these steps.\nZika  virus has been found in South America, Central America, and North America.\nInfection with the virus during pregnancy can cause serious birth defects, including\nmicrocephaly  (a birth defect in which a baby\u2019s head and brain are smaller than\nnormal) and other brain abnormalities?",
        "answer": "These birth defects can lead to lifelong\nproblems, including seizures, feeding problems, hearing loss, vision problems, and\nlearning difficulties"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These birth defects can lead to lifelong\nproblems, including seizures, feeding problems, hearing loss, vision problems, and\nlearning difficulties?",
        "answer": "There still are many things that researchers do not know about\nZika virus.\n\u2022\nUse EPA-registered bug spray with DEET, picaridin, IR3535, oil of lemon eucalyptus,\nparamenthane-diol, or 2-undecanone"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There still are many things that researchers do not know about\nZika virus.\n\u2022\nUse EPA-registered bug spray with DEET, picaridin, IR3535, oil of lemon eucalyptus,\nparamenthane-diol, or 2-undecanone?",
        "answer": "Used as directed, these sprays are safe for\npregnant and breastfeeding women.\n1.\nWear long-sleeved shirts and long pants.\n2.\nTreat clothing and gear with permethrin or buy permethrin-treated items.\n3.\nStay in air-conditioned or screened-in areas during the day and at night"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Used as directed, these sprays are safe for\npregnant and breastfeeding women.\n1.\nWear long-sleeved shirts and long pants.\n2.\nTreat clothing and gear with permethrin or buy permethrin-treated items.\n3.\nStay in air-conditioned or screened-in areas during the day and at night?",
        "answer": "Follow\nthese steps at all times"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Follow\nthese steps at all times?",
        "answer": "Mosquitoes are active during the day and night.\n4.\nWhat precautions can I take to limit my exposure to agents that can cause birth\ndefects?\nLimit your exposure to mercury by not eating bigeye tuna, king mackerel, marlin,\norange roughy, shark, swordfish, or tilefish"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Mosquitoes are active during the day and night.\n4.\nWhat precautions can I take to limit my exposure to agents that can cause birth\ndefects?\nLimit your exposure to mercury by not eating bigeye tuna, king mackerel, marlin,\norange roughy, shark, swordfish, or tilefish?",
        "answer": "Limit eating white (albacore) tuna to 6\nounces a week"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Limit eating white (albacore) tuna to 6\nounces a week?",
        "answer": "You do not have to avoid all fish during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You do not have to avoid all fish during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "In fact, fish and\n\u2022\nBirth Defect: A physical problem that is present at birth.\nBody Mass Index (BMI): A number calculated from height and weight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In fact, fish and\n\u2022\nBirth Defect: A physical problem that is present at birth.\nBody Mass Index (BMI): A number calculated from height and weight?",
        "answer": "BMI is used to\ndetermine whether a person is underweight, normal weight, overweight, or obese.\nChromosomes: Structures that are located inside each cell in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is BMI is used to\ndetermine whether a person is underweight, normal weight, overweight, or obese.\nChromosomes: Structures that are located inside each cell in the body?",
        "answer": "They contain the\ngenes that determine a person\u2019s physical makeup.\nCleft Palate: A birth defect that causes an opening or split in the roof of the mouth.\nClubfoot: A birth defect in which the foot is misshaped and twisted out of position.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They contain the\ngenes that determine a person\u2019s physical makeup.\nCleft Palate: A birth defect that causes an opening or split in the roof of the mouth.\nClubfoot: A birth defect in which the foot is misshaped and twisted out of position.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition?",
        "answer": "An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu?",
        "answer": "A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy?",
        "answer": "An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nCytomegalovirus (CMV): A virus that can be transmitted to a fetus if a woman becomes\ninfected during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nCytomegalovirus (CMV): A virus that can be transmitted to a fetus if a woman becomes\ninfected during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "CMV can cause hearing loss, mental disability, and vision\nproblems in newborns.\nDiabetes Mellitus: A condition in which the levels of sugar in the blood are too high.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nshellfish are nutritious foods with vital nutrients  for a pregnant woman and her\nfetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is CMV can cause hearing loss, mental disability, and vision\nproblems in newborns.\nDiabetes Mellitus: A condition in which the levels of sugar in the blood are too high.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nshellfish are nutritious foods with vital nutrients  for a pregnant woman and her\nfetus?",
        "answer": "Be sure to eat at least 8\u201312 ounces of low-mercury fish and shellfish per week.\nAvoid exposure to lead"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Be sure to eat at least 8\u201312 ounces of low-mercury fish and shellfish per week.\nAvoid exposure to lead?",
        "answer": "Lead can be found in old paint, construction materials,\nalternative medicines, and items made in foreign countries, such as jewelry and\npottery.\n\u2022\nAvoid taking high levels of vitamin A"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Lead can be found in old paint, construction materials,\nalternative medicines, and items made in foreign countries, such as jewelry and\npottery.\n\u2022\nAvoid taking high levels of vitamin A?",
        "answer": "Very high levels of vitamin A have been linked\nto severe birth defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Very high levels of vitamin A have been linked\nto severe birth defects?",
        "answer": "You should consume no more than 10,000 international units\nof vitamin A a day.\n\u2022\nGlossary\nFolic Acid: A vitamin that reduces the risk of certain birth defects when taken before\nand during pregnancy.\nGenes: Segments of DNA that contain instructions for the development of a person\u2019s\nphysical traits and control of the processes in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You should consume no more than 10,000 international units\nof vitamin A a day.\n\u2022\nGlossary\nFolic Acid: A vitamin that reduces the risk of certain birth defects when taken before\nand during pregnancy.\nGenes: Segments of DNA that contain instructions for the development of a person\u2019s\nphysical traits and control of the processes in the body?",
        "answer": "The gene is the basic unit of\nheredity and can be passed from parent to child.\nHigh Blood Pressure: Blood pressure above the normal level"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The gene is the basic unit of\nheredity and can be passed from parent to child.\nHigh Blood Pressure: Blood pressure above the normal level?",
        "answer": "Also called hypertension.\nMicrocephaly: A birth defect in which a baby\u2019s head and brain are smaller than normal.\nBabies with microcephaly may have seizures, developmental delays, mental disability,\nvision and hearing problems, and problems with balance and movement.\nMiscarriage: Loss of a pregnancy that is in the uterus.\nNeural Tube Defects (NTDs): Birth defects that result from a problem in development of\nthe brain, spinal cord, or their coverings.\nNutrients: Nourishing substances found in food, such as vitamins and minerals.\nObesity: A condition characterized by excessive body fat.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOpioids: Drugs that decrease the ability to feel pain.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nRubella: A virus that can be passed to the fetus if a woman becomes infected during\npregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also called hypertension.\nMicrocephaly: A birth defect in which a baby\u2019s head and brain are smaller than normal.\nBabies with microcephaly may have seizures, developmental delays, mental disability,\nvision and hearing problems, and problems with balance and movement.\nMiscarriage: Loss of a pregnancy that is in the uterus.\nNeural Tube Defects (NTDs): Birth defects that result from a problem in development of\nthe brain, spinal cord, or their coverings.\nNutrients: Nourishing substances found in food, such as vitamins and minerals.\nObesity: A condition characterized by excessive body fat.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOpioids: Drugs that decrease the ability to feel pain.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nRubella: A virus that can be passed to the fetus if a woman becomes infected during\npregnancy?",
        "answer": "The virus can cause miscarriage or severe birth defects.\nSeizure Disorders: Any condition that causes seizures, which cause changes in\nmovement, consciousness, mood, or emotions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The virus can cause miscarriage or severe birth defects.\nSeizure Disorders: Any condition that causes seizures, which cause changes in\nmovement, consciousness, mood, or emotions?",
        "answer": "Epilepsy is one kind of seizure disorder.\nSexually Transmitted Infections (STIs): Infections that are spread by sexual contact.\nInfections include chlamydia, gonorrhea, human papillomavirus (HPV), herpes, syphilis,\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nand human immunodeficiency virus (HIV, the cause of acquired immunodeficiency\nsyndrome [AIDS]).\nStillbirth: Birth of a dead fetus.\nToxoplasmosis: An infection caused by Toxoplasma gondii, an organism that may be\nfound in raw meat, garden soil, and cat feces (stool)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Epilepsy is one kind of seizure disorder.\nSexually Transmitted Infections (STIs): Infections that are spread by sexual contact.\nInfections include chlamydia, gonorrhea, human papillomavirus (HPV), herpes, syphilis,\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nand human immunodeficiency virus (HIV, the cause of acquired immunodeficiency\nsyndrome [AIDS]).\nStillbirth: Birth of a dead fetus.\nToxoplasmosis: An infection caused by Toxoplasma gondii, an organism that may be\nfound in raw meat, garden soil, and cat feces (stool)?",
        "answer": "This infection can harm a fetus.\nVaccine: A substance that helps the body fight disease"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This infection can harm a fetus.\nVaccine: A substance that helps the body fight disease?",
        "answer": "Vaccines are made from very\nsmall amounts of weak or dead agents that cause disease (bacteria, toxins, and\nviruses).\nZika: A disease caused by the Zika virus, which is spread through mosquito bites.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ146\nPublished: October 2019\nLast reviewed: April 2023\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Vaccines are made from very\nsmall amounts of weak or dead agents that cause disease (bacteria, toxins, and\nviruses).\nZika: A disease caused by the Zika virus, which is spread through mosquito bites.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ146\nPublished: October 2019\nLast reviewed: April 2023\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nRepeated Miscarriages\nFrequently Asked Questions\nOverview\nRecurrent pregnancy loss  is defined as having two or more miscarriages"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nRepeated Miscarriages\nFrequently Asked Questions\nOverview\nRecurrent pregnancy loss  is defined as having two or more miscarriages?",
        "answer": "After two\nmiscarriages, a thorough physical exam and testing are recommended.\nA small number of women have repeated miscarriages"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is After two\nmiscarriages, a thorough physical exam and testing are recommended.\nA small number of women have repeated miscarriages?",
        "answer": "It\u2019s estimated that fewer than 5\nin 100 have two miscarriages in a row.\nPossible Causes\nAbout half of miscarriages occur randomly when an embryo  receives an abnormal\nnumber of chromosomes  during fertilization"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\u2019s estimated that fewer than 5\nin 100 have two miscarriages in a row.\nPossible Causes\nAbout half of miscarriages occur randomly when an embryo  receives an abnormal\nnumber of chromosomes  during fertilization?",
        "answer": "This type of genetic problem happens by\nchance"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This type of genetic problem happens by\nchance?",
        "answer": "There is no medical condition that causes it"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There is no medical condition that causes it?",
        "answer": "But the chance of this problem\nincreases with age.\nFAQs\nWhat is recurrent pregnancy loss?\nWhat is the likelihood of having repeated miscarriages?\nWhat is the most common cause of miscarriage?\nCan other genetic problems cause repeated miscarriages?\nIn a small number of couples who have repeated miscarriages, one partner has a\nchromosome in which a piece is transferred to another chromosome"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But the chance of this problem\nincreases with age.\nFAQs\nWhat is recurrent pregnancy loss?\nWhat is the likelihood of having repeated miscarriages?\nWhat is the most common cause of miscarriage?\nCan other genetic problems cause repeated miscarriages?\nIn a small number of couples who have repeated miscarriages, one partner has a\nchromosome in which a piece is transferred to another chromosome?",
        "answer": "This is called a\ntranslocation .\nPeople who have a translocation usually do not have any physical signs or symptoms,\nbut some of their eggs  or sperm  will have abnormal chromosomes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is called a\ntranslocation .\nPeople who have a translocation usually do not have any physical signs or symptoms,\nbut some of their eggs  or sperm  will have abnormal chromosomes?",
        "answer": "If an embryo gets\ntoo much or too little genetic material, it often leads to a miscarriage.\nSome medical conditions may increase the risk of repeated miscarriages:\nIn more than half of women with repeated miscarriages, no cause can be found for the\npregnancy loss"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If an embryo gets\ntoo much or too little genetic material, it often leads to a miscarriage.\nSome medical conditions may increase the risk of repeated miscarriages:\nIn more than half of women with repeated miscarriages, no cause can be found for the\npregnancy loss?",
        "answer": "There may be clues about what the problem is, but there is no sure\nanswer.\nTests and Treatment\nCan medical conditions increase the risk of repeated miscarriages?\nCertain congenital  problems of the uterus \u2014Although there are many such\ndisorders, one of the most common that has been linked to miscarriage is a septate\nuterus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There may be clues about what the problem is, but there is no sure\nanswer.\nTests and Treatment\nCan medical conditions increase the risk of repeated miscarriages?\nCertain congenital  problems of the uterus \u2014Although there are many such\ndisorders, one of the most common that has been linked to miscarriage is a septate\nuterus?",
        "answer": "In this condition, the uterus is partially divided into two sections by a wall of\ntissue.\n\u2022\nAsherman syndrome\u2014This condition causes adhesions  and scarring in the uterus.\n\u2022\nFibroids and polyps\u2014These are benign (noncancer) growths of the uterus.\n\u2022\nAntiphospholipid syndrome (APS) \u2014This autoimmune disorder  that affects blood\nclotting can cause a variety of medical problems"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In this condition, the uterus is partially divided into two sections by a wall of\ntissue.\n\u2022\nAsherman syndrome\u2014This condition causes adhesions  and scarring in the uterus.\n\u2022\nFibroids and polyps\u2014These are benign (noncancer) growths of the uterus.\n\u2022\nAntiphospholipid syndrome (APS) \u2014This autoimmune disorder  that affects blood\nclotting can cause a variety of medical problems?",
        "answer": "APS can occur alone or with other\nautoimmune diseases, such as lupus .\n\u2022\nDiabetes mellitus \u2014Diabetes, especially if the disease is poorly controlled, can\nincrease the risk of pregnancy loss"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is APS can occur alone or with other\nautoimmune diseases, such as lupus .\n\u2022\nDiabetes mellitus \u2014Diabetes, especially if the disease is poorly controlled, can\nincrease the risk of pregnancy loss?",
        "answer": "Keeping blood sugar levels in the normal range\nbefore pregnancy and throughout pregnancy can decrease the risk.\n\u2022\nThyroid disease\u2014Problems with the thyroid gland  that are not treated can increase\nthe risk of miscarriage"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Keeping blood sugar levels in the normal range\nbefore pregnancy and throughout pregnancy can decrease the risk.\n\u2022\nThyroid disease\u2014Problems with the thyroid gland  that are not treated can increase\nthe risk of miscarriage?",
        "answer": "Treating thyroid problems can decrease the risk.\n\u2022\nPolycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS)\n\u2022\nHow common are unexplained repeated miscarriages?\nTo help find the cause of repeated miscarriages, your health care professional should\nask about your medical history and past pregnancies"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Treating thyroid problems can decrease the risk.\n\u2022\nPolycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS)\n\u2022\nHow common are unexplained repeated miscarriages?\nTo help find the cause of repeated miscarriages, your health care professional should\nask about your medical history and past pregnancies?",
        "answer": "A complete physical exam,\nincluding a pelvic exam , may be done.\nYou may have blood tests to detect problems with the immune system"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A complete physical exam,\nincluding a pelvic exam , may be done.\nYou may have blood tests to detect problems with the immune system?",
        "answer": "Testing may be\ndone to help detect genetic causes of repeated miscarriages"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Testing may be\ndone to help detect genetic causes of repeated miscarriages?",
        "answer": "Imaging tests may be\nconsidered to find out if a uterine problem is causing repeated miscarriages.\nEven if no cause is found, the chances of having a successful pregnancy without special\ntreatment are good"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Imaging tests may be\nconsidered to find out if a uterine problem is causing repeated miscarriages.\nEven if no cause is found, the chances of having a successful pregnancy without special\ntreatment are good?",
        "answer": "About 65 in 100 women with unexplained recurrent pregnancy loss\nhave a successful next pregnancy.\nIf a specific cause of your repeated miscarriages can be identified, your health care\nprofessional may suggest a treatment that addresses the cause.\nIf you have a chromosome translocation, genetic counseling may be recommended.\nResults of genetic testing can help clarify your options"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is About 65 in 100 women with unexplained recurrent pregnancy loss\nhave a successful next pregnancy.\nIf a specific cause of your repeated miscarriages can be identified, your health care\nprofessional may suggest a treatment that addresses the cause.\nIf you have a chromosome translocation, genetic counseling may be recommended.\nResults of genetic testing can help clarify your options?",
        "answer": "In vitro fertilization (IVF)  with\nspecial genetic testing called preimplantation genetic testing  may be done to select\nunaffected embryos"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In vitro fertilization (IVF)  with\nspecial genetic testing called preimplantation genetic testing  may be done to select\nunaffected embryos?",
        "answer": "IVF can also be done with donor eggs, or intrauterine insemination\n(IUI)  can be done with donor sperm.\nCorrective surgery may be able to increase the chances for a successful pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is IVF can also be done with donor eggs, or intrauterine insemination\n(IUI)  can be done with donor sperm.\nCorrective surgery may be able to increase the chances for a successful pregnancy?",
        "answer": "For\nexample, a septum in the uterus can be removed.\nWhat tests and exams are available to help find the cause of repeated\nmiscarriages?\nWhat are my chances of having a successful pregnancy if I have repeated\nmiscarriages and no cause is found?\nIs treatment available if the cause of my repeated miscarriages can be found?\nWhat can be done if I have a chromosome translocation?\nHow can problems with reproductive organs be treated?\nWhat treatment is available if I have antiphospholipid syndrome?\nUse of a medication that prevents blood clots, such as heparin, sometimes combined\nwith low-dose aspirin, may be prescribed throughout pregnancy and for a few weeks\nafterward"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For\nexample, a septum in the uterus can be removed.\nWhat tests and exams are available to help find the cause of repeated\nmiscarriages?\nWhat are my chances of having a successful pregnancy if I have repeated\nmiscarriages and no cause is found?\nIs treatment available if the cause of my repeated miscarriages can be found?\nWhat can be done if I have a chromosome translocation?\nHow can problems with reproductive organs be treated?\nWhat treatment is available if I have antiphospholipid syndrome?\nUse of a medication that prevents blood clots, such as heparin, sometimes combined\nwith low-dose aspirin, may be prescribed throughout pregnancy and for a few weeks\nafterward?",
        "answer": "This treatment can increase the rates of successful pregnancy.\nFinding Support and Trying Again\nIt\u2019s normal to feel grief after the loss of a pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This treatment can increase the rates of successful pregnancy.\nFinding Support and Trying Again\nIt\u2019s normal to feel grief after the loss of a pregnancy?",
        "answer": "In most cases, physical recovery\nfrom miscarriage takes only a few hours to a couple of days, but the grieving process\ncan take longer"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In most cases, physical recovery\nfrom miscarriage takes only a few hours to a couple of days, but the grieving process\ncan take longer?",
        "answer": "When you have had repeated miscarriages, you may feel like you did\nsomething to make the miscarriages happen"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When you have had repeated miscarriages, you may feel like you did\nsomething to make the miscarriages happen?",
        "answer": "It\u2019s important to remember that\nmiscarriages are almost never caused by anything you did or did not do.\nYour feelings of grief may differ from those of your partner"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\u2019s important to remember that\nmiscarriages are almost never caused by anything you did or did not do.\nYour feelings of grief may differ from those of your partner?",
        "answer": "You are the one who has felt\nthe physical changes of pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You are the one who has felt\nthe physical changes of pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Your partner may also grieve but may not express\nfeelings in the same way you do"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your partner may also grieve but may not express\nfeelings in the same way you do?",
        "answer": "If either of you is having trouble handling the feelings\nthat go along with a pregnancy loss, talk with a health care professional, such as your\nobstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  or a therapist.\nYou may want to reach out to those closest to you and ask for their comfort and\nsupport"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If either of you is having trouble handling the feelings\nthat go along with a pregnancy loss, talk with a health care professional, such as your\nobstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  or a therapist.\nYou may want to reach out to those closest to you and ask for their comfort and\nsupport?",
        "answer": "When you visit your ob-gyn for follow-up care, talk about how you are feeling\nand any other issues related to your pregnancy losses"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When you visit your ob-gyn for follow-up care, talk about how you are feeling\nand any other issues related to your pregnancy losses?",
        "answer": "Sometimes, further counseling\nor referral to a support group in your area can help you and your partner cope.\nYou may want to take time to recover emotionally before trying again"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Sometimes, further counseling\nor referral to a support group in your area can help you and your partner cope.\nYou may want to take time to recover emotionally before trying again?",
        "answer": "But you can\novulate and get pregnant as soon as 2 weeks after an early miscarriage"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But you can\novulate and get pregnant as soon as 2 weeks after an early miscarriage?",
        "answer": "Talk with your\nob-gyn about the best timing for trying again.\nIf you decide to get pregnant again, it\u2019s a good idea to be as healthy as possible\nbeforehand"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Talk with your\nob-gyn about the best timing for trying again.\nIf you decide to get pregnant again, it\u2019s a good idea to be as healthy as possible\nbeforehand?",
        "answer": "The following is standard advice given to everyone planning a pregnancy:\nWhat should I know about coping with repeated miscarriages?\nWhat should I know if I\u2019m thinking about trying again?\nSee your ob-gyn for a prepregnancy care checkup.\n\u2022\nTake 400 micrograms of folic acid  as a daily dietary supplement.\n\u2022\nFollow a healthy diet and get 30 minutes of exercise on most days of the week.\n\u2022\nYou may also decide not to try to get pregnant again"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The following is standard advice given to everyone planning a pregnancy:\nWhat should I know about coping with repeated miscarriages?\nWhat should I know if I\u2019m thinking about trying again?\nSee your ob-gyn for a prepregnancy care checkup.\n\u2022\nTake 400 micrograms of folic acid  as a daily dietary supplement.\n\u2022\nFollow a healthy diet and get 30 minutes of exercise on most days of the week.\n\u2022\nYou may also decide not to try to get pregnant again?",
        "answer": "No choice is right or wrong"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is No choice is right or wrong?",
        "answer": "You\nshould decide what is best for you.\nResources and Glossary\nRISE Pregnancy Loss\nResearchers are working to understand how genetics can affect or cause recurrent\npregnancy loss"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You\nshould decide what is best for you.\nResources and Glossary\nRISE Pregnancy Loss\nResearchers are working to understand how genetics can affect or cause recurrent\npregnancy loss?",
        "answer": "These experts are at Yale School of Medicine and other medical\nschools across the United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These experts are at Yale School of Medicine and other medical\nschools across the United States?",
        "answer": "If you want to help with this research, you can learn\nmore and join the study at risepregnancyloss.org.\nAdhesions: Scars that can make tissue surfaces stick together.\nAntiphospholipid Syndrome (APS): A disorder that can lead to abnormal blood clotting\nand pregnancy problems.\nAutoimmune Disorder: A condition in which the body attacks its own tissues.\nChromosomes: Structures that are located inside each cell in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you want to help with this research, you can learn\nmore and join the study at risepregnancyloss.org.\nAdhesions: Scars that can make tissue surfaces stick together.\nAntiphospholipid Syndrome (APS): A disorder that can lead to abnormal blood clotting\nand pregnancy problems.\nAutoimmune Disorder: A condition in which the body attacks its own tissues.\nChromosomes: Structures that are located inside each cell in the body?",
        "answer": "They contain the\ngenes that determine a person\u2019s physical makeup.\nCongenital: A condition that a person has from birth.\nDiabetes Mellitus: A condition in which the levels of sugar in the blood are too high.\nReach a normal weight for your height"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They contain the\ngenes that determine a person\u2019s physical makeup.\nCongenital: A condition that a person has from birth.\nDiabetes Mellitus: A condition in which the levels of sugar in the blood are too high.\nReach a normal weight for your height?",
        "answer": "Lose weight if you are overweight or gain\nweight if you are underweight.\n\u2022\nDo not drink alcohol.\n\u2022\nDo not smoke.\n\u2022\nIf you have a medical condition, work with your health care team to get your condition\nunder control before trying to get pregnant.\n\u2022\nResources\nGlossary\nEggs: The female reproductive cells made in and released from the ovaries"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Lose weight if you are overweight or gain\nweight if you are underweight.\n\u2022\nDo not drink alcohol.\n\u2022\nDo not smoke.\n\u2022\nIf you have a medical condition, work with your health care team to get your condition\nunder control before trying to get pregnant.\n\u2022\nResources\nGlossary\nEggs: The female reproductive cells made in and released from the ovaries?",
        "answer": "Also called\nthe ova.\nEmbryo: The stage of development that starts at fertilization (joining of an egg and\nsperm) and lasts up to 8 weeks.\nFertilization: A multistep process that joins the egg and the sperm.\nFolic Acid: A vitamin that reduces the risk of certain birth defects when taken before\nand during pregnancy.\nIntrauterine Insemination (IUI): A procedure in which a man\u2019s sperm is placed in a\nwoman\u2019s uterus.\nIn Vitro Fertilization (IVF): A procedure in which an egg is removed from a woman\u2019s\novary, fertilized in a laboratory with the man\u2019s sperm, and then transferred to the\nwoman\u2019s uterus to achieve a pregnancy.\nLupus: An autoimmune disorder that affects the connective tissues in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also called\nthe ova.\nEmbryo: The stage of development that starts at fertilization (joining of an egg and\nsperm) and lasts up to 8 weeks.\nFertilization: A multistep process that joins the egg and the sperm.\nFolic Acid: A vitamin that reduces the risk of certain birth defects when taken before\nand during pregnancy.\nIntrauterine Insemination (IUI): A procedure in which a man\u2019s sperm is placed in a\nwoman\u2019s uterus.\nIn Vitro Fertilization (IVF): A procedure in which an egg is removed from a woman\u2019s\novary, fertilized in a laboratory with the man\u2019s sperm, and then transferred to the\nwoman\u2019s uterus to achieve a pregnancy.\nLupus: An autoimmune disorder that affects the connective tissues in the body?",
        "answer": "The\ndisorder can cause arthritis, kidney disease, heart disease, blood disorders, and\ncomplications during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The\ndisorder can cause arthritis, kidney disease, heart disease, blood disorders, and\ncomplications during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Also called systemic lupus erythematosus or SLE.\nMiscarriage: Loss of a pregnancy that is in the uterus.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPelvic Exam: A physical examination of a woman\u2019s pelvic organs.\nPolycystic Ovary Syndrome (PCOS): A condition that leads to a hormone imbalance that\naffects a woman\u2019s monthly menstrual periods, ovulation, ability to get pregnant, and\nmetabolism.\nPreimplantation Genetic Testing: A type of genetic testing that can be done during in\nvitro fertilization"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also called systemic lupus erythematosus or SLE.\nMiscarriage: Loss of a pregnancy that is in the uterus.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPelvic Exam: A physical examination of a woman\u2019s pelvic organs.\nPolycystic Ovary Syndrome (PCOS): A condition that leads to a hormone imbalance that\naffects a woman\u2019s monthly menstrual periods, ovulation, ability to get pregnant, and\nmetabolism.\nPreimplantation Genetic Testing: A type of genetic testing that can be done during in\nvitro fertilization?",
        "answer": "Tests are done on the fertilized egg before it is transferred to the\nuterus.\nRecurrent Pregnancy Loss: Two or more pregnancy losses.\nSperm: A cell made in the male testicles that can fertilize a female egg.\nThyroid Gland: A butterfly-shaped gland located at the base of the neck in front of the\nwindpipe"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Tests are done on the fertilized egg before it is transferred to the\nuterus.\nRecurrent Pregnancy Loss: Two or more pregnancy losses.\nSperm: A cell made in the male testicles that can fertilize a female egg.\nThyroid Gland: A butterfly-shaped gland located at the base of the neck in front of the\nwindpipe?",
        "answer": "This gland makes, stores, and releases thyroid hormone, which controls the\nbody\u2019s metabolism and regulates how parts of the body work.\nTranslocation: When one part of a chromosome is moved to another chromosome.\nUterus: A muscular organ in the female pelvis"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This gland makes, stores, and releases thyroid hormone, which controls the\nbody\u2019s metabolism and regulates how parts of the body work.\nTranslocation: When one part of a chromosome is moved to another chromosome.\nUterus: A muscular organ in the female pelvis?",
        "answer": "During pregnancy, this organ holds and\nnourishes the fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During pregnancy, this organ holds and\nnourishes the fetus?",
        "answer": "Also called the womb.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ100\nLast updated: January 2023\nLast reviewed: April 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also called the womb.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ100\nLast updated: January 2023\nLast reviewed: April 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nRoutine Tests During Pregnancy\nCertain lab tests are part of routine care during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nRoutine Tests During Pregnancy\nCertain lab tests are part of routine care during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Some of these tests are\ndone with a blood sample"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some of these tests are\ndone with a blood sample?",
        "answer": "Others use a urine sample or a sample of fluid taken from\nyour vagina , cervix , or rectum"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Others use a urine sample or a sample of fluid taken from\nyour vagina , cervix , or rectum?",
        "answer": "These tests can help find conditions that may\nincrease the risk of complications  for you and your fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These tests can help find conditions that may\nincrease the risk of complications  for you and your fetus?",
        "answer": "Many problems found by\nthese tests can be treated during pregnancy.\nTests Done Early in Pregnancy\nSeveral routine lab tests are done early in pregnancy, including\nAlso, pregnant women typically are tested for specific diseases and infections early in\npregnancy, including\nFAQs\nWhat tests are done early in pregnancy?\ncomplete blood count (CBC)\n\u2022\nblood type and Rh factor\n\u2022\nurinalysis\n\u2022\nurine culture\n\u2022\nrubella\n\u2022\nhepatitis B  and hepatitis C\n\u2022\nhuman immunodeficiency virus (HIV)\n\u2022\nother sexually transmitted infections (STIs)\n\u2022\nA CBC counts the number of different types of cells  that make up your blood"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Many problems found by\nthese tests can be treated during pregnancy.\nTests Done Early in Pregnancy\nSeveral routine lab tests are done early in pregnancy, including\nAlso, pregnant women typically are tested for specific diseases and infections early in\npregnancy, including\nFAQs\nWhat tests are done early in pregnancy?\ncomplete blood count (CBC)\n\u2022\nblood type and Rh factor\n\u2022\nurinalysis\n\u2022\nurine culture\n\u2022\nrubella\n\u2022\nhepatitis B  and hepatitis C\n\u2022\nhuman immunodeficiency virus (HIV)\n\u2022\nother sexually transmitted infections (STIs)\n\u2022\nA CBC counts the number of different types of cells  that make up your blood?",
        "answer": "The\nnumber of red blood cells can show whether you have a certain type of anemia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The\nnumber of red blood cells can show whether you have a certain type of anemia?",
        "answer": "The\nnumber of white blood cells can show how many disease-fighting cells are in your\nblood"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The\nnumber of white blood cells can show how many disease-fighting cells are in your\nblood?",
        "answer": "The number of platelets can reveal whether you have a problem with blood\nclotting.\nYes, during the first trimester  of pregnancy you will have a blood test to find out your\nblood type, such as type A or type B"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The number of platelets can reveal whether you have a problem with blood\nclotting.\nYes, during the first trimester  of pregnancy you will have a blood test to find out your\nblood type, such as type A or type B?",
        "answer": "Also, your blood will be tested for the Rh factor.\nThe Rh factor is a protein that can be found on the surface of red blood cells"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also, your blood will be tested for the Rh factor.\nThe Rh factor is a protein that can be found on the surface of red blood cells?",
        "answer": "If your\nblood cells have this protein, you are Rh positive"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If your\nblood cells have this protein, you are Rh positive?",
        "answer": "If your blood cells do not have this\nprotein, you are Rh negative"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If your blood cells do not have this\nprotein, you are Rh negative?",
        "answer": "The \u201cpositive\u201d or \u201cnegative\u201d part of your blood type, such as\nO positive or A negative, refers to your Rh status.\nIf you are Rh negative and your fetus is Rh positive, your body can make antibodies\nagainst the Rh factor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The \u201cpositive\u201d or \u201cnegative\u201d part of your blood type, such as\nO positive or A negative, refers to your Rh status.\nIf you are Rh negative and your fetus is Rh positive, your body can make antibodies\nagainst the Rh factor?",
        "answer": "These antibodies can damage the fetus\u2019s red blood cells"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These antibodies can damage the fetus\u2019s red blood cells?",
        "answer": "This\nusually does not cause problems in a first pregnancy, when your body makes only a\nsmall number of antibodies"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This\nusually does not cause problems in a first pregnancy, when your body makes only a\nsmall number of antibodies?",
        "answer": "But it can cause serious issues in a later pregnancy,\nincluding stillbirth .\nIf you are Rh negative, you may be given medication during pregnancy to help prevent\nthe development of Rh antibodies"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But it can cause serious issues in a later pregnancy,\nincluding stillbirth .\nIf you are Rh negative, you may be given medication during pregnancy to help prevent\nthe development of Rh antibodies?",
        "answer": "If you are Rh negative and have already made a\ncertain number of Rh antibodies, you might need special tests and monitoring\nthroughout pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are Rh negative and have already made a\ncertain number of Rh antibodies, you might need special tests and monitoring\nthroughout pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Your baby may also need treatment after birth.\ntuberculosis (TB)\n\u2022\nWhat does a complete blood count test for?\nWill I be tested for blood type?\nWhat is the Rh factor?\nWhy is it important to know your Rh status?\nWhat will happen if I am Rh negative?\nRead The Rh Factor: How It Can Affect Your Pregnancy to learn more.\nA urinalysis is a quick test of your urine for\nThis test also measures the amount of protein in your blood, which can be compared to\nlevels later in pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your baby may also need treatment after birth.\ntuberculosis (TB)\n\u2022\nWhat does a complete blood count test for?\nWill I be tested for blood type?\nWhat is the Rh factor?\nWhy is it important to know your Rh status?\nWhat will happen if I am Rh negative?\nRead The Rh Factor: How It Can Affect Your Pregnancy to learn more.\nA urinalysis is a quick test of your urine for\nThis test also measures the amount of protein in your blood, which can be compared to\nlevels later in pregnancy?",
        "answer": "High protein levels may signal kidney disease\nor\u00a0 preeclampsia , a serious complication that can occur later in pregnancy or after the\nbaby is born.\nThis test looks for bacteria  in your urine, which can be a sign of a UTI"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is High protein levels may signal kidney disease\nor\u00a0 preeclampsia , a serious complication that can occur later in pregnancy or after the\nbaby is born.\nThis test looks for bacteria  in your urine, which can be a sign of a UTI?",
        "answer": "This test is done\nbecause sometimes UTIs do not cause symptoms.\nIt can take several days to get the results of this test"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This test is done\nbecause sometimes UTIs do not cause symptoms.\nIt can take several days to get the results of this test?",
        "answer": "If the test shows bacteria in your\nurine, you should be treated with antibiotics"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If the test shows bacteria in your\nurine, you should be treated with antibiotics?",
        "answer": "After you finish treatment, you may have a\nrepeat test to see if the bacteria are gone.\nRubella (sometimes called German measles) can cause birth defects  if you are\ninfected during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is After you finish treatment, you may have a\nrepeat test to see if the bacteria are gone.\nRubella (sometimes called German measles) can cause birth defects  if you are\ninfected during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Your blood can show whether you have been infected with\nrubella or if you have been vaccinated against this disease"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your blood can show whether you have been infected with\nrubella or if you have been vaccinated against this disease?",
        "answer": "If you had this infection\nbefore or you have been vaccinated against rubella, you are immune  to the disease.\nRubella is easily spread"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you had this infection\nbefore or you have been vaccinated against rubella, you are immune  to the disease.\nRubella is easily spread?",
        "answer": "If your blood test shows you are not immune, avoid anyone who\nhas the disease while you are pregnant"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If your blood test shows you are not immune, avoid anyone who\nhas the disease while you are pregnant?",
        "answer": "There is a vaccine, but it contains a live virus\nand is not recommended during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There is a vaccine, but it contains a live virus\nand is not recommended during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "If you have not been vaccinated, you can get\nthe measles-mumps-rubella (MMR) vaccine  after the baby is born.\nWhat is a urinalysis?\nred blood cells, a possible sign of a urinary tract disease\n\u2022\nwhite blood cells, a possible sign of a urinary tract infection (UTI)\n\u2022\nglucose , because high levels of blood sugar can be a sign of diabetes\n\u2022\nWhat is a urine culture?\nWhy is testing for rubella done?\nWhat if I\u2019m not immune to rubella?\nHepatitis is a virus that infects the liver"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have not been vaccinated, you can get\nthe measles-mumps-rubella (MMR) vaccine  after the baby is born.\nWhat is a urinalysis?\nred blood cells, a possible sign of a urinary tract disease\n\u2022\nwhite blood cells, a possible sign of a urinary tract infection (UTI)\n\u2022\nglucose , because high levels of blood sugar can be a sign of diabetes\n\u2022\nWhat is a urine culture?\nWhy is testing for rubella done?\nWhat if I\u2019m not immune to rubella?\nHepatitis is a virus that infects the liver?",
        "answer": "If you are pregnant and have hepatitis B or\nhepatitis C, you can pass the virus to your fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are pregnant and have hepatitis B or\nhepatitis C, you can pass the virus to your fetus?",
        "answer": "Everyone should be tested for hepatitis\nB and hepatitis C infection during pregnancy.\nIf you are infected with hepatitis B or hepatitis C, you might need special care during\npregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Everyone should be tested for hepatitis\nB and hepatitis C infection during pregnancy.\nIf you are infected with hepatitis B or hepatitis C, you might need special care during\npregnancy?",
        "answer": "Your baby may also need special care after birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your baby may also need special care after birth?",
        "answer": "You can breastfeed if you\nhave either infection"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can breastfeed if you\nhave either infection?",
        "answer": "A vaccine is available to protect the baby against hepatitis B"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A vaccine is available to protect the baby against hepatitis B?",
        "answer": "The\nvaccine is given as a series of three shots, with the first dose given to the baby within a\nfew hours of birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The\nvaccine is given as a series of three shots, with the first dose given to the baby within a\nfew hours of birth?",
        "answer": "Read Hepatitis B and Hepatitis C in Pregnancy to learn more.\nHIV attacks cells of the body\u2019s immune system and causes acquired immunodeficiency\nsyndrome (AIDS)  if not treated"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read Hepatitis B and Hepatitis C in Pregnancy to learn more.\nHIV attacks cells of the body\u2019s immune system and causes acquired immunodeficiency\nsyndrome (AIDS)  if not treated?",
        "answer": "If you have HIV, there is a chance you could pass it to\nyour fetus.\nWhile you are pregnant, you can take medication that can greatly reduce the risk of\npassing HIV to your fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have HIV, there is a chance you could pass it to\nyour fetus.\nWhile you are pregnant, you can take medication that can greatly reduce the risk of\npassing HIV to your fetus?",
        "answer": "You can also get specialized care to ensure that you stay as\nhealthy as possible throughout your pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can also get specialized care to ensure that you stay as\nhealthy as possible throughout your pregnancy?",
        "answer": "This is why everyone is tested for HIV\nearly in pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is why everyone is tested for HIV\nearly in pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Read HIV and Pregnancy to learn more.\nYou should be tested for syphilis three times during pregnancy: at your first prenatal\nvisit, in the third trimester, and at delivery.\u00a0\nYou should be tested for chlamydia  and gonorrhea if you are under age 25 or if you are\nat increased risk for getting STIs.\nThese tests are done early in pregnancy because these infections can cause serious\nproblems for you and your fetus.\nWhat is hepatitis?\nWhat if I have hepatitis during pregnancy?\nWhy is it important to have a test for HIV?\nWhat if I have HIV?\nWhat other STI tests are done?\nWhat if I have syphilis, chlamydia, or gonorrhea?\nIf you have syphilis, chlamydia, or gonorrhea, you should be treated during pregnancy\nand tested again to see if the treatment has worked"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read HIV and Pregnancy to learn more.\nYou should be tested for syphilis three times during pregnancy: at your first prenatal\nvisit, in the third trimester, and at delivery.\u00a0\nYou should be tested for chlamydia  and gonorrhea if you are under age 25 or if you are\nat increased risk for getting STIs.\nThese tests are done early in pregnancy because these infections can cause serious\nproblems for you and your fetus.\nWhat is hepatitis?\nWhat if I have hepatitis during pregnancy?\nWhy is it important to have a test for HIV?\nWhat if I have HIV?\nWhat other STI tests are done?\nWhat if I have syphilis, chlamydia, or gonorrhea?\nIf you have syphilis, chlamydia, or gonorrhea, you should be treated during pregnancy\nand tested again to see if the treatment has worked?",
        "answer": "Your sex partner or partners should\nalso be treated to prevent you from getting infected again.\nPeople who are at high risk of TB should be tested for it"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your sex partner or partners should\nalso be treated to prevent you from getting infected again.\nPeople who are at high risk of TB should be tested for it?",
        "answer": "Those at high risk include\npeople who are infected with HIV, live in close contact with someone who has TB, or are\nfrom a country with high rates of TB"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Those at high risk include\npeople who are infected with HIV, live in close contact with someone who has TB, or are\nfrom a country with high rates of TB?",
        "answer": "Tests Done Later in Pregnancy\nThe tests done later in pregnancy include glucose screening and group B streptococcus\n(GBS)  screening.\nThis test measures the level of glucose, or sugar, in your blood"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Tests Done Later in Pregnancy\nThe tests done later in pregnancy include glucose screening and group B streptococcus\n(GBS)  screening.\nThis test measures the level of glucose, or sugar, in your blood?",
        "answer": "A high blood sugar level\nmay be a sign of gestational diabetes , which can cause problems during pregnancy.\nFor this test, you drink a special sugar mixture"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A high blood sugar level\nmay be a sign of gestational diabetes , which can cause problems during pregnancy.\nFor this test, you drink a special sugar mixture?",
        "answer": "An hour later, a blood sample is taken\nand sent to a lab"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An hour later, a blood sample is taken\nand sent to a lab?",
        "answer": "If your blood sugar level is high, you should have another type of\nglucose test to confirm the results.\nThis test usually is done between 24 and 28 weeks of pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If your blood sugar level is high, you should have another type of\nglucose test to confirm the results.\nThis test usually is done between 24 and 28 weeks of pregnancy?",
        "answer": "This test might be\ndone in the first trimester of pregnancy if you have risk factors for diabetes or had\ngestational diabetes in a past pregnancy.\nGBS is one of the many bacteria that live in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This test might be\ndone in the first trimester of pregnancy if you have risk factors for diabetes or had\ngestational diabetes in a past pregnancy.\nGBS is one of the many bacteria that live in the body?",
        "answer": "It usually does not cause serious\nillness in adults, and it is not an STI.\nWho should be tested for tuberculosis (TB)?\nWhat tests are done later in pregnancy?\nWhat is a glucose screening test?\nWhen is a glucose screening done?\nWhat is group B strep (GBS)?\nWhy is GBS a concern during pregnancy?\nIn women, GBS is most often found in the vagina and rectum"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It usually does not cause serious\nillness in adults, and it is not an STI.\nWho should be tested for tuberculosis (TB)?\nWhat tests are done later in pregnancy?\nWhat is a glucose screening test?\nWhen is a glucose screening done?\nWhat is group B strep (GBS)?\nWhy is GBS a concern during pregnancy?\nIn women, GBS is most often found in the vagina and rectum?",
        "answer": "This means that GBS can\npass from you to your fetus during labor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This means that GBS can\npass from you to your fetus during labor?",
        "answer": "This is rare"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is rare?",
        "answer": "It happens to 1 or 2 babies out of\n100 when the mother does not receive treatment with antibiotics during labor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It happens to 1 or 2 babies out of\n100 when the mother does not receive treatment with antibiotics during labor?",
        "answer": "The\nchance of a newborn getting sick is much lower when the mother receives treatment.\nEven though it is rare for a baby to get GBS, it can be very serious when it happens"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The\nchance of a newborn getting sick is much lower when the mother receives treatment.\nEven though it is rare for a baby to get GBS, it can be very serious when it happens?",
        "answer": "A\nsmall number of babies with GBS die even with immediate treatment.\nThe test for GBS is called a culture"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A\nsmall number of babies with GBS die even with immediate treatment.\nThe test for GBS is called a culture?",
        "answer": "It is done between 36 and 38 weeks of pregnancy.\nFor this test, a swab is used to take a sample from the vagina and rectum.\nIf the results show that GBS is present, antibiotics should be given through an\nintravenous (IV) line  once labor has started"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is done between 36 and 38 weeks of pregnancy.\nFor this test, a swab is used to take a sample from the vagina and rectum.\nIf the results show that GBS is present, antibiotics should be given through an\nintravenous (IV) line  once labor has started?",
        "answer": "This is done to help protect the fetus from\nbeing infected"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is done to help protect the fetus from\nbeing infected?",
        "answer": "The best time for treatment is during labor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The best time for treatment is during labor?",
        "answer": "Read Group B Strep and\nPregnancy to learn more.\nGenetic Testing for Birth Defects\nScreening for birth defects begins by assessing your risk factors"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read Group B Strep and\nPregnancy to learn more.\nGenetic Testing for Birth Defects\nScreening for birth defects begins by assessing your risk factors?",
        "answer": "Early in your\npregnancy, your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn) \u00a0may give you a list of questions to\nfind out whether you have risk factors"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Early in your\npregnancy, your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn) \u00a0may give you a list of questions to\nfind out whether you have risk factors?",
        "answer": "If you do have risk factors, you might want to see\na genetic counselor  for more detailed information about your risks.\nMost babies with birth defects are born to couples without risk factors"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you do have risk factors, you might want to see\na genetic counselor  for more detailed information about your risks.\nMost babies with birth defects are born to couples without risk factors?",
        "answer": "But the risk of\nbirth defects is higher when certain factors are present"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But the risk of\nbirth defects is higher when certain factors are present?",
        "answer": "Risk factors include\nHow can GBS affect a newborn?\nHow is the test for GBS done?\nWhat is the first step to screen for birth defects during pregnancy?\nWhat factors increase the risk of birth defects?\nhaving a personal or family history of birth defects\n\u2022\nbelonging to certain ethnic groups\n\u2022\nbeing 35 or older\n\u2022\nWhen done during pregnancy, screening tests\u00a0can tell you the chances that the fetus\nmay be at risk for certain common birth defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Risk factors include\nHow can GBS affect a newborn?\nHow is the test for GBS done?\nWhat is the first step to screen for birth defects during pregnancy?\nWhat factors increase the risk of birth defects?\nhaving a personal or family history of birth defects\n\u2022\nbelonging to certain ethnic groups\n\u2022\nbeing 35 or older\n\u2022\nWhen done during pregnancy, screening tests\u00a0can tell you the chances that the fetus\nmay be at risk for certain common birth defects?",
        "answer": "A screening test cannot tell whether\nthe fetus actually has a birth defect"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A screening test cannot tell whether\nthe fetus actually has a birth defect?",
        "answer": "There is no risk to the fetus from screening tests.\nDiagnostic tests can detect many, but not all, birth defects caused by defects in a gene\nor chromosomes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There is no risk to the fetus from screening tests.\nDiagnostic tests can detect many, but not all, birth defects caused by defects in a gene\nor chromosomes?",
        "answer": "You can choose to have diagnostic tests instead of or in addition to\nscreening tests"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can choose to have diagnostic tests instead of or in addition to\nscreening tests?",
        "answer": "Some diagnostic tests carry risks, including a small risk of pregnancy\nloss.\nNo, screening and testing are a personal choice"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some diagnostic tests carry risks, including a small risk of pregnancy\nloss.\nNo, screening and testing are a personal choice?",
        "answer": "Some people would rather not know if\nthey are at risk of having a child with a birth defect or whether their child will have a birth\ndefect"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some people would rather not know if\nthey are at risk of having a child with a birth defect or whether their child will have a birth\ndefect?",
        "answer": "Others want to know in advance.\nKnowing beforehand allows the option of deciding not to continue the pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Others want to know in advance.\nKnowing beforehand allows the option of deciding not to continue the pregnancy?",
        "answer": "If you\nchoose to continue the pregnancy, knowing beforehand gives you time to prepare for\nhaving a child with a disorder"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you\nchoose to continue the pregnancy, knowing beforehand gives you time to prepare for\nhaving a child with a disorder?",
        "answer": "This means you can organize the medical care your child\nmay need"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This means you can organize the medical care your child\nmay need?",
        "answer": "Talk with your ob-gyn or genetic counselor about your test results.\n[3 Questions to Ask Yourself Before Getting Prenatal Genetic Testing]\nAcquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (AIDS): A group of signs and symptoms, usually\nof severe infections, in a person who has human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).\nAnemia: Abnormally low levels of red blood cells in the bloodstream.\u00a0\nAntibiotics: Medications that treat or decrease the risk of certain infections caused by\nbacteria.\nhaving diabetes before pregnancy\n\u2022\nWhat is the difference between screening and diagnostic testing for birth\ndefects?\nAm I required to have screening or testing for birth defects?\nGlossary\nAntibodies: Proteins in the blood that the body makes in reaction to foreign substances,\nsuch as bacteria and viruses.\nBacteria: One-celled organisms that can cause infections in the human body.\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth.\nCells: The smallest units of structures in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Talk with your ob-gyn or genetic counselor about your test results.\n[3 Questions to Ask Yourself Before Getting Prenatal Genetic Testing]\nAcquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (AIDS): A group of signs and symptoms, usually\nof severe infections, in a person who has human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).\nAnemia: Abnormally low levels of red blood cells in the bloodstream.\u00a0\nAntibiotics: Medications that treat or decrease the risk of certain infections caused by\nbacteria.\nhaving diabetes before pregnancy\n\u2022\nWhat is the difference between screening and diagnostic testing for birth\ndefects?\nAm I required to have screening or testing for birth defects?\nGlossary\nAntibodies: Proteins in the blood that the body makes in reaction to foreign substances,\nsuch as bacteria and viruses.\nBacteria: One-celled organisms that can cause infections in the human body.\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth.\nCells: The smallest units of structures in the body?",
        "answer": "Cells are the building blocks for all\nparts of the body.\nCervix: The lower, narrow end of the uterus at the top of the vagina.\nChlamydia: A sexually transmitted infection caused by bacteria"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Cells are the building blocks for all\nparts of the body.\nCervix: The lower, narrow end of the uterus at the top of the vagina.\nChlamydia: A sexually transmitted infection caused by bacteria?",
        "answer": "This infection can lead\nto pelvic inflammatory disease, pelvic pain, and infertility.\nChromosomes: Structures found in each cell in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This infection can lead\nto pelvic inflammatory disease, pelvic pain, and infertility.\nChromosomes: Structures found in each cell in the body?",
        "answer": "They contain the genes that\ndetermine a person\u2019s physical makeup.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They contain the genes that\ndetermine a person\u2019s physical makeup.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition?",
        "answer": "An example is pneumonia that develops with the flu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example is pneumonia that develops with the flu?",
        "answer": "An example of a\npregnancy complication is preterm labor.\nDiabetes:\u00a0A condition that causes high levels of sugar in the blood.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nGene: Segments of DNA that contain instructions for the development of a person\u2019s\nphysical traits and control of the processes in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example of a\npregnancy complication is preterm labor.\nDiabetes:\u00a0A condition that causes high levels of sugar in the blood.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nGene: Segments of DNA that contain instructions for the development of a person\u2019s\nphysical traits and control of the processes in the body?",
        "answer": "The gene is the basic unit of\nheredity and can be passed from parent to child.\nGenetic Counselor: A health care professional with special training in genetics who can\nprovide expert advice about genetic disorders and prenatal testing.\nGestational Diabetes: Diabetes that starts during pregnancy.\nGlucose: A sugar in the blood that is the body\u2019s main source of fuel.\nGonorrhea: A sexually transmitted infection that can lead to pelvic inflammatory\ndisease, infertility, and arthritis.\nGroup B Streptococcus (GBS): A type of bacteria that many people carry normally and\ncan be passed to the fetus at the time of delivery"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The gene is the basic unit of\nheredity and can be passed from parent to child.\nGenetic Counselor: A health care professional with special training in genetics who can\nprovide expert advice about genetic disorders and prenatal testing.\nGestational Diabetes: Diabetes that starts during pregnancy.\nGlucose: A sugar in the blood that is the body\u2019s main source of fuel.\nGonorrhea: A sexually transmitted infection that can lead to pelvic inflammatory\ndisease, infertility, and arthritis.\nGroup B Streptococcus (GBS): A type of bacteria that many people carry normally and\ncan be passed to the fetus at the time of delivery?",
        "answer": "GBS can cause serious infection in\nsome newborns"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is GBS can cause serious infection in\nsome newborns?",
        "answer": "Antibiotics are given during labor to women who carry the bacteria to\nprevent newborn infection.\nHepatitis B: An infection caused by a virus that can be spread through blood, semen, or\nother body fluid infected with the virus.\nHepatitis C: An infection caused by a virus that can be spread through infected blood.\nHuman Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV): A virus that attacks certain cells of the body\u2019s\nimmune system"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Antibiotics are given during labor to women who carry the bacteria to\nprevent newborn infection.\nHepatitis B: An infection caused by a virus that can be spread through blood, semen, or\nother body fluid infected with the virus.\nHepatitis C: An infection caused by a virus that can be spread through infected blood.\nHuman Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV): A virus that attacks certain cells of the body\u2019s\nimmune system?",
        "answer": "If left untreated, HIV can cause acquired immunodeficiency syndrome\n(AIDS).\nImmune: Protected against infectious disease.\nIntravenous (IV) Line: A tube inserted into a vein and used to deliver medication or\nfluids.\nMeasles\u2013Mumps\u2013Rubella (MMR) Vaccine: A shot given to protect against measles,\nmumps, and rubella"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If left untreated, HIV can cause acquired immunodeficiency syndrome\n(AIDS).\nImmune: Protected against infectious disease.\nIntravenous (IV) Line: A tube inserted into a vein and used to deliver medication or\nfluids.\nMeasles\u2013Mumps\u2013Rubella (MMR) Vaccine: A shot given to protect against measles,\nmumps, and rubella?",
        "answer": "The shot contains live viruses that have been changed to not cause\ndisease"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The shot contains live viruses that have been changed to not cause\ndisease?",
        "answer": "The shot is not recommended for pregnant women.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with medical and surgical training and\neducation in the female reproductive system.\nPreeclampsia:\u00a0[pre-ee-KLAMP-see-uh]: A disorder during pregnancy or after childbirth\nthat causes high blood pressure and other signs of organ injury"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The shot is not recommended for pregnant women.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with medical and surgical training and\neducation in the female reproductive system.\nPreeclampsia:\u00a0[pre-ee-KLAMP-see-uh]: A disorder during pregnancy or after childbirth\nthat causes high blood pressure and other signs of organ injury?",
        "answer": "These signs include an\nabnormal amount of protein in the urine, a low number of platelets, abnormal kidney or\nliver function, pain over the upper abdomen, fluid in the lungs, a severe headache, or\nvision changes.\nRectum: The last part of the digestive tract.\nRh Factor:\u00a0A protein that can be found on the surface of red blood cells and makes up\npart of a person\u2019s blood type.\nRubella:\u00a0A virus that can be passed to the fetus if you become infected during\npregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These signs include an\nabnormal amount of protein in the urine, a low number of platelets, abnormal kidney or\nliver function, pain over the upper abdomen, fluid in the lungs, a severe headache, or\nvision changes.\nRectum: The last part of the digestive tract.\nRh Factor:\u00a0A protein that can be found on the surface of red blood cells and makes up\npart of a person\u2019s blood type.\nRubella:\u00a0A virus that can be passed to the fetus if you become infected during\npregnancy?",
        "answer": "The virus can cause miscarriage or severe birth defects.\nSexually Transmitted Infections (STIs):\u00a0Infections that are spread by sexual contact.\nInfections include chlamydia, gonorrhea, human papillomavirus (HPV), herpes, syphilis,\nand human immunodeficiency virus (HIV, the cause of acquired immunodeficiency\nsyndrome [AIDS]).\nStillbirth: Birth of a dead fetus.\nSyphilis:\u00a0A sexually transmitted infection (STI) that is caused by an organism called\nTreponema pallidum"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The virus can cause miscarriage or severe birth defects.\nSexually Transmitted Infections (STIs):\u00a0Infections that are spread by sexual contact.\nInfections include chlamydia, gonorrhea, human papillomavirus (HPV), herpes, syphilis,\nand human immunodeficiency virus (HIV, the cause of acquired immunodeficiency\nsyndrome [AIDS]).\nStillbirth: Birth of a dead fetus.\nSyphilis:\u00a0A sexually transmitted infection (STI) that is caused by an organism called\nTreponema pallidum?",
        "answer": "This infection may cause major health problems or death in its\nlater stages.\nTrimester: A time period of 3 months"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This infection may cause major health problems or death in its\nlater stages.\nTrimester: A time period of 3 months?",
        "answer": "There are three trimesters in pregnancy: the first\ntrimester, second trimester, and third trimester.\nTuberculosis [tu-buhr-kyuh-LOH-suhs] (TB): A disease that affects the lungs and other\norgans in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There are three trimesters in pregnancy: the first\ntrimester, second trimester, and third trimester.\nTuberculosis [tu-buhr-kyuh-LOH-suhs] (TB): A disease that affects the lungs and other\norgans in the body?",
        "answer": "TB is caused by bacteria.\nUrinary Tract Infection (UTI): An infection in any part of the urinary system, including the\nkidneys, bladder, or urethra.\nVagina: A tube-like structure surrounded by muscles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is TB is caused by bacteria.\nUrinary Tract Infection (UTI): An infection in any part of the urinary system, including the\nkidneys, bladder, or urethra.\nVagina: A tube-like structure surrounded by muscles?",
        "answer": "The vagina leads from the uterus\nto the outside of the body.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ133\nLast updated: April 2024\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nLast reviewed: August 2023\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The vagina leads from the uterus\nto the outside of the body.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ133\nLast updated: April 2024\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nLast reviewed: August 2023\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nThe Top 6 Pregnancy Questions I Hear\nFrom First-Time Moms\nAn ob-gyn discusses exercise, coffee, sleep positions, and more.\nDr"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nThe Top 6 Pregnancy Questions I Hear\nFrom First-Time Moms\nAn ob-gyn discusses exercise, coffee, sleep positions, and more.\nDr?",
        "answer": "Anne Srisuro\nFirst-time moms usually have a long list of questions"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Anne Srisuro\nFirst-time moms usually have a long list of questions?",
        "answer": "They want to do\neverything they can to protect their pregnancy, and there is a lot to think about.\nExpert View\n\ue921\nEach week can come with new symptoms, confusing advice from friends and\nfamily, and potential reasons to worry.\nAs an ob-gyn, here are the questions I most often hear from patients\u2014and the\nanswers that can help them have a healthy pregnancy.\n1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They want to do\neverything they can to protect their pregnancy, and there is a lot to think about.\nExpert View\n\ue921\nEach week can come with new symptoms, confusing advice from friends and\nfamily, and potential reasons to worry.\nAs an ob-gyn, here are the questions I most often hear from patients\u2014and the\nanswers that can help them have a healthy pregnancy.\n1?",
        "answer": "Are there any foods I should avoid during pregnancy?\nThis is the number one question I get"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Are there any foods I should avoid during pregnancy?\nThis is the number one question I get?",
        "answer": "There are wonderful resources online that\ncover healthy eating (visit Nutrition During Pregnancy, for one)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There are wonderful resources online that\ncover healthy eating (visit Nutrition During Pregnancy, for one)?",
        "answer": "What it boils\ndown to is this: You don\u2019t want to eat something that might contain bacteria\u00a0that\ncould make you sick"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is What it boils\ndown to is this: You don\u2019t want to eat something that might contain bacteria\u00a0that\ncould make you sick?",
        "answer": "Pregnant women are more likely to get very sick from\nbacteria in food, which can be dangerous for you and your pregnancy.\nRisky foods include raw or undercooked meat, fish, and eggs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Pregnant women are more likely to get very sick from\nbacteria in food, which can be dangerous for you and your pregnancy.\nRisky foods include raw or undercooked meat, fish, and eggs?",
        "answer": "To avoid\nproblems, cook food thoroughly and wash your hands, knives, and cutting\nboards after handling raw meat or fish"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is To avoid\nproblems, cook food thoroughly and wash your hands, knives, and cutting\nboards after handling raw meat or fish?",
        "answer": "Avoid homemade mayonnaise and\ndressings that use raw eggs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Avoid homemade mayonnaise and\ndressings that use raw eggs?",
        "answer": "Cook scrambled eggs thoroughly.\nAvoid raw sprouts, including bean and alfalfa"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Cook scrambled eggs thoroughly.\nAvoid raw sprouts, including bean and alfalfa?",
        "answer": "The moist conditions they\u2019re\ngrown in are ideal for bacteria growth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The moist conditions they\u2019re\ngrown in are ideal for bacteria growth?",
        "answer": "Don\u2019t eat unpasteurized (raw) milk and\ncheeses, such as some feta, queso fresco, and blue cheeses"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Don\u2019t eat unpasteurized (raw) milk and\ncheeses, such as some feta, queso fresco, and blue cheeses?",
        "answer": "Deli meats and hot\ndogs should be thoroughly cooked or microwaved to kill any bacteria.\nCooked seafood is a good source of omega-3 fatty acids, an important nutrient\nfor your pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Deli meats and hot\ndogs should be thoroughly cooked or microwaved to kill any bacteria.\nCooked seafood is a good source of omega-3 fatty acids, an important nutrient\nfor your pregnancy?",
        "answer": "But certain fish should be avoided because they have high\nlevels of mercury"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But certain fish should be avoided because they have high\nlevels of mercury?",
        "answer": "Do not eat bigeye tuna, king mackerel, marlin, orange roughy,\nshark, swordfish, or tilefish"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Do not eat bigeye tuna, king mackerel, marlin, orange roughy,\nshark, swordfish, or tilefish?",
        "answer": "Limit white (albacore) tuna to 6 ounces or less a\nweek"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Limit white (albacore) tuna to 6 ounces or less a\nweek?",
        "answer": "Here\u2019s a list with safer options.\nAlso, fish caught in local rivers or lakes can be unsafe because of chemicals in\nthe water"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Here\u2019s a list with safer options.\nAlso, fish caught in local rivers or lakes can be unsafe because of chemicals in\nthe water?",
        "answer": "In my area, for example, there\u2019s mercury runoff from old gold mines.\nIt\u2019s best to avoid eating fish caught locally unless you can check local safety\ninformation"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In my area, for example, there\u2019s mercury runoff from old gold mines.\nIt\u2019s best to avoid eating fish caught locally unless you can check local safety\ninformation?",
        "answer": "Otherwise, eat no more than 6 ounces of it and avoid eating other\nfish that week.\n2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Otherwise, eat no more than 6 ounces of it and avoid eating other\nfish that week.\n2?",
        "answer": "Can I keep drinking coffee?\nThere has been research on whether caffeine increases the risk of miscarriage\nor preterm birth, but the results are unclear"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Can I keep drinking coffee?\nThere has been research on whether caffeine increases the risk of miscarriage\nor preterm birth, but the results are unclear?",
        "answer": "Most experts agree it\u2019s safe to drink\nabout one cup of coffee a day\u2014that\u2019s 12 ounces (200 milligrams) of caffeine.\nPay attention to tea, chocolate, soft drinks, and other caffeine sources when\nyou\u2019re calculating how much you\u2019re taking in.\n3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Most experts agree it\u2019s safe to drink\nabout one cup of coffee a day\u2014that\u2019s 12 ounces (200 milligrams) of caffeine.\nPay attention to tea, chocolate, soft drinks, and other caffeine sources when\nyou\u2019re calculating how much you\u2019re taking in.\n3?",
        "answer": "Can I keep exercising? Or can I start a new exercise\nroutine?\nIf you\u2019re already active, we encourage you to continue exercising"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Can I keep exercising? Or can I start a new exercise\nroutine?\nIf you\u2019re already active, we encourage you to continue exercising?",
        "answer": "We\nrecommend 30 minutes of moderate exercise most days of the week, for 150\nminutes total each week"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is We\nrecommend 30 minutes of moderate exercise most days of the week, for 150\nminutes total each week?",
        "answer": "Walking, swimming, and yoga are some of the safest\nexercises you can do while pregnant"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Walking, swimming, and yoga are some of the safest\nexercises you can do while pregnant?",
        "answer": "(Read Exercise During Pregnancy\u00a0to learn\nmore.) Just talk with your ob-gyn first, as there are some medical conditions\nthat may make exercise riskier.\nSome sports should be avoided, primarily if there\u2019s a risk of falling or impact to\nthe abdomen"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is (Read Exercise During Pregnancy\u00a0to learn\nmore.) Just talk with your ob-gyn first, as there are some medical conditions\nthat may make exercise riskier.\nSome sports should be avoided, primarily if there\u2019s a risk of falling or impact to\nthe abdomen?",
        "answer": "These sports include skiing, off-road cycling, and contact sports\nlike soccer or basketball"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These sports include skiing, off-road cycling, and contact sports\nlike soccer or basketball?",
        "answer": "Also avoid gymnastics, horseback riding, scuba diving,\nand skydiving"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also avoid gymnastics, horseback riding, scuba diving,\nand skydiving?",
        "answer": "And it\u2019s best to avoid activities where you are lying on your back\nfor more than 10 minutes.\nIf you haven\u2019t been active, talk about your plan with your ob-gyn"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is And it\u2019s best to avoid activities where you are lying on your back\nfor more than 10 minutes.\nIf you haven\u2019t been active, talk about your plan with your ob-gyn?",
        "answer": "Start out slow,\nwith 10 to 15 minutes of exercise, and add 5 minutes a week"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Start out slow,\nwith 10 to 15 minutes of exercise, and add 5 minutes a week?",
        "answer": "Walking may be\nthe easiest thing to do"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Walking may be\nthe easiest thing to do?",
        "answer": "When you work up to 30 minutes, walking can do\nwonders for your health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When you work up to 30 minutes, walking can do\nwonders for your health?",
        "answer": "I recommend patients add 30-second intervals of\nfaster walking once they\u2019ve worked up to it.\nA lot of my patients are runners who continue to run when they get pregnant.\nThe main thing is to listen to your body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is I recommend patients add 30-second intervals of\nfaster walking once they\u2019ve worked up to it.\nA lot of my patients are runners who continue to run when they get pregnant.\nThe main thing is to listen to your body?",
        "answer": "If it hurts or doesn\u2019t feel right, stop"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If it hurts or doesn\u2019t feel right, stop?",
        "answer": "One\npatient did half marathons, got pregnant, and continued training"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is One\npatient did half marathons, got pregnant, and continued training?",
        "answer": "Her growing\nbelly and pelvic pressure made running increasingly uncomfortable, so she cut\nback on the training"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Her growing\nbelly and pelvic pressure made running increasingly uncomfortable, so she cut\nback on the training?",
        "answer": "Give yourself permission to cut back or stop when\nnecessary.\n4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Give yourself permission to cut back or stop when\nnecessary.\n4?",
        "answer": "How much kicking should I feel? When should I be\nconcerned?\nI bring this up all the time with my patients because I know new moms get\nworried"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is How much kicking should I feel? When should I be\nconcerned?\nI bring this up all the time with my patients because I know new moms get\nworried?",
        "answer": "Most first-time moms won\u2019t feel any movement (kicking) until about 5\nmonths of pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Most first-time moms won\u2019t feel any movement (kicking) until about 5\nmonths of pregnancy?",
        "answer": "With a second pregnancy, you typically feel movement\nearlier because you\u2019re more familiar with what it feels like.\nOnce you start feeling the fetus move, you should feel something every day until\nabout 7 months.\nIf you start to feel less movement than what you think is normal, you can ask\nyour ob-gyn if they recommend kick counts"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is With a second pregnancy, you typically feel movement\nearlier because you\u2019re more familiar with what it feels like.\nOnce you start feeling the fetus move, you should feel something every day until\nabout 7 months.\nIf you start to feel less movement than what you think is normal, you can ask\nyour ob-gyn if they recommend kick counts?",
        "answer": "This is a test where you time how\nlong it takes for you to feel 10 movements"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is a test where you time how\nlong it takes for you to feel 10 movements?",
        "answer": "Do the counts after your biggest\nmeal of the day, because that\u2019s typically when there is the most movement.\nIf you haven\u2019t felt 10 kicks within 2 hours, call your ob-gyn"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Do the counts after your biggest\nmeal of the day, because that\u2019s typically when there is the most movement.\nIf you haven\u2019t felt 10 kicks within 2 hours, call your ob-gyn?",
        "answer": "There may not be a\nproblem, but more tests may be needed to be sure.\n5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There may not be a\nproblem, but more tests may be needed to be sure.\n5?",
        "answer": "Do I really need to sleep on my left side? Can I sleep\non my belly?\nA lot of women read online that they should sleep on their left side throughout\ntheir entire pregnancy, but that\u2019s difficult and not necessary"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Do I really need to sleep on my left side? Can I sleep\non my belly?\nA lot of women read online that they should sleep on their left side throughout\ntheir entire pregnancy, but that\u2019s difficult and not necessary?",
        "answer": "You can sleep on\neither side, right or left.\nYou just want to avoid sleeping on your back later in pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can sleep on\neither side, right or left.\nYou just want to avoid sleeping on your back later in pregnancy?",
        "answer": "As your belly\ngrows, sleeping on your back puts more pressure on the blood vessels that\nsupply blood to your uterus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is As your belly\ngrows, sleeping on your back puts more pressure on the blood vessels that\nsupply blood to your uterus?",
        "answer": "If you find yourself sleeping on your back in your\nsecond or third trimester, don\u2019t panic"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you find yourself sleeping on your back in your\nsecond or third trimester, don\u2019t panic?",
        "answer": "Just turn to one side or the other.\nYou can sleep on your belly, but you\u2019ll get to a point where it\u2019s just not possible.\n6"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Just turn to one side or the other.\nYou can sleep on your belly, but you\u2019ll get to a point where it\u2019s just not possible.\n6?",
        "answer": "Is it normal to be short of breath?\nYes, it\u2019s perfectly normal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Is it normal to be short of breath?\nYes, it\u2019s perfectly normal?",
        "answer": "You may find you can go up a flight of stairs with very\nlittle effort, but you are short of breath"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may find you can go up a flight of stairs with very\nlittle effort, but you are short of breath?",
        "answer": "Shortness of breath can start early in\npregnancy\u2014it has to do with how pregnancy hormones affect the lungs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Shortness of breath can start early in\npregnancy\u2014it has to do with how pregnancy hormones affect the lungs?",
        "answer": "But if\nyou have shortness of breath along with chest pain, a cough, or heart\npalpitations, if you\u2019re feeling faint, or if there\u2019s a major change in your breathing,\nthen you need to contact your ob-gyn.\nOf course, you can call your ob-gyn at any time\u2014whenever you have any\nquestions or concerns"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But if\nyou have shortness of breath along with chest pain, a cough, or heart\npalpitations, if you\u2019re feeling faint, or if there\u2019s a major change in your breathing,\nthen you need to contact your ob-gyn.\nOf course, you can call your ob-gyn at any time\u2014whenever you have any\nquestions or concerns?",
        "answer": "We are always here to help.\nPublished: April 2022\nLast reviewed: February 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is We are always here to help.\nPublished: April 2022\nLast reviewed: February 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved.\nRead copyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved.\nRead copyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It\ndoes not explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It\ndoes not explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the\nadvice of a physician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the\nadvice of a physician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nAbout the Author\nDr"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nAbout the Author\nDr?",
        "answer": "Anne Srisuro\nDr"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Anne Srisuro\nDr?",
        "answer": "Srisuro is an obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-\ngyn) in Sacramento, California"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Srisuro is an obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-\ngyn) in Sacramento, California?",
        "answer": "She is a Fellow of\nthe American College of Obstetricians and\nGynecologists.\nTobacco, Alcohol, Drugs, and Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nDuring pregnancy, women should not use tobacco, alcohol, marijuana, illegal drugs, or\nprescription medications for nonmedical reasons"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is She is a Fellow of\nthe American College of Obstetricians and\nGynecologists.\nTobacco, Alcohol, Drugs, and Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nDuring pregnancy, women should not use tobacco, alcohol, marijuana, illegal drugs, or\nprescription medications for nonmedical reasons?",
        "answer": "Avoiding these substances and\ngetting regular prenatal care  are important to having a healthy pregnancy and a healthy\nbaby"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Avoiding these substances and\ngetting regular prenatal care  are important to having a healthy pregnancy and a healthy\nbaby?",
        "answer": "Counseling and treatment are available if you have hard time quitting unhealthy\nsubstances on your own.\nWhen a woman smokes cigarettes during pregnancy, her fetus  is exposed to many\nharmful chemicals"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Counseling and treatment are available if you have hard time quitting unhealthy\nsubstances on your own.\nWhen a woman smokes cigarettes during pregnancy, her fetus  is exposed to many\nharmful chemicals?",
        "answer": "Nicotine is one of 4,000 chemicals that can pass from a pregnant\nwoman to her fetus.\nNicotine damages a fetus\u2019s brain and lungs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Nicotine is one of 4,000 chemicals that can pass from a pregnant\nwoman to her fetus.\nNicotine damages a fetus\u2019s brain and lungs?",
        "answer": "This damage is permanent"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This damage is permanent?",
        "answer": "Nicotine also\ncauses blood vessels to narrow, so less oxygen and fewer nutrients  reach the fetus.\nSmoking during pregnancy increases the risk of preterm  birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Nicotine also\ncauses blood vessels to narrow, so less oxygen and fewer nutrients  reach the fetus.\nSmoking during pregnancy increases the risk of preterm  birth?",
        "answer": "Babies that are born too\nearly may not be fully developed"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Babies that are born too\nearly may not be fully developed?",
        "answer": "They may be born with serious health problems"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They may be born with serious health problems?",
        "answer": "Some\nFAQs\nWhat substances should I avoid during pregnancy?\nHow does nicotine affect pregnancy?\nWhat problems can happen if I smoke during pregnancy?\nhealth problems, like cerebral palsy , can last a lifetime"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some\nFAQs\nWhat substances should I avoid during pregnancy?\nHow does nicotine affect pregnancy?\nWhat problems can happen if I smoke during pregnancy?\nhealth problems, like cerebral palsy , can last a lifetime?",
        "answer": "Other problems, such as\nlearning disabilities, may appear later in childhood or even in adulthood.\nBabies born to women who smoked during pregnancy are at risk of other problems,\nincluding:\nIdeally, you should stop smoking before pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Other problems, such as\nlearning disabilities, may appear later in childhood or even in adulthood.\nBabies born to women who smoked during pregnancy are at risk of other problems,\nincluding:\nIdeally, you should stop smoking before pregnancy?",
        "answer": "But stopping smoking during\npregnancy is better than not stopping at all"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But stopping smoking during\npregnancy is better than not stopping at all?",
        "answer": "If you are smoking when you find out you\nare pregnant, you should stop"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are smoking when you find out you\nare pregnant, you should stop?",
        "answer": "See the Resources section for how to get help with\nquitting.\nYes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is See the Resources section for how to get help with\nquitting.\nYes?",
        "answer": "Secondhand smoke is other people\u2019s smoke that you inhale"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Secondhand smoke is other people\u2019s smoke that you inhale?",
        "answer": "Breathing secondhand\nsmoke during pregnancy increases the risk of having a low-birth-weight baby"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Breathing secondhand\nsmoke during pregnancy increases the risk of having a low-birth-weight baby?",
        "answer": "Also,\nbabies who are exposed to secondhand smoke have an increased risk of SIDS"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also,\nbabies who are exposed to secondhand smoke have an increased risk of SIDS?",
        "answer": "They are\nmore likely to have asthma attacks and ear infections"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They are\nmore likely to have asthma attacks and ear infections?",
        "answer": "Take steps to avoid secondhand\nsmoke at home and work.\nE-cigarettes are powered by a battery"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Take steps to avoid secondhand\nsmoke at home and work.\nE-cigarettes are powered by a battery?",
        "answer": "They contain nicotine, plus flavoring and a\npropellant that may not be safe for you or your fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They contain nicotine, plus flavoring and a\npropellant that may not be safe for you or your fetus?",
        "answer": "Avoid e-cigarettes\u2014or \u201cvaping\u201d\u2014\nduring pregnancy.\nHow else can my baby be affected if I smoke during pregnancy?\nLow birth weight\n\u2022\nBirth defects  such as cleft lip (a split in the upper lip)\n\u2022\nHigher rates of colic (uncontrollable crying and irritability)\n\u2022\nSudden infant death syndrome (SIDS)\n\u2022\nChildhood asthma and obesity\n\u2022\nWhen should I stop smoking?\nIs secondhand smoke harmful during pregnancy?\nCan e-cigarettes be used during pregnancy?\nCan smokeless tobacco be used during pregnancy?\nSome people prefer to chew tobacco rather than smoke it"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Avoid e-cigarettes\u2014or \u201cvaping\u201d\u2014\nduring pregnancy.\nHow else can my baby be affected if I smoke during pregnancy?\nLow birth weight\n\u2022\nBirth defects  such as cleft lip (a split in the upper lip)\n\u2022\nHigher rates of colic (uncontrollable crying and irritability)\n\u2022\nSudden infant death syndrome (SIDS)\n\u2022\nChildhood asthma and obesity\n\u2022\nWhen should I stop smoking?\nIs secondhand smoke harmful during pregnancy?\nCan e-cigarettes be used during pregnancy?\nCan smokeless tobacco be used during pregnancy?\nSome people prefer to chew tobacco rather than smoke it?",
        "answer": "The products used are called\nsmokeless tobacco"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The products used are called\nsmokeless tobacco?",
        "answer": "Smokeless tobacco also contains nicotine that can be passed to a\nfetus during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Smokeless tobacco also contains nicotine that can be passed to a\nfetus during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "These products also should be avoided.\nAlcohol can interfere with the normal growth of a fetus and cause birth defects"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These products also should be avoided.\nAlcohol can interfere with the normal growth of a fetus and cause birth defects?",
        "answer": "When a\nwoman drinks during pregnancy, her fetus can develop lifelong problems"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When a\nwoman drinks during pregnancy, her fetus can develop lifelong problems?",
        "answer": "It is safest not\nto drink at all while you are pregnant.\nFetal alcohol syndrome (FAS)  is the most severe disorder that can be caused by\ndrinking during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is safest not\nto drink at all while you are pregnant.\nFetal alcohol syndrome (FAS)  is the most severe disorder that can be caused by\ndrinking during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "FAS can cause:\nFAS is most likely to occur in infants whose mothers drink heavily throughout\npregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is FAS can cause:\nFAS is most likely to occur in infants whose mothers drink heavily throughout\npregnancy?",
        "answer": "But alcohol-related problems also can occur with lesser amounts of alcohol\nuse.\nIf it is hard for you to stop drinking, help is available (see the Resources section)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But alcohol-related problems also can occur with lesser amounts of alcohol\nuse.\nIf it is hard for you to stop drinking, help is available (see the Resources section)?",
        "answer": "Talk\nwith your obstetrician-gynecologist (ob-gyn)  or other obstetric care provider  about\nyour drinking habits"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Talk\nwith your obstetrician-gynecologist (ob-gyn)  or other obstetric care provider  about\nyour drinking habits?",
        "answer": "If you are dependent on alcohol, you may need specialized\ncounseling and medical care.\nMarijuana used during pregnancy is associated with attention and behavioral problems\nin children"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are dependent on alcohol, you may need specialized\ncounseling and medical care.\nMarijuana used during pregnancy is associated with attention and behavioral problems\nin children?",
        "answer": "Some studies suggest that marijuana use may increase the risk of stillbirth\nand the risk that babies will be smaller than babies who are not exposed to marijuana\nCan I drink any alcohol during pregnancy?\nWhat is fetal alcohol syndrome?\nGrowth problems\n\u2022\nMental disability\n\u2022\nBehavioral problems\n\u2022\nAbnormal facial features\n\u2022\nWhere can I get help to stop drinking?\nWhat effects does marijuana have during pregnancy?\nbefore birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some studies suggest that marijuana use may increase the risk of stillbirth\nand the risk that babies will be smaller than babies who are not exposed to marijuana\nCan I drink any alcohol during pregnancy?\nWhat is fetal alcohol syndrome?\nGrowth problems\n\u2022\nMental disability\n\u2022\nBehavioral problems\n\u2022\nAbnormal facial features\n\u2022\nWhere can I get help to stop drinking?\nWhat effects does marijuana have during pregnancy?\nbefore birth?",
        "answer": "For these reasons, you should not use marijuana in any form during\npregnancy.\nThe American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (ACOG) recommends that\npregnant women and those planning to get pregnant stop using medical marijuana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For these reasons, you should not use marijuana in any form during\npregnancy.\nThe American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (ACOG) recommends that\npregnant women and those planning to get pregnant stop using medical marijuana?",
        "answer": "You\nand your ob-gyn or other obstetric care provider can discuss other treatments that will\nbe safer for your fetus.\nDrug use can mean using illegal drugs, such as heroin, cocaine, and methamphetamines\n(\u201cmeth\u201d)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You\nand your ob-gyn or other obstetric care provider can discuss other treatments that will\nbe safer for your fetus.\nDrug use can mean using illegal drugs, such as heroin, cocaine, and methamphetamines\n(\u201cmeth\u201d)?",
        "answer": "It also can mean using prescription medication in a way your doctor did not\norder, such as taking pain medication for the \u201chigh\u201d even when you no longer have pain.\nYour ob-gyn or other obstetric care provider may ask about your use of drugs\nthroughout your pregnancy.\nThe early stage of pregnancy is the time when main body parts of the fetus form"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It also can mean using prescription medication in a way your doctor did not\norder, such as taking pain medication for the \u201chigh\u201d even when you no longer have pain.\nYour ob-gyn or other obstetric care provider may ask about your use of drugs\nthroughout your pregnancy.\nThe early stage of pregnancy is the time when main body parts of the fetus form?",
        "answer": "Using\nillegal drugs or misusing prescription medication early in pregnancy can cause birth\ndefects and miscarriage .\nDuring the later weeks of pregnancy, illegal drug use can interfere with the growth of the\nfetus and cause preterm birth and fetal death"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Using\nillegal drugs or misusing prescription medication early in pregnancy can cause birth\ndefects and miscarriage .\nDuring the later weeks of pregnancy, illegal drug use can interfere with the growth of the\nfetus and cause preterm birth and fetal death?",
        "answer": "Babies born to women who used illegal\ndrugs during pregnancy may need specialized care after birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Babies born to women who used illegal\ndrugs during pregnancy may need specialized care after birth?",
        "answer": "These babies have an\nincreased risk of long-term medical and behavioral problems.\nOpioids  are a type of medication that relieves pain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These babies have an\nincreased risk of long-term medical and behavioral problems.\nOpioids  are a type of medication that relieves pain?",
        "answer": "They also release chemicals in the\nbrain that have a calming effect"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They also release chemicals in the\nbrain that have a calming effect?",
        "answer": "Doctors may prescribe opioids for people who have\nI have a prescription for medical marijuana \u2014 is it safe to use it during\npregnancy?\nWhat should I know about drug use during pregnancy?\nHow do drugs affect the fetus early in pregnancy?\nHow do drugs affect the fetus later in pregnancy?\nWhat are opioids?\nhad surgery, dental work, or an injury"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Doctors may prescribe opioids for people who have\nI have a prescription for medical marijuana \u2014 is it safe to use it during\npregnancy?\nWhat should I know about drug use during pregnancy?\nHow do drugs affect the fetus early in pregnancy?\nHow do drugs affect the fetus later in pregnancy?\nWhat are opioids?\nhad surgery, dental work, or an injury?",
        "answer": "Prescribed opioids include oxycodone,\nhydromorphone, hydrocodone, fentanyl, and codeine.\nWhen taken under a doctor\u2019s care, opioids are safe for both you and your fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Prescribed opioids include oxycodone,\nhydromorphone, hydrocodone, fentanyl, and codeine.\nWhen taken under a doctor\u2019s care, opioids are safe for both you and your fetus?",
        "answer": "If you\nare prescribed an opioid before or during pregnancy, you and your ob-gyn or other\nobstetric care provider should discuss the risks and benefits of this treatment"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you\nare prescribed an opioid before or during pregnancy, you and your ob-gyn or other\nobstetric care provider should discuss the risks and benefits of this treatment?",
        "answer": "It is\nimportant to take the medication only as prescribed.\nMost people who use a prescription opioid have no trouble stopping their use, but some\npeople develop an addiction"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is\nimportant to take the medication only as prescribed.\nMost people who use a prescription opioid have no trouble stopping their use, but some\npeople develop an addiction?",
        "answer": "This is called opioid use disorder"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is called opioid use disorder?",
        "answer": "People with this\ndisorder may look for other ways to get the drug when their prescription runs out"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is People with this\ndisorder may look for other ways to get the drug when their prescription runs out?",
        "answer": "They\nmay go from doctor to doctor to have new prescriptions written for them, or they may\nuse illegal opioids.\nMisusing opioids during pregnancy can increase the risk of serious complications ,\nincluding:\nThe best treatment for opioid use disorder during pregnancy is opioid replacement\nmedication, behavioral therapy, and counseling"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They\nmay go from doctor to doctor to have new prescriptions written for them, or they may\nuse illegal opioids.\nMisusing opioids during pregnancy can increase the risk of serious complications ,\nincluding:\nThe best treatment for opioid use disorder during pregnancy is opioid replacement\nmedication, behavioral therapy, and counseling?",
        "answer": "The medications that are given are long-\nacting opioids"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The medications that are given are long-\nacting opioids?",
        "answer": "This means that they stay active in the body for a long time"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This means that they stay active in the body for a long time?",
        "answer": "These\nopioids, called methadone and buprenorphine, reduce cravings but do not cause the\npleasant feelings that other opioids cause.\nIs it safe to take prescription opioids during pregnancy?\nWhat is opioid use disorder?\nWhat problems can opioid use disorder cause during pregnancy?\nPlacenta problems\n\u2022\nFetal growth problems\n\u2022\nPreterm birth\n\u2022\nStillbirth\n\u2022\nWhat is the best treatment for opioid use disorder?\nYes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These\nopioids, called methadone and buprenorphine, reduce cravings but do not cause the\npleasant feelings that other opioids cause.\nIs it safe to take prescription opioids during pregnancy?\nWhat is opioid use disorder?\nWhat problems can opioid use disorder cause during pregnancy?\nPlacenta problems\n\u2022\nFetal growth problems\n\u2022\nPreterm birth\n\u2022\nStillbirth\n\u2022\nWhat is the best treatment for opioid use disorder?\nYes?",
        "answer": "Treatment with either methadone or buprenorphine makes it more likely that the\nfetus will grow normally and not be born too early"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Treatment with either methadone or buprenorphine makes it more likely that the\nfetus will grow normally and not be born too early?",
        "answer": "Based on many years of research,\nneither medicine has been found to cause birth defects.\nSome babies born to women taking opioids, including methadone or buprenorphine\ntaken for treatment of opioid use disorder, can have temporary withdrawal symptoms.\nThis is called neonatal abstinence syndrome (NAS)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Based on many years of research,\nneither medicine has been found to cause birth defects.\nSome babies born to women taking opioids, including methadone or buprenorphine\ntaken for treatment of opioid use disorder, can have temporary withdrawal symptoms.\nThis is called neonatal abstinence syndrome (NAS)?",
        "answer": "Symptoms of NAS can include\nshaking and tremors, poor feeding or sucking, crying, fever, diarrhea, vomiting, and sleep\nproblems.\nNot all babies will go through withdrawal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Symptoms of NAS can include\nshaking and tremors, poor feeding or sucking, crying, fever, diarrhea, vomiting, and sleep\nproblems.\nNot all babies will go through withdrawal?",
        "answer": "For those that do, some things can be done to\nmake babies with NAS feel better, including swaddling, breastfeeding, and skin-to-skin\ncontact"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is For those that do, some things can be done to\nmake babies with NAS feel better, including swaddling, breastfeeding, and skin-to-skin\ncontact?",
        "answer": "Some babies also may be given medication"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some babies also may be given medication?",
        "answer": "A baby may need to stay in the\nneonatal intensive care unit (NICU)  for a few days or weeks while taking the\nmedication"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A baby may need to stay in the\nneonatal intensive care unit (NICU)  for a few days or weeks while taking the\nmedication?",
        "answer": "NAS causes no known lasting physical or intellectual problems for babies.\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth\nCerebral Palsy: A disorder of the nervous system that affects movement, posture, and\ncoordination"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is NAS causes no known lasting physical or intellectual problems for babies.\nBirth Defects: Physical problems that are present at birth\nCerebral Palsy: A disorder of the nervous system that affects movement, posture, and\ncoordination?",
        "answer": "This disorder is present at birth.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This disorder is present at birth.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition?",
        "answer": "An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu?",
        "answer": "A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy?",
        "answer": "An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nFetal Alcohol Syndrome (FAS): The most severe disorder resulting from alcohol use\nduring pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nFetal Alcohol Syndrome (FAS): The most severe disorder resulting from alcohol use\nduring pregnancy?",
        "answer": "FAS can cause abnormalities in brain development, physical growth,\nand facial features of a baby or child.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nIs it safe to take methadone or buprenorphine during pregnancy?\nWhat is neonatal abstinence syndrome?\nWhat is the treatment for a baby\u2019s withdrawal symptoms?\nGlossary\nLow Birth Weight: Weighing less than 5 \u00bd pounds (2,500 grams) at birth.\nMiscarriage: Loss of a pregnancy that is in the uterus.\nNeonatal Abstinence Syndrome (NAS): A group of problems that happen to a newborn\nwho was exposed to addictive substances before birth"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is FAS can cause abnormalities in brain development, physical growth,\nand facial features of a baby or child.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nIs it safe to take methadone or buprenorphine during pregnancy?\nWhat is neonatal abstinence syndrome?\nWhat is the treatment for a baby\u2019s withdrawal symptoms?\nGlossary\nLow Birth Weight: Weighing less than 5 \u00bd pounds (2,500 grams) at birth.\nMiscarriage: Loss of a pregnancy that is in the uterus.\nNeonatal Abstinence Syndrome (NAS): A group of problems that happen to a newborn\nwho was exposed to addictive substances before birth?",
        "answer": "A common cause of NAS is\nopioid use disorder.\nNeonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU): A special part of a hospital in which sick newborns\nreceive medical care.\nNutrients: Nourishing substances found through food, such as vitamins and minerals.\nObstetric Care Provider: A health care professional who cares for a woman during\npregnancy, labor, and delivery"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A common cause of NAS is\nopioid use disorder.\nNeonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU): A special part of a hospital in which sick newborns\nreceive medical care.\nNutrients: Nourishing substances found through food, such as vitamins and minerals.\nObstetric Care Provider: A health care professional who cares for a woman during\npregnancy, labor, and delivery?",
        "answer": "These professionals include obstetrician\u2013gynecologists\n(ob-gyns), certified nurse\u2013midwives (CNMs), maternal\u2013 fetal medicine specialists\n(MFMs), and family practice doctors with experience in maternal care.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOpioid: Drugs that decreases the ability to feel pain.\nOpioid Use Disorder: A treatable disease that can be caused by frequent opioid use"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These professionals include obstetrician\u2013gynecologists\n(ob-gyns), certified nurse\u2013midwives (CNMs), maternal\u2013 fetal medicine specialists\n(MFMs), and family practice doctors with experience in maternal care.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOpioid: Drugs that decreases the ability to feel pain.\nOpioid Use Disorder: A treatable disease that can be caused by frequent opioid use?",
        "answer": "It is\nsometimes called opioid addiction.\nOxygen: An element that we breathe in to sustain life.\nPrenatal Care: A program of care for a pregnant woman before the birth of her baby.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nStillbirth: Birth of a dead fetus.\nSudden Infant Death Syndrome (SIDS): The unexpected death of an infant in which the\ncause is unknown.\nResources\nCounseling and treatment are available to help you stop using unhealthy\nsubstances"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is\nsometimes called opioid addiction.\nOxygen: An element that we breathe in to sustain life.\nPrenatal Care: A program of care for a pregnant woman before the birth of her baby.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nStillbirth: Birth of a dead fetus.\nSudden Infant Death Syndrome (SIDS): The unexpected death of an infant in which the\ncause is unknown.\nResources\nCounseling and treatment are available to help you stop using unhealthy\nsubstances?",
        "answer": "These organizations offer support and guidance:\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ170\nPublished: June 2020\nLast reviewed: December 2021\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These organizations offer support and guidance:\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ170\nPublished: June 2020\nLast reviewed: December 2021\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nQuit Smoking Hotline\n1-800-QUIT-NOW (784-8669)\n\u2022\nAmerican Lung Association\n1-800-586-4872\nhttp://www.lung.org\n\u2022\nAlcoholics Anonymous\n212-870-3400\nhttp://www.aa.org\n\u2022\nNarcotics Anonymous\n818-773-9999\nhttp://www.na.org\n\u2022\nSubstance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA)\n24-hour Treatment Referral Line: 1-800-662-HELP (4357)\nhttp://www.samhsa.gov\n\u2022\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nQuit Smoking Hotline\n1-800-QUIT-NOW (784-8669)\n\u2022\nAmerican Lung Association\n1-800-586-4872\nhttp://www.lung.org\n\u2022\nAlcoholics Anonymous\n212-870-3400\nhttp://www.aa.org\n\u2022\nNarcotics Anonymous\n818-773-9999\nhttp://www.na.org\n\u2022\nSubstance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA)\n24-hour Treatment Referral Line: 1-800-662-HELP (4357)\nhttp://www.samhsa.gov\n\u2022\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nTravel During Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nOverview\nIn most cases, pregnant women can travel safely until close to their due dates"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nTravel During Pregnancy\nFrequently Asked Questions\nOverview\nIn most cases, pregnant women can travel safely until close to their due dates?",
        "answer": "But\ntravel may not be recommended if you have pregnancy complications"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But\ntravel may not be recommended if you have pregnancy complications?",
        "answer": "If you are\nplanning a trip, talk with your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are\nplanning a trip, talk with your obstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)?",
        "answer": "And no matter how\nyou choose to travel, think ahead about your comfort and safety.\nThe best time to travel is mid-pregnancy (14 to 28 weeks)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is And no matter how\nyou choose to travel, think ahead about your comfort and safety.\nThe best time to travel is mid-pregnancy (14 to 28 weeks)?",
        "answer": "During these weeks, your\nenergy has returned, morning sickness is improved or gone, and you are still able to get\naround easily"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is During these weeks, your\nenergy has returned, morning sickness is improved or gone, and you are still able to get\naround easily?",
        "answer": "After 28 weeks, it may be harder to move around or sit for a long time.\nPreparing for a Trip\nYes, talk about your travel plans with your ob-gyn"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is After 28 weeks, it may be harder to move around or sit for a long time.\nPreparing for a Trip\nYes, talk about your travel plans with your ob-gyn?",
        "answer": "You can discuss whether it is safe for\nyou to travel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can discuss whether it is safe for\nyou to travel?",
        "answer": "Travel is not recommended if you have certain complications, including\nFAQs\nIs travel safe during pregnancy?\nWhen is the best time to travel during pregnancy?\nShould I talk with my ob-gyn before a trip?\npreeclampsia\n\u2022\nprelabor rupture of membranes (PROM)\n\u2022\nYes, you should have a prenatal check-up before you leave"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Travel is not recommended if you have certain complications, including\nFAQs\nIs travel safe during pregnancy?\nWhen is the best time to travel during pregnancy?\nShould I talk with my ob-gyn before a trip?\npreeclampsia\n\u2022\nprelabor rupture of membranes (PROM)\n\u2022\nYes, you should have a prenatal check-up before you leave?",
        "answer": "At this visit, your ob-gyn can\nconfirm your due date"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is At this visit, your ob-gyn can\nconfirm your due date?",
        "answer": "You may also talk about whether you are up-to-date on\nvaccinations and symptoms to watch for while traveling.\nIf something goes wrong while you are away, your caregivers will need to know how far\nalong you are and any other important information about your pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may also talk about whether you are up-to-date on\nvaccinations and symptoms to watch for while traveling.\nIf something goes wrong while you are away, your caregivers will need to know how far\nalong you are and any other important information about your pregnancy?",
        "answer": "If you\u2019ll be\ngoing far from home, take a copy of your health record with you.\nYour ob-gyn may want to double-check that your vaccines are up to date, even if you\nreviewed them at an earlier prenatal visit"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you\u2019ll be\ngoing far from home, take a copy of your health record with you.\nYour ob-gyn may want to double-check that your vaccines are up to date, even if you\nreviewed them at an earlier prenatal visit?",
        "answer": "Also, you may need more vaccines depending\non where you are going.\nSome symptoms could signal a health problem"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also, you may need more vaccines depending\non where you are going.\nSome symptoms could signal a health problem?",
        "answer": "Go to a hospital or call emergency\nmedical services right away if you have any of the following:\npreterm  labor\n\u2022\nShould I have a check-up before a trip?\nWhy is it important to know my due date before traveling?\nWhy would my ob-gyn check my vaccinations before travel?\nWhat symptoms should I watch for while traveling?\nVaginal bleeding\n\u2022\nPelvic or abdominal pain or contractions\n\u2022\nRupture of the membranes (your \u201cwater breaks\u201d)\n\u2022\nSigns and symptoms of preeclampsia (headache that will not go away, seeing spots\nor other changes in eyesight, swelling of the face or hands)\n\u2022\nSevere vomiting or diarrhea\n\u2022\nSigns of deep vein thrombosis (DVT)  (read Preventing Deep Vein Thrombosis)\n\u2022\nWhat should I know about deep vein thrombosis and preventing blood clots?\nDVT is a condition in which a blood clot forms in the veins, usually in the leg"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Go to a hospital or call emergency\nmedical services right away if you have any of the following:\npreterm  labor\n\u2022\nShould I have a check-up before a trip?\nWhy is it important to know my due date before traveling?\nWhy would my ob-gyn check my vaccinations before travel?\nWhat symptoms should I watch for while traveling?\nVaginal bleeding\n\u2022\nPelvic or abdominal pain or contractions\n\u2022\nRupture of the membranes (your \u201cwater breaks\u201d)\n\u2022\nSigns and symptoms of preeclampsia (headache that will not go away, seeing spots\nor other changes in eyesight, swelling of the face or hands)\n\u2022\nSevere vomiting or diarrhea\n\u2022\nSigns of deep vein thrombosis (DVT)  (read Preventing Deep Vein Thrombosis)\n\u2022\nWhat should I know about deep vein thrombosis and preventing blood clots?\nDVT is a condition in which a blood clot forms in the veins, usually in the leg?",
        "answer": "DVT can\nlead to a dangerous condition called pulmonary embolism"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is DVT can\nlead to a dangerous condition called pulmonary embolism?",
        "answer": "This is when a blood clot\ntravels to the lungs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is when a blood clot\ntravels to the lungs?",
        "answer": "Research shows that any type of travel lasting 4 hours or more\u2014\nwhether by car, train, bus, or plane\u2014doubles the risk of DVT"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Research shows that any type of travel lasting 4 hours or more\u2014\nwhether by car, train, bus, or plane\u2014doubles the risk of DVT?",
        "answer": "Being pregnant is an extra\nrisk factor for DVT.\nIf you are planning a long trip, take the following steps to reduce your risk of DVT:\nSpecial stockings that compress the legs, either below the knee or full length, can be\nworn to help prevent blood clots from forming"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Being pregnant is an extra\nrisk factor for DVT.\nIf you are planning a long trip, take the following steps to reduce your risk of DVT:\nSpecial stockings that compress the legs, either below the knee or full length, can be\nworn to help prevent blood clots from forming?",
        "answer": "Talk with your ob-gyn before you try\nthese stockings"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Talk with your ob-gyn before you try\nthese stockings?",
        "answer": "Some people should not wear them (for example, those with diabetes\nmellitus  and other circulation problems)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some people should not wear them (for example, those with diabetes\nmellitus  and other circulation problems)?",
        "answer": "Also, compression stockings can increase the\nrisk of DVT if they are too tight or worn incorrectly.\nVisit your ob-gyn at least 4 to 6 weeks before a trip outside the United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also, compression stockings can increase the\nrisk of DVT if they are too tight or worn incorrectly.\nVisit your ob-gyn at least 4 to 6 weeks before a trip outside the United States?",
        "answer": "At this\nvisit you can go over your travel plans, get advice about specific health issues, and\ndiscuss vaccines that are recommended for the area you will be visiting.\nThis also gives you time to call your health insurance"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is At this\nvisit you can go over your travel plans, get advice about specific health issues, and\ndiscuss vaccines that are recommended for the area you will be visiting.\nThis also gives you time to call your health insurance?",
        "answer": "Ask if you are covered outside the\nUnited States"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Ask if you are covered outside the\nUnited States?",
        "answer": "If not, you may be able to buy travel health insurance.\nCarry a copy of your health record with you outside the country"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If not, you may be able to buy travel health insurance.\nCarry a copy of your health record with you outside the country?",
        "answer": "Also, before leaving\nhome, locate the nearest hospital or medical clinic in the place you are visiting.\nTraveling by Car, Plane, or Ship\nWhen taking a car trip, keep in mind the shortest route is often the best"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also, before leaving\nhome, locate the nearest hospital or medical clinic in the place you are visiting.\nTraveling by Car, Plane, or Ship\nWhen taking a car trip, keep in mind the shortest route is often the best?",
        "answer": "Make each\nday\u2019s drive as brief as possible"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Make each\nday\u2019s drive as brief as possible?",
        "answer": "Also follow these tips:\nDrink lots of fluids without caffeine.\n\u2022\nWear loose-fitting clothing.\n\u2022\nWalk and stretch at regular intervals.\n\u2022\nHow should I prepare for international travel?\nWhat are some ways to make car trips safer?\nRead Car Safety for Pregnant Women, Babies, and Children\u00a0for more advice.\nDuring a healthy pregnancy, occasional air travel is almost always safe"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also follow these tips:\nDrink lots of fluids without caffeine.\n\u2022\nWear loose-fitting clothing.\n\u2022\nWalk and stretch at regular intervals.\n\u2022\nHow should I prepare for international travel?\nWhat are some ways to make car trips safer?\nRead Car Safety for Pregnant Women, Babies, and Children\u00a0for more advice.\nDuring a healthy pregnancy, occasional air travel is almost always safe?",
        "answer": "Most airlines\nallow you to fly domestically until about 36 weeks of pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Most airlines\nallow you to fly domestically until about 36 weeks of pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Your ob-gyn can\nprovide proof of your due date if you need it.\nIf you are planning an international flight, the cut-off for traveling may be earlier"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your ob-gyn can\nprovide proof of your due date if you need it.\nIf you are planning an international flight, the cut-off for traveling may be earlier?",
        "answer": "Check\nwith your airline.\nAvoid flying if you have a medical or pregnancy condition that may be made worse by\nflying or could require emergency medical care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Check\nwith your airline.\nAvoid flying if you have a medical or pregnancy condition that may be made worse by\nflying or could require emergency medical care?",
        "answer": "Keep in mind that most common\npregnancy emergencies usually happen in the first and third trimesters .\nYes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Keep in mind that most common\npregnancy emergencies usually happen in the first and third trimesters .\nYes?",
        "answer": "Lower air pressure during a flight may slightly reduce the amount of oxygen  in your\nblood, but your body will adjust"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Lower air pressure during a flight may slightly reduce the amount of oxygen  in your\nblood, but your body will adjust?",
        "answer": "Radiation  exposure increases at higher altitudes, but\nthe level of exposure isn\u2019t a concern for pregnant women"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Radiation  exposure increases at higher altitudes, but\nthe level of exposure isn\u2019t a concern for pregnant women?",
        "answer": "If you are a frequent flier, talk\nwith your ob-gyn about how much flying is safe for you.\nWear your seat belt at all times"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are a frequent flier, talk\nwith your ob-gyn about how much flying is safe for you.\nWear your seat belt at all times?",
        "answer": "The belt should sit low on your hip bones, below your\nbelly.\n\u2022\nPlan to make frequent stops"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The belt should sit low on your hip bones, below your\nbelly.\n\u2022\nPlan to make frequent stops?",
        "answer": "Use these stops to move around and stretch your legs.\n\u2022\nWear comfortable shoes and clothing that is not too tight.\n\u2022\nWear a few layers of light clothing that can easily be added or removed.\n\u2022\nEat regular meals to boost your energy.\n\u2022\nDrink extra fluids"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Use these stops to move around and stretch your legs.\n\u2022\nWear comfortable shoes and clothing that is not too tight.\n\u2022\nWear a few layers of light clothing that can easily be added or removed.\n\u2022\nEat regular meals to boost your energy.\n\u2022\nDrink extra fluids?",
        "answer": "Take water with you"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Take water with you?",
        "answer": "You may need to pee more often\u2014don\u2019t hold it\ntoo long.\n\u2022\nIs air travel safe during pregnancy?\nWhen should I not fly?\nAre plane cabins safe for pregnant women?\nHow can I make plane travel more comfortable?\nBook an aisle seat if you can"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may need to pee more often\u2014don\u2019t hold it\ntoo long.\n\u2022\nIs air travel safe during pregnancy?\nWhen should I not fly?\nAre plane cabins safe for pregnant women?\nHow can I make plane travel more comfortable?\nBook an aisle seat if you can?",
        "answer": "This makes it easier to get up and stretch your legs\nduring a long flight.\n\u2022\nOne of the most common health problems for people taking a cruise is seasickness\n(also called motion sickness)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This makes it easier to get up and stretch your legs\nduring a long flight.\n\u2022\nOne of the most common health problems for people taking a cruise is seasickness\n(also called motion sickness)?",
        "answer": "Seasickness can cause nausea, dizziness, weakness,\nheadache, and vomiting.\nIf you have never taken a cruise, planning your first one while you are pregnant may not\nbe a good idea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Seasickness can cause nausea, dizziness, weakness,\nheadache, and vomiting.\nIf you have never taken a cruise, planning your first one while you are pregnant may not\nbe a good idea?",
        "answer": "But if seasickness is usually not a problem for you, traveling by sea\nduring pregnancy may not upset your stomach.\nYou may have heard about noroviruses, which affect the digestive system"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But if seasickness is usually not a problem for you, traveling by sea\nduring pregnancy may not upset your stomach.\nYou may have heard about noroviruses, which affect the digestive system?",
        "answer": "Noroviruses\nare very contagious and can spread quickly on ships.\nSymptoms include cramping, diarrhea, and vomiting"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Noroviruses\nare very contagious and can spread quickly on ships.\nSymptoms include cramping, diarrhea, and vomiting?",
        "answer": "You can get infected by eating\nfood, drinking liquids, or touching surfaces that are contaminated with the virus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can get infected by eating\nfood, drinking liquids, or touching surfaces that are contaminated with the virus?",
        "answer": "If you\nhave symptoms of norovirus while on a cruise, seek medical care right away.\nAvoid gas-producing carbonated drinks before or during your flight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you\nhave symptoms of norovirus while on a cruise, seek medical care right away.\nAvoid gas-producing carbonated drinks before or during your flight?",
        "answer": "Gas expands at\nhigh altitude and can cause discomfort"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Gas expands at\nhigh altitude and can cause discomfort?",
        "answer": "Drink water instead.\n\u2022\nWear your seat belt at all times"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Drink water instead.\n\u2022\nWear your seat belt at all times?",
        "answer": "Turbulence can happen without warning during air\ntravel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Turbulence can happen without warning during air\ntravel?",
        "answer": "The belt should sit low on your hip bones, below your belly.\n\u2022\nMove your feet, toes, and legs often"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The belt should sit low on your hip bones, below your belly.\n\u2022\nMove your feet, toes, and legs often?",
        "answer": "Get up and walk around a few times during your\nflight.\n\u2022\nWhat should I know about traveling by ship?\nHow should I plan to stay healthy on a cruise?\nPlan to wash your hands often with soap and water"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Get up and walk around a few times during your\nflight.\n\u2022\nWhat should I know about traveling by ship?\nHow should I plan to stay healthy on a cruise?\nPlan to wash your hands often with soap and water?",
        "answer": "Pack hand sanitizer that\ncontains at least 60 percent alcohol for those times when you won\u2019t be near a sink.\n\u2022\nBefore you leave, ask your ob-gyn about which medications are safe for you to take\nto calm seasickness, if needed.\n\u2022\nMake sure a doctor or nurse is on the ship and that your scheduled stops are places\nwith modern medical facilities in case you need medical attention.\n\u2022\nI've heard about stomach viruses on cruises"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Pack hand sanitizer that\ncontains at least 60 percent alcohol for those times when you won\u2019t be near a sink.\n\u2022\nBefore you leave, ask your ob-gyn about which medications are safe for you to take\nto calm seasickness, if needed.\n\u2022\nMake sure a doctor or nurse is on the ship and that your scheduled stops are places\nwith modern medical facilities in case you need medical attention.\n\u2022\nI've heard about stomach viruses on cruises?",
        "answer": "What should I know?\nBefore you book a cruise, you can check whether your ship has passed a health and\nsafety inspection conducted by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).\nThe CDC inspects cruise ships to prevent widespread virus outbreaks"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is What should I know?\nBefore you book a cruise, you can check whether your ship has passed a health and\nsafety inspection conducted by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).\nThe CDC inspects cruise ships to prevent widespread virus outbreaks?",
        "answer": "You can read\nthese reports on the CDC\u2019s Vessel Sanitation Program website\n(www.cdc.gov/nceh/vsp).\nPreventing Infections\nThe CDC has health notices and travel recommendations by country on its Travelers\u2019\nHealth website (wwwnc.cdc.gov/travel).\nYou can take steps to protect yourself and others from COVID-19 while you travel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can read\nthese reports on the CDC\u2019s Vessel Sanitation Program website\n(www.cdc.gov/nceh/vsp).\nPreventing Infections\nThe CDC has health notices and travel recommendations by country on its Travelers\u2019\nHealth website (wwwnc.cdc.gov/travel).\nYou can take steps to protect yourself and others from COVID-19 while you travel?",
        "answer": "Steps\nrecommended by the CDC include the following:\nRead all of the CDC recommendations at wwwnc.cdc.gov/travel/diseases/covid19"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Steps\nrecommended by the CDC include the following:\nRead all of the CDC recommendations at wwwnc.cdc.gov/travel/diseases/covid19?",
        "answer": "You\ncan also read about COVID-19 and pregnancy at www.acog.org/COVID-pregnancy.\nYou can get sick if you eat raw or undercooked food or drink local water in some\ncountries"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You\ncan also read about COVID-19 and pregnancy at www.acog.org/COVID-pregnancy.\nYou can get sick if you eat raw or undercooked food or drink local water in some\ncountries?",
        "answer": "Serious illnesses, such as hepatitis A  and listeriosis , can also be spread by\ncontaminated food and water"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Serious illnesses, such as hepatitis A  and listeriosis , can also be spread by\ncontaminated food and water?",
        "answer": "These diseases can cause severe complications during\npregnancy.\nSafe eating can help you avoid illness:\nHow can I check on the safety of my cruise ship?\nWhere can I learn about health concerns in other countries?\nWhat should I know about travel and COVID-19?\nGet up to date on COVID-19 vaccines before you travel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These diseases can cause severe complications during\npregnancy.\nSafe eating can help you avoid illness:\nHow can I check on the safety of my cruise ship?\nWhere can I learn about health concerns in other countries?\nWhat should I know about travel and COVID-19?\nGet up to date on COVID-19 vaccines before you travel?",
        "answer": "Vaccines help prevent serious\nillness caused by the virus.\n\u2022\nConsider wearing a mask in crowded indoor areas, such as in airports and other\ntransportation hubs.\n\u2022\nWhat should I know about food safety while I am traveling?\nTap water may not be safe in many middle- and low-income countries"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Vaccines help prevent serious\nillness caused by the virus.\n\u2022\nConsider wearing a mask in crowded indoor areas, such as in airports and other\ntransportation hubs.\n\u2022\nWhat should I know about food safety while I am traveling?\nTap water may not be safe in many middle- and low-income countries?",
        "answer": "If you are\ntraveling somewhere the tap water is not safe, follow these tips:\nGet more tips from the CDC at wwwnc.cdc.gov/travel/page/food-water-safety.\nZika  virus was first found in Central, North, and South America, but there have been\ncases of Zika virus infection throughout the world"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you are\ntraveling somewhere the tap water is not safe, follow these tips:\nGet more tips from the CDC at wwwnc.cdc.gov/travel/page/food-water-safety.\nZika  virus was first found in Central, North, and South America, but there have been\ncases of Zika virus infection throughout the world?",
        "answer": "The virus can spread\nZika virus infection generally causes no symptoms"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The virus can spread\nZika virus infection generally causes no symptoms?",
        "answer": "When it does cause symptoms, they\nmay be mild and include fever, rash, joint pain, and red and itchy eyes.\nIf you are infected with Zika virus during pregnancy, your baby is at risk of serious birth\ndefects, including microcephaly"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is When it does cause symptoms, they\nmay be mild and include fever, rash, joint pain, and red and itchy eyes.\nIf you are infected with Zika virus during pregnancy, your baby is at risk of serious birth\ndefects, including microcephaly?",
        "answer": "Microcephaly can lead to lifelong problems, such as\nseizures, feeding problems, hearing loss, vision problems, and learning difficulties.\nThere is no vaccine to prevent Zika virus infection and there is no treatment"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Microcephaly can lead to lifelong problems, such as\nseizures, feeding problems, hearing loss, vision problems, and learning difficulties.\nThere is no vaccine to prevent Zika virus infection and there is no treatment?",
        "answer": "You can\ncheck if Zika virus is spreading in any country at the CDC\u2019s Zika Travel Information\nwebsite.\nAvoid fresh fruits and vegetables unless they have been cooked or you have washed\nand peeled them yourself.\n\u2022\nDo not eat raw or undercooked meat or fish.\n\u2022\nDo not drink milk or eat foods made with milk that has not been pasteurized.\n\u2022\nBoil tap water for 1 minute before drinking it"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can\ncheck if Zika virus is spreading in any country at the CDC\u2019s Zika Travel Information\nwebsite.\nAvoid fresh fruits and vegetables unless they have been cooked or you have washed\nand peeled them yourself.\n\u2022\nDo not eat raw or undercooked meat or fish.\n\u2022\nDo not drink milk or eat foods made with milk that has not been pasteurized.\n\u2022\nBoil tap water for 1 minute before drinking it?",
        "answer": "Carbonated drinks are safe.\n\u2022\nDo not put ice made from unboiled water in your drinks.\n\u2022\nDo not drink out of glasses that may have been washed in unboiled water.\n\u2022\nBrush your teeth with bottled water.\n\u2022\nWhat should I know about Zika virus?\nthrough a bite by an infected mosquito\n\u2022\nto a fetus  during pregnancy or birth\n\u2022\nduring sex\n\u2022\nHow can I prevent Zika virus?\nIf Zika is spreading in a certain country and you cannot avoid that area, you can reduce\nyour chance of infection by\nAlso, use a condom every time you have sex if you have a male partner who lives in or\ntravels to areas where Zika virus is spreading.\nMalaria  is another serious disease carried by mosquitoes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Carbonated drinks are safe.\n\u2022\nDo not put ice made from unboiled water in your drinks.\n\u2022\nDo not drink out of glasses that may have been washed in unboiled water.\n\u2022\nBrush your teeth with bottled water.\n\u2022\nWhat should I know about Zika virus?\nthrough a bite by an infected mosquito\n\u2022\nto a fetus  during pregnancy or birth\n\u2022\nduring sex\n\u2022\nHow can I prevent Zika virus?\nIf Zika is spreading in a certain country and you cannot avoid that area, you can reduce\nyour chance of infection by\nAlso, use a condom every time you have sex if you have a male partner who lives in or\ntravels to areas where Zika virus is spreading.\nMalaria  is another serious disease carried by mosquitoes?",
        "answer": "Symptoms include fever,\nchills, headache, and nausea and vomiting"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Symptoms include fever,\nchills, headache, and nausea and vomiting?",
        "answer": "While you are pregnant, you should not travel\nto areas where there is risk of malaria, including Africa, Asia, and Central and South\nAmerica"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is While you are pregnant, you should not travel\nto areas where there is risk of malaria, including Africa, Asia, and Central and South\nAmerica?",
        "answer": "If travel to these areas cannot be avoided, your ob-gyn may prescribe an\nantimalarial drug that is safe to use during pregnancy.\nMedical Care While Traveling\nEven if you are in good health before going on a trip, you never know when an\nemergency will come up"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If travel to these areas cannot be avoided, your ob-gyn may prescribe an\nantimalarial drug that is safe to use during pregnancy.\nMedical Care While Traveling\nEven if you are in good health before going on a trip, you never know when an\nemergency will come up?",
        "answer": "Locate the nearest hospital or medical clinic in the place you\nare visiting"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Locate the nearest hospital or medical clinic in the place you\nare visiting?",
        "answer": "You may also want to check whether they accept your health insurance.\nYou can find ob-gyns who are members of the American College of Obstetricians and\nGynecologists (ACOG) at acog.org/FindanObGyn"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You may also want to check whether they accept your health insurance.\nYou can find ob-gyns who are members of the American College of Obstetricians and\nGynecologists (ACOG) at acog.org/FindanObGyn?",
        "answer": "The American Medical Association\n(AMA) also has a DoctorFinder tool.\nwearing long-sleeved shirts and pants to help protect against mosquitoes.\n\u2022\ntreating clothing and gear with permethrin or buying items that are treated with\npermethrin.\n\u2022\nusing EPA-registered bug spray with DEET, picaridin, IR3535, oil of lemon eucalyptus,\nor para-menthane-diol"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The American Medical Association\n(AMA) also has a DoctorFinder tool.\nwearing long-sleeved shirts and pants to help protect against mosquitoes.\n\u2022\ntreating clothing and gear with permethrin or buying items that are treated with\npermethrin.\n\u2022\nusing EPA-registered bug spray with DEET, picaridin, IR3535, oil of lemon eucalyptus,\nor para-menthane-diol?",
        "answer": "Used as directed, these sprays are safe to use while pregnant\nor breastfeeding.\n\u2022\nWhat should I know about malaria?\nHow can I prepare for a health emergency while traveling?\nHow can I find a doctor while traveling in the United States?\nHow can I find a doctor outside the United States?\nThe International Association for Medical Assistance to Travelers (IAMAT) has a\nworldwide directory of doctors who provide health care for travelers"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Used as directed, these sprays are safe to use while pregnant\nor breastfeeding.\n\u2022\nWhat should I know about malaria?\nHow can I prepare for a health emergency while traveling?\nHow can I find a doctor while traveling in the United States?\nHow can I find a doctor outside the United States?\nThe International Association for Medical Assistance to Travelers (IAMAT) has a\nworldwide directory of doctors who provide health care for travelers?",
        "answer": "You must be a\nmember to view the directory of doctors, but membership is free"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You must be a\nmember to view the directory of doctors, but membership is free?",
        "answer": "Visit www.iamat.org.\nAfter you arrive at your destination, you can also register with an American embassy or\nconsulate"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Visit www.iamat.org.\nAfter you arrive at your destination, you can also register with an American embassy or\nconsulate?",
        "answer": "This may help if you need to leave the country because of an emergency.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This may help if you need to leave the country because of an emergency.\nComplications: Diseases or conditions that happen as a result of another disease or\ncondition?",
        "answer": "An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example is pneumonia that occurs as a result of the flu?",
        "answer": "A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is A complication\nalso can occur as a result of a condition, such as pregnancy?",
        "answer": "An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nDeep Vein Thrombosis (DVT): A condition in which a blood clot forms in veins in the leg\nor other areas of the body.\nDiabetes Mellitus: A condition in which the levels of sugar in the blood are too high.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nHepatitis A: An infection caused by a virus that can be spread by contaminated food or\nwater.\nListeriosis: A type of illness you can get from bacteria found in unpasteurized milk, hot\ndogs, luncheon meats, and smoked seafood.\nMalaria: A disease caused by a parasite that is spread through mosquito bites.\nMicrocephaly: A birth defect in which a baby\u2019s head and brain are smaller than normal.\nBabies with microcephaly may have seizures, developmental delays, mental disability,\nvision and hearing problems, and problems with balance and movement.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOxygen: An element that we breathe in to sustain life.\nGlossary\nPreeclampsia: A disorder that can occur during pregnancy or after childbirth in which\nthere is high blood pressure and other signs of organ injury"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is An example of a pregnancy\ncomplication is preterm labor.\nDeep Vein Thrombosis (DVT): A condition in which a blood clot forms in veins in the leg\nor other areas of the body.\nDiabetes Mellitus: A condition in which the levels of sugar in the blood are too high.\nFetus: The stage of human development beyond 8 completed weeks after fertilization.\nHepatitis A: An infection caused by a virus that can be spread by contaminated food or\nwater.\nListeriosis: A type of illness you can get from bacteria found in unpasteurized milk, hot\ndogs, luncheon meats, and smoked seafood.\nMalaria: A disease caused by a parasite that is spread through mosquito bites.\nMicrocephaly: A birth defect in which a baby\u2019s head and brain are smaller than normal.\nBabies with microcephaly may have seizures, developmental delays, mental disability,\nvision and hearing problems, and problems with balance and movement.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nOxygen: An element that we breathe in to sustain life.\nGlossary\nPreeclampsia: A disorder that can occur during pregnancy or after childbirth in which\nthere is high blood pressure and other signs of organ injury?",
        "answer": "These signs include an\nabnormal amount of protein in the urine, a low number of platelets, abnormal kidney or\nliver function, pain over the upper abdomen, fluid in the lungs, or a severe headache or\nchanges in vision.\nPrelabor Rupture of Membranes (PROM): Rupture of the amniotic membranes that\nhappens before labor begins"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is These signs include an\nabnormal amount of protein in the urine, a low number of platelets, abnormal kidney or\nliver function, pain over the upper abdomen, fluid in the lungs, or a severe headache or\nchanges in vision.\nPrelabor Rupture of Membranes (PROM): Rupture of the amniotic membranes that\nhappens before labor begins?",
        "answer": "Also called premature rupture of membranes.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nRadiation: A type of energy that is transmitted in the form of rays, waves, or particles.\nTrimesters: The 3-month periods of time in pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also called premature rupture of membranes.\nPreterm: Less than 37 weeks of pregnancy.\nRadiation: A type of energy that is transmitted in the form of rays, waves, or particles.\nTrimesters: The 3-month periods of time in pregnancy?",
        "answer": "They are referred to as first,\nsecond, or third.\nZika: A disease caused by the Zika virus, which is spread through mosquito bites.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ055\nLast updated: July 2023\nLast reviewed: January 2023\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They are referred to as first,\nsecond, or third.\nZika: A disease caused by the Zika virus, which is spread through mosquito bites.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ055\nLast updated: July 2023\nLast reviewed: January 2023\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nVaccine Safety During Pregnancy\nVaccine Basics\nVaccines  train the immune system  to attack specific viruses  and bacteria"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nAbout ACOG\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use\nVaccine Safety During Pregnancy\nVaccine Basics\nVaccines  train the immune system  to attack specific viruses  and bacteria?",
        "answer": "This\nmakes vaccination an important part of preventing infections during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This\nmakes vaccination an important part of preventing infections during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "If you\nare pregnant or thinking about getting pregnant, you need certain vaccines"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you\nare pregnant or thinking about getting pregnant, you need certain vaccines?",
        "answer": "At different\npoints during their lives, babies, children, teens, adults, and seniors all need certain\nvaccines, too.\n[Are you current on your vaccines? These are the ones you should get as an adult.]\nMost vaccines are made with inactivated (killed) versions of a pathogen (a virus or\nbacteria that causes disease)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is At different\npoints during their lives, babies, children, teens, adults, and seniors all need certain\nvaccines, too.\n[Are you current on your vaccines? These are the ones you should get as an adult.]\nMost vaccines are made with inactivated (killed) versions of a pathogen (a virus or\nbacteria that causes disease)?",
        "answer": "Some vaccines are made with parts of the pathogen or\nwith a killed toxin made by the pathogen"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Some vaccines are made with parts of the pathogen or\nwith a killed toxin made by the pathogen?",
        "answer": "None of these things can cause the disease\nitself when given as a vaccine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is None of these things can cause the disease\nitself when given as a vaccine?",
        "answer": "Most vaccines also contain some other ingredients,\nincluding\nFAQs\nWhy are vaccines important?\nHow are vaccines made?\nwater or other fluids\n\u2022\npreservatives and stabilizers\n\u2022\nchemicals added to inactivate the virus or bacteria\n\u2022\nsubstances that help create a stronger immune response to the vaccine\n\u2022\nsmall amounts of the material that was used to grow the virus or bacteria\n\u2022\nThe amounts of these ingredients are very small"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Most vaccines also contain some other ingredients,\nincluding\nFAQs\nWhy are vaccines important?\nHow are vaccines made?\nwater or other fluids\n\u2022\npreservatives and stabilizers\n\u2022\nchemicals added to inactivate the virus or bacteria\n\u2022\nsubstances that help create a stronger immune response to the vaccine\n\u2022\nsmall amounts of the material that was used to grow the virus or bacteria\n\u2022\nThe amounts of these ingredients are very small?",
        "answer": "All of them are tested extensively to\nmake sure they are safe"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All of them are tested extensively to\nmake sure they are safe?",
        "answer": "You can learn more about these ingredients from the Centers\nfor Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).\nVaccines are subject to strict safety standards"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You can learn more about these ingredients from the Centers\nfor Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).\nVaccines are subject to strict safety standards?",
        "answer": "In the United States, vaccines are\napproved by the U.S"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In the United States, vaccines are\napproved by the U.S?",
        "answer": "Food and Drug Administration (FDA) only after thorough research.\nTesting starts with animals and small groups of human volunteers"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Food and Drug Administration (FDA) only after thorough research.\nTesting starts with animals and small groups of human volunteers?",
        "answer": "Later, vaccines are\ntested in large clinical trials with thousands of volunteers"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Later, vaccines are\ntested in large clinical trials with thousands of volunteers?",
        "answer": "If a clinical trial shows that a\nvaccine is safe and effective, there are a few other safety reviews"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If a clinical trial shows that a\nvaccine is safe and effective, there are a few other safety reviews?",
        "answer": "Then vaccine experts\nmeet to review the testing results.\nOnce a vaccine is licensed by the FDA, a committee called the Advisory Committee on\nImmunization Practices (ACIP) at the CDC recommends how best to use it to control\ndisease"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Then vaccine experts\nmeet to review the testing results.\nOnce a vaccine is licensed by the FDA, a committee called the Advisory Committee on\nImmunization Practices (ACIP) at the CDC recommends how best to use it to control\ndisease?",
        "answer": "This recommendation goes to the CDC director, who reviews and approves the\nrecommendation.\nVaccines and Pregnancy\nVaccines cause the body to create antibodies"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This recommendation goes to the CDC director, who reviews and approves the\nrecommendation.\nVaccines and Pregnancy\nVaccines cause the body to create antibodies?",
        "answer": "Antibodies are proteins that can identify\nbacteria and viruses and stop them from entering cells  and making a person sick"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Antibodies are proteins that can identify\nbacteria and viruses and stop them from entering cells  and making a person sick?",
        "answer": "After\nyou get a vaccine during pregnancy and your body creates antibodies, some of those\nantibodies pass to the fetus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is After\nyou get a vaccine during pregnancy and your body creates antibodies, some of those\nantibodies pass to the fetus?",
        "answer": "This means the baby will have the antibodies to protect\nagainst disease after birth.\nAntibodies are a safe, normal reaction to a vaccine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This means the baby will have the antibodies to protect\nagainst disease after birth.\nAntibodies are a safe, normal reaction to a vaccine?",
        "answer": "They protect your baby during the\nfirst few months of life until your baby can be vaccinated.\nIt is safe to get vaccines for the flu, whooping cough, COVID-19, respiratory syncytial\nvirus (RSV), hepatitis , pneumonia , and certain types of meningitis  during pregnancy.\nHow are vaccines approved?\nHow does getting vaccinated during pregnancy protect my baby?\nWhich vaccines may be given during pregnancy?\nWhich vaccines should be given in every pregnancy?\nTwo vaccines are recommended during each pregnancy:\nCertain vaccines should not be given during pregnancy because they contain live,\nattenuated viruses"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is They protect your baby during the\nfirst few months of life until your baby can be vaccinated.\nIt is safe to get vaccines for the flu, whooping cough, COVID-19, respiratory syncytial\nvirus (RSV), hepatitis , pneumonia , and certain types of meningitis  during pregnancy.\nHow are vaccines approved?\nHow does getting vaccinated during pregnancy protect my baby?\nWhich vaccines may be given during pregnancy?\nWhich vaccines should be given in every pregnancy?\nTwo vaccines are recommended during each pregnancy:\nCertain vaccines should not be given during pregnancy because they contain live,\nattenuated viruses?",
        "answer": "\u201cAttenuated\u201d means that the virus has been weakened so that it\ncannot cause disease in a healthy person"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is \u201cAttenuated\u201d means that the virus has been weakened so that it\ncannot cause disease in a healthy person?",
        "answer": "The vaccines that women should not get\nduring pregnancy include\nTdap vaccine\u2014This vaccine protects against whooping cough"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The vaccines that women should not get\nduring pregnancy include\nTdap vaccine\u2014This vaccine protects against whooping cough?",
        "answer": "Tdap vaccines\u00a0are\nrecommended between 27 and 36 weeks of pregnancy.\n\u2022\nFlu vaccine\u2014The flu is a serious illness that can be much more severe during\npregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Tdap vaccines\u00a0are\nrecommended between 27 and 36 weeks of pregnancy.\n\u2022\nFlu vaccine\u2014The flu is a serious illness that can be much more severe during\npregnancy?",
        "answer": "You should get a flu vaccine\u00a0if you are pregnant during flu season\n(October through May)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is You should get a flu vaccine\u00a0if you are pregnant during flu season\n(October through May)?",
        "answer": "It is best to get the flu vaccine early in the flu season, as soon\nas the vaccine is available.\n\u2022\nWhen are other vaccines recommended during pregnancy?\nRSV vaccine\u2014The Pfizer RSV vaccine\u00a0is recommended if you are 32 to 36 weeks\npregnant from September to January"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is best to get the flu vaccine early in the flu season, as soon\nas the vaccine is available.\n\u2022\nWhen are other vaccines recommended during pregnancy?\nRSV vaccine\u2014The Pfizer RSV vaccine\u00a0is recommended if you are 32 to 36 weeks\npregnant from September to January?",
        "answer": "RSV is a seasonal virus that can be dangerous\nfor babies and young children.\n\u2022\nCOVID-19 vaccine\u2014If you are pregnant and not up to date on your COVID-19\nvaccines, you should get the currently recommended vaccine.\n\u2022\nHepatitis, pneumonia, and certain meningitis vaccines\u2014These may be\nrecommended based on your risk of getting these diseases"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is RSV is a seasonal virus that can be dangerous\nfor babies and young children.\n\u2022\nCOVID-19 vaccine\u2014If you are pregnant and not up to date on your COVID-19\nvaccines, you should get the currently recommended vaccine.\n\u2022\nHepatitis, pneumonia, and certain meningitis vaccines\u2014These may be\nrecommended based on your risk of getting these diseases?",
        "answer": "Talk with your\nobstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  about the vaccines that you have had in the\npast"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Talk with your\nobstetrician\u2013gynecologist (ob-gyn)  about the vaccines that you have had in the\npast?",
        "answer": "Your ob-gyn may recommend these vaccines based on your medical history\nand occupation.\n\u2022\nAre there vaccines that should not be given during pregnancy?\nlive, attenuated flu vaccine given as a nasal spray (but the flu shot is safe)\n\u2022\nmeasles\u2013mumps\u2013rubella (MMR) vaccine\n\u2022\nchickenpox  vaccine\n\u2022\nAlso, the vaccine for human papillomavirus (HPV)  is not a live, attenuated vaccine, but\nit still should not be given during pregnancy.\nVaccine Safety\nYes, vaccines are safe for both of you"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Your ob-gyn may recommend these vaccines based on your medical history\nand occupation.\n\u2022\nAre there vaccines that should not be given during pregnancy?\nlive, attenuated flu vaccine given as a nasal spray (but the flu shot is safe)\n\u2022\nmeasles\u2013mumps\u2013rubella (MMR) vaccine\n\u2022\nchickenpox  vaccine\n\u2022\nAlso, the vaccine for human papillomavirus (HPV)  is not a live, attenuated vaccine, but\nit still should not be given during pregnancy.\nVaccine Safety\nYes, vaccines are safe for both of you?",
        "answer": "In fact, vaccination is one of the most important\nthings that you can do to protect your health and your baby\u2019s health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is In fact, vaccination is one of the most important\nthings that you can do to protect your health and your baby\u2019s health?",
        "answer": "Keep in mind that\nvaccines have been safely given to millions of pregnant women for more than 50 years.\nThere is a tiny amount of mercury (also called thimerosal) in a small number of\nvaccines"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Keep in mind that\nvaccines have been safely given to millions of pregnant women for more than 50 years.\nThere is a tiny amount of mercury (also called thimerosal) in a small number of\nvaccines?",
        "answer": "It is safe and not harmful during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is safe and not harmful during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "But it is no longer used in most\nnew vaccines due to new technology.\nThimerosal is safe because it uses a type of mercury called ethylmercury"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But it is no longer used in most\nnew vaccines due to new technology.\nThimerosal is safe because it uses a type of mercury called ethylmercury?",
        "answer": "This is\ndifferent than the type of mercury found in fish"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This is\ndifferent than the type of mercury found in fish?",
        "answer": "Ethylmercury is a nonpoisonous salt,\nand it naturally leaves the body after a vaccine.\nThimerosal is used mainly in vaccines that come in multidose vials"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Ethylmercury is a nonpoisonous salt,\nand it naturally leaves the body after a vaccine.\nThimerosal is used mainly in vaccines that come in multidose vials?",
        "answer": "This means the vial\nhas enough vaccine for more than one person"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is This means the vial\nhas enough vaccine for more than one person?",
        "answer": "Vials with more than one dose need to\nbe kept pure"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Vials with more than one dose need to\nbe kept pure?",
        "answer": "Thimerosal helps prevent germs from growing in a vial that has multiple\ndoses"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Thimerosal helps prevent germs from growing in a vial that has multiple\ndoses?",
        "answer": "But most new vaccines come in single-dose vials, which is why thimerosal is not\nused much anymore.\nFind more information about thimerosal and vaccine safety and all vaccine ingredients\nfrom the CDC.\nSome people have no side effects from getting a vaccine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is But most new vaccines come in single-dose vials, which is why thimerosal is not\nused much anymore.\nFind more information about thimerosal and vaccine safety and all vaccine ingredients\nfrom the CDC.\nSome people have no side effects from getting a vaccine?",
        "answer": "Other people have mild side\neffects, such as a sore arm or a low fever, that go away within a day or two"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Other people have mild side\neffects, such as a sore arm or a low fever, that go away within a day or two?",
        "answer": "Severe side\neffects and reactions are rare"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Severe side\neffects and reactions are rare?",
        "answer": "The CDC monitors reactions for all vaccines given in the\nUnited States.\nAre vaccines safe for me and my baby?\nIs there mercury in vaccines?\nDo vaccines have side effects?\nWhen you get a vaccine, you should get an information sheet that lists the possible side\neffects associated with that vaccine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The CDC monitors reactions for all vaccines given in the\nUnited States.\nAre vaccines safe for me and my baby?\nIs there mercury in vaccines?\nDo vaccines have side effects?\nWhen you get a vaccine, you should get an information sheet that lists the possible side\neffects associated with that vaccine?",
        "answer": "If you have ever had a reaction to a vaccine, or if\nyou have concerns about side effects, talk with your ob-gyn.\nCOVID-19 Vaccines\nCurrently there are two types of COVID-19 vaccines available in the United States: mRNA\n(Moderna and Pfizer) and protein subunit (Novavax).\nTo understand how vaccines work, it helps to understand the COVID-19 virus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is If you have ever had a reaction to a vaccine, or if\nyou have concerns about side effects, talk with your ob-gyn.\nCOVID-19 Vaccines\nCurrently there are two types of COVID-19 vaccines available in the United States: mRNA\n(Moderna and Pfizer) and protein subunit (Novavax).\nTo understand how vaccines work, it helps to understand the COVID-19 virus?",
        "answer": "The\nsurface of COVID-19 cells contains a \u201cspike protein.\u201d This protein attaches to and infects\nhealthy cells in the body.\nThe COVID-19 vaccines work by teaching your body to fight the spike protein so it\ncannot bind to healthy cells"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The\nsurface of COVID-19 cells contains a \u201cspike protein.\u201d This protein attaches to and infects\nhealthy cells in the body.\nThe COVID-19 vaccines work by teaching your body to fight the spike protein so it\ncannot bind to healthy cells?",
        "answer": "There is no live or inactive (killed) virus in the mRNA and\nprotein subunit vaccines"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There is no live or inactive (killed) virus in the mRNA and\nprotein subunit vaccines?",
        "answer": "Learn more about these types of vaccines and how they work\nfrom the CDC.\nThese vaccines cannot give you COVID-19"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Learn more about these types of vaccines and how they work\nfrom the CDC.\nThese vaccines cannot give you COVID-19?",
        "answer": "The vaccines do not affect your genes or\nDNA"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The vaccines do not affect your genes or\nDNA?",
        "answer": "There is no evidence that the COVID-19 vaccines cause infertility or have an\nimpact on pregnancy.\nYes, COVID-19 vaccines are safe during pregnancy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is There is no evidence that the COVID-19 vaccines cause infertility or have an\nimpact on pregnancy.\nYes, COVID-19 vaccines are safe during pregnancy?",
        "answer": "Scientists have compared the\npregnancies of women who have received COVID-19 vaccines and women who have\nnot"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Scientists have compared the\npregnancies of women who have received COVID-19 vaccines and women who have\nnot?",
        "answer": "The reports show that these women have had similar pregnancy outcomes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The reports show that these women have had similar pregnancy outcomes?",
        "answer": "Data do\nnot show any safety concerns"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Data do\nnot show any safety concerns?",
        "answer": "Read COVID-19 Vaccines: Answers From Ob-Gyns\u00a0to\nlearn more.\nResources and Glossary\nHow do COVID-19 vaccines work?\nAre the COVID-19 vaccines safe during pregnancy?\nResources\nAmerican College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (ACOG)\nwww.acog.org/Vaccine-Resources\nCenters for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)\nwww.cdc.gov/vaccines/pregnancy\nwww.flu.gov\nwww.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines\nVaccines.gov\nwww.vaccines.gov\nFind a COVID-19 vaccine near you.\nAntibodies: Proteins in the blood that the body makes in reaction to foreign substances,\nsuch as bacteria and viruses.\nBacteria: One-celled organisms that can cause infections in the human body.\nCells: The smallest units of a structure in the body"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read COVID-19 Vaccines: Answers From Ob-Gyns\u00a0to\nlearn more.\nResources and Glossary\nHow do COVID-19 vaccines work?\nAre the COVID-19 vaccines safe during pregnancy?\nResources\nAmerican College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (ACOG)\nwww.acog.org/Vaccine-Resources\nCenters for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)\nwww.cdc.gov/vaccines/pregnancy\nwww.flu.gov\nwww.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines\nVaccines.gov\nwww.vaccines.gov\nFind a COVID-19 vaccine near you.\nAntibodies: Proteins in the blood that the body makes in reaction to foreign substances,\nsuch as bacteria and viruses.\nBacteria: One-celled organisms that can cause infections in the human body.\nCells: The smallest units of a structure in the body?",
        "answer": "Cells are the building blocks for all\nparts of the body.\nChickenpox: A contagious disease caused by a virus that results in small, fluid-filled\nblisters on the skin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Cells are the building blocks for all\nparts of the body.\nChickenpox: A contagious disease caused by a virus that results in small, fluid-filled\nblisters on the skin?",
        "answer": "Also called varicella.\nHepatitis: Infection of the liver that can be caused by several types of viruses.\nHuman Papillomavirus (HPV): The name for a group of related viruses, some of which\ncause genital warts and some of which are linked to cancer of the cervix, vulva, vagina,\npenis, anus, mouth, and throat.\nImmune System: The body\u2019s natural defense system against viruses and bacteria that\ncause disease.\nMeasles\u2013Mumps\u2013Rubella (MMR) Vaccine: A shot given to protect against measles,\nmumps, and rubella"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Also called varicella.\nHepatitis: Infection of the liver that can be caused by several types of viruses.\nHuman Papillomavirus (HPV): The name for a group of related viruses, some of which\ncause genital warts and some of which are linked to cancer of the cervix, vulva, vagina,\npenis, anus, mouth, and throat.\nImmune System: The body\u2019s natural defense system against viruses and bacteria that\ncause disease.\nMeasles\u2013Mumps\u2013Rubella (MMR) Vaccine: A shot given to protect against measles,\nmumps, and rubella?",
        "answer": "The shot contains live viruses that have been changed to not cause\ndisease"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The shot contains live viruses that have been changed to not cause\ndisease?",
        "answer": "The shot is not recommended for pregnant women.\nGlossary\nAbout ACOG\nMeningitis: Inflammation of the covering of the brain or spinal cord.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPneumonia: An infection of the lungs.\nVaccines: Substances that help the body fight disease"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is The shot is not recommended for pregnant women.\nGlossary\nAbout ACOG\nMeningitis: Inflammation of the covering of the brain or spinal cord.\nObstetrician\u2013Gynecologist (Ob-Gyn): A doctor with special training and education in\nwomen\u2019s health.\nPneumonia: An infection of the lungs.\nVaccines: Substances that help the body fight disease?",
        "answer": "Vaccines are made from very\nsmall amounts of weak or dead agents that cause disease (bacteria, toxins, and\nviruses).\nViruses: Agents that cause certain types of infections.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ531\nLast updated: January 2024\nLast reviewed: January 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Vaccines are made from very\nsmall amounts of weak or dead agents that cause disease (bacteria, toxins, and\nviruses).\nViruses: Agents that cause certain types of infections.\nIf you have further questions, contact your ob-gyn.\nDon't have an ob-gyn? Learn how to find a doctor near you.\nFAQ531\nLast updated: January 2024\nLast reviewed: January 2024\nCopyright 2025 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists?",
        "answer": "All rights reserved"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is All rights reserved?",
        "answer": "Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Read\ncopyright and permissions information.\nThis information is designed as an educational aid for the public?",
        "answer": "It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It offers current information and\nopinions related to women's health?",
        "answer": "It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not intended as a statement of the standard of care?",
        "answer": "It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It does\nnot explain all of the proper treatments or methods of care?",
        "answer": "It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is It is not a substitute for the advice of a\nphysician?",
        "answer": "Read ACOG\u2019s complete disclaimer.\nDisclaimer\nContact Us\nHow to Find an Ob-Gyn\n\uf09a\n\ue92a\n\uf0e1\n\ue923\nCopyright 2025 American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists\nPrivacy Statement\n|\nTerms and Conditions of Use"
    }
]